Danger looms!
Despite recent victories
in the Outer Rim,
criminal minds plot
at the very heart of the Republic.
The bounty hunter Cad Bane
has assembled some of the deadliest
criminals in the galaxy
and plans a daring attack
to seize members of the Senate.
What could be the aim
of this despicable act?
Here we go.
Attention, attention!
This is a restricted area.
No landing is permitted
without permission.
Violators will be prosecuted
to the full extent of the law.
Put up your hands.
I've got business with the Senate.
How about you fellas step aside?
On your knees.
Raise your hands.
Slowly.
Son,
I wouldn't be so hasty
if I were you.
Cuff him.
- Where's that coming from?
- I see the shooter up in the tower.
Over there!
You two, get these uniforms on
and get this platform clear.
Base to platform.
What was all that? Report.
Protesters against the war.
We've taken care of them.
Finish getting those uniforms on
and clear this platform, now.
Everybody else,
follow me.
I'm supposed to be
on a meditative retreat.
We should go away together.
I know a place far away from here
where no one would recognise us.
It would be like
we're actually husband and wife,
instead of senator and Jedi.
- I can't, Ani.
- What do you mean, you can't?
It's only two weeks.
We'll be back before anyone
even notices we're gone.
I have to bring this bill
before the Senate. It's important.
More important
than the way you feel about me?
Not more important,
but important.
The work I do...
The work we both do...
is in service to the Republic.
To protect those who would otherwise
be powerless to protect themselves.
Of course.
But those are ideals.
Isn't our love
more important to you?
- But I...
- No, no "but".
To me,
there's nothing more important
than the way I feel about you.
Nothing.
- Anakin, don't be so...
- You don't believe me.
- I didn't say...
- I'll prove it.
Just watch.
When I finished constructing
my lightsaber, Obi-Wan said to me,
"Anakin, this weapon is your life. "
This weapon is my life.
No, Anakin, I can't.
A Jedi lightsaber is...
Wow.
It's heavier than I thought.
It's yours.
Believe me now?
If all you want to do
is make fun of me,
- I think you should just go.
- That's not what I want.
Not at all.
Stop!
You know what to do.
I'll figure it out.
You better not fail me,
bubble brain.
Don't worry,
I'll have the power out in no time.
The rest of you come with me.
But, Senator Organa,
it just wouldn't be...
Quick, hide!
Now stand aside.
I apologise for my abruptness.
Senator Organa,
how good to see you.
What is it?
Senator Filo has called
a meeting in the lobby
before we vote
on the Enhanced Privacy Invasion Bill.
Right,
Privacy Invasion Bill.
We must hurry
if we are to stop the vote.
Coming, Senator Amidala?
Of course.
Quietly.
Guard change happens... now.
Here we go.
Now let's go talk to some senators.
Help me.
No!
We cannot allow the chancellor
to move this enhanced Privacy
Invasion Bill forward.
We are all in agreement then.
Morning, Senators.
You should all consider yourselves
to be in my power.
As long as everybody behaves
this will be quick and painless.
Do nothing,
and it will all be over soon.
I don't know
who you think you are
but I for one have no intention
of listening to this kind of insolence.
All right, then.
If you all gather at the center
of this lovely atrium,
my co-workers and I will relieve you
of any communication devices.
I see five of them here in the room.
If we...
What are you going to do?
It's not like we carry weapons.
Chancellor Palpatine.
What is it, Senator Free Taa?
I think you should see this.
Sorry to bother you, Chancellor,
but I've taken control of the east wing
of your Senate building,
and the occupants
are now my hostages.
If you care about them,
I'd advise you to free Ziro the Hutt
from the detention center.
You should know that the Republic
does not take kindly to such threats.
If you have attempted such a fool-hardy
action as to kidnap a senator,
I assure you that it will be met
with appropriate force.
This ought to do it.
What's going on?
I'm in control.
I make the rules now.
Orn Free Taa,
help me with this door.
It's no use, sir.
Someone's gotten
to the central control panel.
They've triggered
the security system.
The Senate buildings
have sealed themselves.
This is Chancellor Palpatine.
There is an emergency
at the Senate building.
Jedi Council, come in.
Is anyone there?
That's no use either, sir.
They've cut off all communication
with the outside.
Hand over your
communication devices, please.
- I can't let them search me.
- What?
Why not?
- I have something they must not find.
- What is it?
Well,
hello there, little lady.
And who might you be?
I am Padme Amidala,
Senator from Naboo.
And I demand
that you release us immediately.
The Galactic Senate
will not treat with terrorists.
Ain't you awful young and pretty
to be a senator?
Skywalker?!
After him!
Hello, come in.
Anyone there?
Uh-oh.
This is General Skywalker.
Chancellor Palpatine,
- can you hear me?
- My dear boy,
I'm glad to know
you're there and all right.
- What is going on down there?
- I hear it too.
Coming from up ahead.
They've sealed the entire building.
Nobody can get in
and we cannot get out.
It's up to you. You have to
get to the power control room
and turn off the security seal.
You have two more floors to check.
Come on.
We've got two more floors to check.
You take downstairs,
I'll go up.
We'll meet on the other side.
No lightsaber cuts?
Interesting.
What happened?
Where's the droid?
The droid's gone,
but there's good news.
- The Jedi's unarmed.
- What?
It doesn't look like
he has his lightsaber.
Go, bring him back to me.
- The lightsaber, I've got it.
- What?
Why do you have a Jedi's lightsaber?
The question is whether we should
try and get it back to A...
...the Jedi knight
or use it ourselves.
Everybody quiet.
I've got a call to make.
So here's what you're going to do.
First you're going to
make a pardon disc.
- You can give it to your friend there.
- Me?
My ship will come and pick him up
and take him to the prison.
Once Ziro has been released
and is handed over to me,
then your associate will be released.
Understand?
Oh, I do.
But I feel it is my duty
to warn you
that you will end up
paying for this outrage.
I can live with that.
Come on, open the door.
I won't hurt you.
Well, well,
what have we here?
Blast it!
Tie your little pet up.
We'll bring him to Bane.
Here's the pardon disc.
Let's go.
Why do I have to
go to the jail for this?
- Move it.
- Sorry, Senator.
But everyone has a job to do.
Hurry up.
Young Skywalker.
Not so impressive
without your lightsaber,
are you, Jedi?
Toss him in with the others.
3D, are we on schedule?
Arriving at the prison now.
Unlock the doors.
- It's so bright out here!
- Oh, my God.
Why couldn't they do this at night
when it's cooler?
Go and get the parting gifts.
Look at Senator Orn Free Taa.
He looks so unhappy.
Now get me as far away
from Coruscant as possible!
Now!
Well, Mr. Chancellor,
thanks to your calm leadership,
the crisis is passed.
I got what I want,
so I'll return your Senate
and your senators.
Enjoy them,
but don't try anything
until the sun has set.
Understand?
We are to rendezvous
back at the Senate building.
What?!
No, no, no, no!
The Outer Rim, not the Senate,
you stupid machine!
We need to
get to the landing platform.
- Is everything ready?
- Yep, yep.
Turn on the field.
If you so much as breathe
on one of these lasers,
the whole room will blow up.
Senators, Jedi,
I bid you all
the most respectful farewell.
Let's go.
All clear!
- Sir, are you all right?
- Yes, yes, I'm fine.
Mission accomplished, sir.
The chancellor is safe.
Well done, trooper.
You were foolish to think you could
get away with this, bounty hunter.
Now lay down your arms
and come quietly.
No, Chancellor.
I am afraid it is you
who have been foolish
with your senators' lives.
One false move
and the east wing of the Senate building
goes up in smoke.
Please, Ani, wake up.
You win, bounty hunter.
Holster!
Stand down.
What are you looking so sad about?
The bounty hunter said
we should just sit here.
I think we should just sit here.
Well,
that's not a very good idea.
Come on.
Let's get going.
Too bad
I don't have my lightsaber.
You mean this?
I found it
where you dropped it.
Now, quickly.
We don't have much time.
Well, Hutt,
it doesn't look like prison had
too adverse an effect on you.
You can't imagine
the unspeakable things I've suffered.
The horror!
I doubt I'll ever really recover.
How about some dead senators
as payback?
Another daring rescue,
Master Jedi.
I do my best, Senator.
Congratulations
on a job well done,
bounty hunter.
Time to pay up, Hutt.
I don't work for free.