A galaxy, divided by war.
Peaceful worlds must choose sides
or face the threat of invasion.
Republican Separatist armies vie
for the allegiance of neutral planets.
Desparate to build a Republic supply
base in the system of Toydaria,
Jedi Master Yoda travels to secret
negotiations on a remote neutral moon.
We are getting no signal from
the Republic, Your Highness.
I don't see anything.
It is not like the Jedi
to be late.
Greetings, King Katuunko.
- Who are you?
- I am only a messenger, Majesty.
My master wishes to speak with you.
Katuunko,
great king of Toydaria,
forgive my intrusion.
Count Dooku.
I am aware Master Yoda
hopes you will allow the Jedi
to build a Republic base in your system
in exchange for protection,
correct?
Your spies serve you well, Count.
I ask, how can the Jedi protect you...
if they cannot protect themselves?
Toydarian Royal Delegation, this is
the Republican envoy, please respond.
General, the Toydarians beacon is
active on the moon,
but all our transmissions are
being jammed.
We caught them by surprise, all right.
We're losing our shields.
Too late, it is.
Sprung is the trap.
- I must get you to safety, General.
- Retreat you must.
On the moon below, is my mission.
There, I must go.
I suppose you and your droid
armies can do better?
Without a doubt.
I sense you are one who respects
strength, Your Highness.
Our droid armies outnumber the
Republic clones 100 to 1.
Perhaps.
But I have heard
that a single Jedi
equals 100 battle droids.
Quickly now,
reach the planets surface we must.
In an escape pod, sir?
The enemy will fire
at anything we launch.
Then launch all of them,
you will.
Master Yoda's powers have
been greatly exaggerated.
That remains to be seen, Count.
Indeed.
But when you decide to join us,
my apprentice will contact me.
Hang on.
Almost...
What a terrible shot.
Ah, well,
it's my programming.
That was a close one.
General, I think we're out of range.
I agree,
but entering another trap, we are.
Are you sure?
A disturbance in the force,
there is.
My Lord,
Master Yoda's warship
has fled the system.
What further evidence do you require
of the Jedi's weakness?
This is King Katuunko. Speak.
Master Yoda would like to
talk with you, sir.
A pleasure it is, to hear your voice,
Your Highness.
Master Yoda of the Jedi Council,
this is.
Master Jedi,
I thought perhaps Count Dooku
had frightened you off.
Delayed have I been,
but not too far away am I now.
Unaware I was, Count Dooku was
invited to our meeting.
The Count invited himself.
He assures me that in this time of war,
his droids can offer my world
greater security than your Jedi.
Hmmm, a matter of debate that is.
Your Majesty might prefer
more than words.
What do you have in mind?
If Yoda is indeed the Jedi warrior
you believe he is,
let him prove it.
Allow me to send my best troops
to capture him.
If he escapes, join the Republic.
But should my droids defeat Yoda,
consider an alliance with the Separatists.
I did not request Yoda's presence here
to test him in battle.
Accept the challenge, I do,
Your Highness.
Arrive by nightfall, I will.
Master Yoda must be given a fair fight.
My dear King Katuunko,
I would have it no other way.
Beautiful, this moon is.
Amazing, the universe is.
There's gotta be a full
battalion in there.
Probably packin' armor, too.
We'll have somethin' for 'em.
I'm deploying my forces, master.
Yoda has made a grave mistake,
straying this far from Coruscant.
I will see the Jedi gets his
"fair fight".
Carry only what you need.
Too much weight slow you down,
it will.
Destroy Ventress, your weapons will not.
Come, Lieutenant. Hurry, we must.
Sir, the rendezvous point is that way.
As is our enemy.
To reach our goal,
a straight path, we will not follow.
Let's move it, boys.
Find Master Yoda.
Ahh, what does he look like?
He'll be the small shriveled green one,
with the light saber.
Small, huh?
Don't worry, Supreme Leader,
we'll take care of him.
I think I see them.
They're hiding deep in the trees.
Fire on sector 11.
At ease be, my friends.
Within range, we are not.
Hold it, hold it.
I said, hold it!
That's far enough!
I mean it! Stop!
I said, stop!
- We're too big to fit in there.
- No, we're not. Watch this.
- You were right.
- Next time, listen to orders.
Those tanks are too big to follow.
See, see?
Size is not everything.
Smaller in number are we,
but larger in mind.
Do you have any idea
what the General was talkin' about?
How should I know?
There's no figurin' a Jedi Master.
Infantry, advance.
Go get 'em, boys.
Sir, there are two patrols
coming in on foot.
Now is the time to face the enemy,
Lieutenant. Ambush them, we will.
- We'll flank them from the south.
- Right, let's move.
What was that?
Blast him!
Look, little green life form.
You bucket head, that's the Jedi!
He is a little one.
Blast him!
Split up by squad and spread out.
- Roger, roger.
OK, clankers, suck laser!
- Where's the General?
- I don't know. We got separated.
Clankers!
Fall back!
There are too many of them.
He's around here somewhere.
Hey, get off of me!
Don't move.
The Jedi destroyed
our advance troops.
Master Yoda is living up to
my expectations.
Commander,
have you pinpointed the Jedi's location?
Affirmative. The clones gave
away their position.
Our heavy troops are moving
to engage them now.
I hope the General reaches the
rendezvous point.
This should buy him time.
- Lieutenant, can you walk?
- I think I'm okay.
Die, Republic dog!
What are we gonna do, sir?
- What's the General doing?
- Keep blasting!
Hey, what's going on?
Get out of the way, all of you!
I'm having a serious malfunction!
Don't shoot!
I'm on your side!
- You found us just in time, sir.
- Left behind,
no one will be.
Rollers, inbound.
Retreat!
Cover you, I will.
Republic troops are injured,
the Jedi is in full retreat, Supreme Leader.
Good. Pursue them without delay.
The contest is not over yet.
Master Yoda,
I hear you're having trouble
with the droid army?
Trouble?
I know nothing of this trouble.
Look forward to our meeting soon,
I do.
The Jedi won't allude me for long.
Are you sure we should go in there,
General? There's no way out.
Now rest, we must.
We're low on ammo, sir.
Only 2 grenades,
and 1 rocket for the launcher.
Against a battalion?
Forget it, we've lost.
So certain of defeat, are you?
With respect, General,
maybe you should go on.
Let us slow 'em down.
All around us, is that with
which we need to prevail, is.
Come, sit.
Your helmets, remove them.
Your faces I wish to see.
There's not much to look at here, sir.
We all share the same face.
Deceive you, eyes can.
In the force, very different
each one of you are.
Rys, always focused on the enemy,
are you.
For inspiration, look to yourself,
and those beside you.
Jeck, concerned about weapons you are.
Weapons do not win battles.
Your mind, powerful it is.
Outthink the droids, you can.
Thire, rush not into fights.
Long is the war.
Only by surviving it, will you prevail.
Yes.
Clones you may be,
but the force resides in all life forms.
Use it, you can, to quiet your mind.
Tanks.
- Is that the best they can throw at us?
- Yeah, but I've only got one shot left.
- Greet them, I will.
- General,
you don't plan to take that whole
column by yourself?
Have you three, I do.
Outnumbered are they.
Know the time to help me, you will.
It's the Jedi!
Block his escape!
Prepare to fire!
Supreme Leader, we found the Jedi.
Excellent. Where is he?
He's just sitting here,
in front of our tanks.
Shoot him!
Shoot him now!
Quickly!
Ready, aim, fire!
Fire!
He's gone under the tank!
Oh, no!
Run for it!
But I just got promoted.
Doesn't look like the General needs
help to me.
We've got him in our sights.
That's a lot of smoke,
for a surrender.
Report. What's going on over there?
224, come in.
Where is 224?
Destroyed, Supreme Leader.
The Jedi has overrun our position
and...
I think perhaps all those stories
about the Jedi are true.
The fight isn't over yet, Majesty.
The General's cutting 'em up.
We've got trouble.
Clankers sent reinforcements.
General's too busy with that tank.
He won't see 'em coming.
I think I know how to deal with them.
Yeah! Great shot, sir!
That's givin' it to the clankers.
Learned something today,
have you, Lieutenant?
I think we all did, General.
Come, behind schedule are we.
Not polite to be late.
You were right, Count Dooku.
One Jedi is not worth 100 battle droids.
More like, 1,000.
I'm sorry, but I will be
joining the Republic.
I urge you to reconsider, wise king.
I promise you won't regret it.
Your agent also promised me
Yoda would get a fair fight.
I will not deal with those
who break their words.
So be it.
Perhaps our negotiations will be
more fruitful with your successor.
Ventress, kill him!
Jedi Master Yoda.
I am very pleased to meet you,
at last.
Share the feeling, I do,
King Katoonku.
Failed you, Ventress has,
Count.
I don't fear you, Jedi.
Strong you are with the dark side,
young one,
but not that strong.
Still much to learn, you have.
Surrender, you should.
In the end,
cowards are those
who follow the dark side.
It's a pity I wasn't there in person,
my old master.
A pity, indeed,
my fallen apprentice.
Perhaps now,
begin negotiations, we can.
That is not necessary, my friend.
You have my faith.
Toydaria would be honored
to host a Republic base.
My people...
are at your service.
Your Majesty,
fail you, we will not.