Battle droids on Naboo!
As the Separatist rebellion
rages through the galaxy,
even peaceful planets
are threatened.
Following the discovery of Separatist
droids wandering the grassy wasteland,
Naboo is once again on high alert.
Fearing their home
is facing another invasion,
Senator Amidala
and Representative Binks
race to Naboo
to assess the situation.
Meanwhile,
near the Gungan swamplands,
an even graver threat
is about to be discovered.
We came as soon as we could, my Lady.
Have you found any more droids?
Only the three. But you can be sure
they aren't tourists.
I need you to convince the Senate
or the Jedi Council
or whoever is in charge of this terrible war
that we are threatened.
They'll need more proof.
Finding a couple of battle droids
will not be enough.
Captain Typho,
the battle droid is ready for analysis.
Have you been able to
retrieve any information?
Unfortunately,
the Naboo security who discovered them
prefer to shoot first
and retrieve data later.
If they were found
in the grasslands,
where'd they pick up all this mud?
Add that
to our very long list of questions.
Yummy-yummy.
I'm getting a bad feeling about this.
With your permission, Senator Padme,
I would like to shut down
before I get sensory overload.
- Permission denied.
- Denied?
3PO, you may be able to
get some information out of him.
Cannot see.
Where am I?
You are in very good hands
on board a Separatist ship.
Count Dooku himself intends
to reward you for your bravery.
- Bravery?
- For your assignment on Naboo.
Do try to activate
what's left of your memory.
We all want to hear
your tale of medical heroics.
Virus.
Yes, the virus.
You do remember. Please continue.
A small amount leaked out.
Must contain.
Naboo cannot know.
Lab must remain secret.
A secret lab on Naboo?
Where? You must...
It is a secret.
This is no Separatist ship.
Unless you want to become
a box of spare parts,
you'll tell us where that lab is.
- The lab is secret.
- Look out.
We'll never get any information
out of him now.
Meesa sorry.
It was an accident.
Is this what you're after?
Meesa love him.
He's a very, very good
tongue grabbing.
Yousa finden in one placen.
Where?
In the mud under the perlote tree.
Like the mud on this droid.
The eastern swamps.
I think Jar Jar just found out
the location of that lab.
They're planning an attack on Naboo.
It's the only explanation.
Delicate, the situation is.
Two Jedi, we will send.
May I recommend General Kenobi
and General Skywalker?
Relations with the Gungans
are a little tense right now,
but they trust General Kenobi
like one of their own.
Send them, we will.
I want as much information
as possible before the Jedi arrive.
See if you and 3PO can download
any of the other battle droids' memory.
I'm going to find that lab.
Are you sure that's wise?
Come on, Jar Jar.
Back!
That water gone poodoo.
This is muy bad.
This is bombad.
- Whatsa happen to them?
- It's the plague.
We're definitely getting close.
- Whosa are you?
- What you doing?
Why yousa here?
Whatsa yousa thinkin'?
Don't move.
I don't want to hurt you.
Jar Jar, put your helmet back on.
Yousa okeyday. It's not in the air,
it's in the water.
Who are you?
Meesa Peppi Bow.
We think the virus
that made your animals sick
came from the perlote trees.
Yousa follow thisa river,
yousa finda yousa perlote.
Meesa take you.
No, Peppi, you stay here.
You'll be going home soon,
I promise.
I'll send some soldiers to pick you up
and take you back to Theed.
Keep your eyes open.
Look for anything
out of the ordinary.
I suppose one can never have
too many lab rats.
Please, escort our guests inside.
Roger, roger.
A hatch.
Captain Typho, I think we're standing
right on top of the lab.
I need a geo scan
of coordinates SP127.
No way we're going to open this.
- We'll just have to...
- Freeze!
Hold it right there.
Yousa let us go.
Who are you?
Why are you holding us?
Wonderful specimens.
What's a life-form like you
doing in a swamp like this?
I was about to ask you
the same thing.
Thanks to the support
of my compassionate friends
in the Separatist Alliance,
I am creating life.
Howsa yousa creating life?
I'm so pleased you inquired.
A demonstration is in order.
Allow me to present
the return of the infamous
Blue Shadow virus.
The Blue Shadow virus?
I thought that deadly disease
was extinct.
Yes, it was wiped from the galaxy
generations ago,
but I have given it life once again.
Yousa not creating life.
Yousa taking life.
Yousa poisoned the Gungan water.
Unfortunately,
the Blue Shadow virus,
in its natural form,
thrives only in water
until I improved upon that weakness.
Your eyes do not deceive you.
I have perfected an airborne strain
of the Blue Shadow virus.
This is the last of the bombs,
doctor.
I'm well aware this is the last.
You think I'd lose count?
The virus in its gaseous forms
combined with these bombs
will release the Blue Shadow virus
back into the galaxy,
more potent than ever before.
Are you insane?
It's a deadly disease.
No life-forms are immune to it.
That's why it was eradicated.
You mean murdered.
Take this away.
Meanwhile, as we speak,
thousands and thousands
of so-called
superior life-forms
are spreading their disease of war
throughout the galaxy.
Perhaps they are the ones
who should be eradicated.
General Kenobi, Anakin,
we're so glad...
Where's Senator Amidala?
- She went to look for the lab.
- And you let her go?
Senator Padme can be very hard to stop
once she has made up her mind.
- Good point. I know what you mean.
- This is Peppi Bow.
She was the last person to see them.
- Padme sent her here to safety.
- Theysa looking for the sick-maker.
- "They"?
- Representative Binks was with her.
Go with the Gungan.
See if you can find them.
You've got it, Master.
Why didn't you send someone
to look for them?
Considering the latest developments,
we thought it was best to wait for you.
What latest developments?
We did a robo-lobotomy
on the battle droids
and came up
with this piece of memory.
Who is that?
Dr. Nuvo Vindi,
the senior medic
for the Perma families.
He disappeared ten years ago.
Good news,
my soulless automaton friends.
We now have enough
of the Blue Shadow virus
to start filling the bombs.
He said "bombs. "
We will only need to send one bomb
to each key star system.
Work quickly.
I want them ready to deliver...
If those bombs get delivered,
we'll be facing a galaxy-wide plague.
The war will be
the least of our worries.
There is some good news.
Senator Amidala found the lab.
She sent us the coordinates
before she disappeared.
We've managed to get
a geo scan of the area.
- It's enormous.
- It looks like there are 3 entry points.
Here, here, and here.
This appears to be the main lab.
And the bombs?
There seems to be
an above average amount of radiation
in this area.
It's likely
where they're being assembled.
If Padme has alerted them
to our presence in any way...
If Padme's in there, and then we go in
guns a-blazin', she may get killed.
It is a risk we have to take.
Dr. Vindi and those bombs
must not leave the lab.
And if they or we detonate one
during the attack?
Better to have one planet infected
than the entire galaxy.
These the ship belonging to them.
So where are they?
Their tracks end here.
Peppi, it's a scope.
Don't let them see you.
- Where are they?
- Patience.
They'll be here in a moment.
You seem a bit on edge.
There's a good chance we're about
to destroy all life on this planet,
including ours and the senator's,
so yes, I'm a bit on edge.
- Why aren't you?
- I'm better at hiding it.
- Master, are you there?
- Did you find her?
Negative. I'm pretty sure
she's inside the lab.
The whole area is wired
with pressure sensors.
There's no way to get in
without being detected.
- But I'm more than happy to...
- Do not attempt to get inside.
I need you to detonate a bunker bomb
at the south end of the facility.
It should cause a nice distraction
and seal off the bomb area
while we come in
through the hatches.
You can count on me.
Rex and his men
will be right behind you, Snips.
They'll have your back.
Come on, we'd better hurry.
Padme may be lost, Anakin.
Don't risk the mission
trying to rescue her.
I'll take care of the bombs.
You focus on the doctor.
I know what's at stake here.
Now!
We have a breach!
All droids to hatch number one!
Friends of yours, I assume.
They arrived quicker
than I would've thought.
- Meesa come too?
- No.
Stay here and make sure
no one escapes.
Okeyday.
It's quiet in here.
Looks like Ahsoka's distraction
is working.
Forward! Come on!
Fall back!
Padme!
Take another step
and your friends die.
Drop your weapons.
Wait!
Do as he says.
I can't hold them.
Need some help?
So good to see you, Master Kenobi.
I realize I won't be able
to hold you for long, Jedi.
That is why
I'm going to give you a choice.
Fine with me, as long as
one of the options is killing you.
How about capture me
or save your friends?
Are you okay?
Ani, how about
the next time you rescue me
before you kill
all the battle droids?
A little "thank you"
would go a long way.
Things are going well.
The lab is secure, and hopefully,
Anakin has reached Padme by now.
I'll get the bombs.
I'll keep the droids occupied.
Grab your blasters.
We need to find that doctor.
Well, looks like the bomb room.
Yes, and luckily,
they appear inactive.
I spoke too soon.
Get these deactivated now!
Anakin, I'm guessing
you didn't capture the doctor.
I'm working on it.
Do you have the bombs?
Dr. Vindi has
remotely activated the bombs.
- They're counting down.
- That's great.
And on top of that,
- one of them seems to be missing.
- It's down here somewhere.
Ahsoka, we've got another situation.
Send all the clones
to search the facility.
- We've got a mis...
- Master?
We've got a missing bomb and
a trigger-happy mad doctor on the loose.
Missing bomb? I saw Dr. Vindi
give a little droid a bomb.
You guys split up.
Find that droid.
You heard him. Let's move!
Jedi!
Leaving so soon, doctor?
You are running out of time.
Catch!
Obi-Wan, Dr. Vindi's escaping!
He's at the landing platform.
All right.
I'm on my way.
Something smells good in here.
Hey, there, little guy.
How about
you hand that over to me?
He's getting away!
Ahsoka,
I found the last bomb.
Stay there.
I'll get the bomb squad.
Almost got it.
Don't shoot! If he drops
one of those vials, we're finished.
No, no-sa!
You're under arrest, Dr. Vindi.
The bomb's going off,
and we're all going to die!
Yeah, die!
Oops.
What happened?
Deactivated.
Plenty of time to spare.
Plenty of...
- Ahsoka, are you there?
- I'm here, Master.
The bomb has been deactivated.
Did you find Vindi?
Deactivated as well.
Have you seen Padme?
She's right next to me.
I'm okay, too.
Thanks for asking.