Viceroy Gunray captured!
Senator Padme Amidala
has scored a victory
against the Separatist alliance
on the remote world of Rodia,
securing the arrest
of diabolical confederate leader
Nute Gunray.
The Jedi council has dispatched
Master Luminara Unduli
and Anakin Skywalker's
padawan Ahsoka
to escort the viceroy
to Coruscant under heavy guard.
Once there, he will face trial
for his many war crimes.
Captain, have you made contact
with the cruiser?
Yes, General.
We'll patch you through now.
Jedi cruiser Tranquility,
this is General Luminara Unduli
requesting permission to land.
You are clear, General.
- We await your prisoner's arrival.
- Thank you, Captain Argyus.
I look forward to
delivering him to you.
I am a man of great wealth,
and I can be very generous
to my allies.
That is a very tempting offer,
Viceroy.
In the meantime,
I have a gift for you.
Finally.
It's been such a boring trip.
This is an outrageous
miscarriage of justice.
- I demand my litigator.
- Keep moving.
Greetings, General. We have the brig
all ready for this traitor.
Very good, Captain.
Commander Gree, let's get under way.
Right away, sir.
Let's move!
Senate commandos?
How does a money-grubbing worm
like Gunray rate all this security?
He doesn't look that dangerous.
Don't let your overconfidence
give Gunray another advantage, Ahsoka.
Even now,
his allies may be conspiring
against us.
Gunray's capture
could be a serious threat to us,
my friend.
The viceroy will not last long
under Jedi interrogation.
I have already put a plan
into action, My Lord.
My best agent, Asajj Ventress,
will infiltrate the Jedi ship
and either free Gunray
or silence him.
Ventress?
You are putting
a great deal of faith
in an operative
who has failed us in the past.
She is a gifted assassin.
You have my word...
she will complete
her mission to the letter.
Very well.
You may proceed.
Master.
There is no margin for error
this time, child.
You must prove yourself
worthy of being my apprentice.
I am worthy,
as you shall see.
How goes the interrogation?
- Has the viceroy cracked?
- Not yet.
Neimoidians are a slippery lot,
but the Jedi will wear him down.
Your thoughts betray you, Viceroy.
I can sense your concern,
the fear that you will lose
the wealth
and the power
that the war has given you.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
You hide a great many things.
The names of your secret allies,
the locations of their bases.
I am an innocent pawn
in all of this.
If you're merely a pawn,
then who are you protecting?
No one.
I know nothing.
Liar! Liar!
I'm tired of all this whining.
Tell us what we want to know
right now,
or I will gut you
like a Rokarian dirt fish.
Padawan!
Terror is not a weapon the Jedi use.
I wasn't serious.
But the only way he'll talk
is if he's scared enough.
Perhaps I was too hasty.
Let us negotiate.
Captain, status report.
Droid fighters incoming.
They've brought boarding ships.
Green company,
prepare to repel the enemy.
Green leader to Commander Gree.
Super battle droids
have breached our hull.
They're headed
for the detention level.
We need reinforcements.
- Commander, I'll need your assistance.
- Let's go.
You will stay here
with Captain Argyus.
- Guard the viceroy.
- But...
As you wish, Master.
It appears you are in no position
to negotiate after all, Padawan.
- Perhaps after my rescue...
- Rescue?
Maybe they're here
to make sure you won't talk.
All units, there's a bo...
Trooper, what have you found?
Come in, trooper.
Do you copy?
Super battle droids are everywhere.
Fall back to the detention level.
We have to protect the prisoner.
See anything?
Engine room seems clear.
- We'll lock it down.
- Good, Captain.
The enemy's advancing
toward the prison level.
- We're on our way.
- You keep watch here, 327.
Okay, 327-T.
You know droids never like
to be called by their nicknames.
There. Looks like
the last of them, General.
Yes, Commander,
but I sense our troubles
are not over.
Sounds like your rescue
didn't work out after all.
I am ready to discuss
our bargain again.
Padawan Tano,
may I have a word?
Certainly, Captain.
If I leave,
you won't go anywhere, will you?
I've got the all-clear.
The enemy has been repelled.
And their attempt
to free Gunray has... failed?
If it isn't the hairless harpy.
If it isn't Skywalker's filthy,
obnoxious little pet.
How nice of you.
Tell you what,
I'll give you a merciful death.
The padawan.
Come on.
Shoot her!
Skywalker's not here
to save you now.
Good thing I don't need saving.
Over here!
Open this door,
and I'll buy you a planet.
Yes!
Yes, such delicious irony.
How do you like your room now,
youngling?
Halt, assassin!
Surrender.
What are we waiting for?
Ahsoka!
Thanks.
Everything's running haywire.
Doors, lifts...
Communication's down.
Propulsion's dead.
She's crippled the entire ship.
Our attacker has come for Gunray.
Stay here and guard him.
I'll confront her myself.
Master, all due respect,
but Ventress is too powerful
for any one Jedi to fight alone.
Let me help you.
I am more than capable
of dealing with a lone assassin
armed with
undisciplined fighting skills.
- But...
- Stay here and keep a clear head.
Luminara Unduli
may be a Jedi master,
but she has no idea
what that bog witch is capable of.
No idea!
I can't let her
face that lowlife alone.
Wouldn't we have a better chance
of stopping her if I helped?
Sometimes being a good soldier
means doing what you think is right.
That's why we're superior to droids.
Do you think you'll still be
able to call on the Force
after I've separated your head
from your body?
Even with my vision clouded,
I recognize the fighting style
of Count Dooku.
Your version is unrefined,
amateurish,
sloppy.
I can't disobey a direct order
and leave my post,
- can I?
- I wouldn't.
Don't worry.
We've got this under control,
Master Jedi.
Your friend won't be going anywhere.
All I know is,
I never risk my own skin
if I don't have to.
What?
- Watch him closely.
- You can trust us, Commander.
Call us if you need help, sir.
Now you fall...
as all Jedi must.
I know, I know.
You told me to stay.
Well, as long as you're here...
We have to find her.
We can't let her get to Gunray.
What's that, Captain?
Nothing to worry about.
What are you doing?
No, please don't.
Do shut up.
Count Dooku is paying me a fortune
to deliver your slimy carcass.
So please, try to stay alive.
- Ahsoka?
- What happened to "Padawan Tano"?
This assassin...
I've never faced
an adversary like her.
I should have listened
to your advice.
Master, I never meant to
overstep my bounds, but...
General Unduli,
we've been betrayed.
Argyus has freed Gunray.
I've been a fool.
Let's get back there.
We'll take her together.
Stop!
This is your last warning.
Don't shoot.
I am an innocent pawn.
He won't shoot.
He doesn't want to damage his prize.
- Stand down, Captain.
- Come and get me.
Why'd you do it, Argyus?
A clone like you
would never understand.
I wanted a life with more
than empty servitude.
And for that,
you'd betray the Republic?
Like I told the padawan,
sometimes being a good soldier
means doing what you think is right.
You and I disagree
on what makes a good sold...
You should have taken my offer
when you had the chance,
clone.
The outer shields are still down.
The ship is still in turmoil.
We're home free.
As successful a rescue
as one could hope for, Viceroy.
I will be a legend for this.
I always had a good feeling
about you, Captain.
You see, assassin?
Our plan went off without a hitch.
Our plan?
And I will, of course,
make sure your contributions
are noted
in my report to Count Dooku.
I'll tell him myself.
Greetings, Viceroy.
I always had a good feeling
about you, assassin.
I'm sorry that despicable
wealth-worm Gunray got away.
It's okay, Snips.
I know you did your best.
Master, I...
Troubling, is the treachery
of the Senate guard...
Captain Argyus.
Revealed all around us,
our enemies are.
I'm not sure all is lost.
Gunray and his accomplices stole
a Republic ship to make their getaway.
It could be tracked.
- Indeed.
- A coward, Viceroy Gunray is,
but powerful allies, he has.
Swiftly, we must move,
if we are to recapture him.
Master Fisto's fleet
was near Gunray's position.
I've already contacted him
to follow the signal.
Ahsoka, I'll meet you
at the rendezvous point.
Yes, Master.
Master Luminara,
I guess this is good-bye for now.
I owe you my life, Ahsoka.
Protecting a Jedi master
is the role of the padawan.
And teaching is usually
the role of the master.
Master Skywalker should be proud.
Farewell.
Thank you, Master.
Commander,
let's get under way.
Yes, General.
Ahead full.