Republic outpost overrun!
The Jedi have lost all contact
with the clone security force
stationed on the bleak
snow-covered planet of Orto-Plutonia.
Obi-Wan Kenobi and Anakin Skywalker,
accompanied by dignitaries
from the nearby moon of Pantora,
are sent to investigate
the disappearance of the clone troopers
on the desolate
and forbidding landscape.
And this is the planet's
tropical zone.
It's not Tatooine, that's for sure.
Captain Rex,
have your men survey the area.
Place as many sensor beacons
as you can before dark.
Right away, sir.
Unload that gear!
Let's move!
Why would the Republic
want an outpost way out here?
The chairman...
of Orto-Plutonia requested it?
Why?
General Kenobi.
Chairman Cho, Senator Chuchi.
I suggest you wait here
until we can secure the area.
I respect your judgment,
General Kenobi,
but I will go where I choose.
This is sovereign Pantora territory.
I thought this planet was uninhabited,
and therefore, it's not aligned.
Our moon of Pantora
is the only civilization in this system.
I'm the one who asked the Senate
to protect this planet.
This wasteland belongs to us.
With all due respect, Chairman,
this is for the Senate to decide,
not us.
But the Jedi report to the Senate,
which is Senator Chuchi of Pantora.
Technically speaking, Master Jedi,
the chairman is correct.
Since the planet is uninhabited,
the moon of Pantora reserves the right
to continue as its protectorate.
Point taken, Senator.
Anakin, stay here with the senator
and the droids
while we secure the base.
I don't get it.
It must be Separatists.
I am not sure.
Might we go inside, Master Anakin?
R2 would like to
get out of the cold.
We'll go inside as soon as
Obi-Wan signals that it's safe.
Do you think the Separatists are building
a forward base to attack Pantora?
I don't think we're dealing
with Separatists.
These computers
haven't been touched.
Sir, our scouts have spotted
a droid base
on the other side of the ice ridge.
By the look of things,
I'd say whoever attacked our base
took out the droids also.
Rex, help Anakin
place the sensor beacons.
- You four, come with me.
- Yes, General.
Let's go.
Did you find anything?
I found some large footprints.
Have one of your men make a cast.
- Sensors are in place.
- I think I've found something.
Blast it.
685 to command.
There are too many of them!
They've overrun the base.
We need reinforcements!
- What was that?
- Whatever it was, it's a good warrior.
The droid's log indicates they were
investigating the southern canyon.
Sounds like a good place to start.
I want the weapon system back online
and the shields operational.
There's no telling
what the Separatists have planned.
Chairman, what makes you so certain
the Separatists
are behind this attack?
Look around, Senator.
Isn't this carnage proof enough?
I know,
but there are no dead droids here,
no blast marks. The clones' injuries
were not consistent with what...
So you're an expert on war now,
are you, Senator?
No, Chairman.
- No, I only...
- Let me tell you something, Senator.
I have led our people
since before you were born.
I've seen 100 planets rise and fall
through force of arms.
If it's not the Separatists
out there,
then it's a malevolent
and aggressive enemy nonetheless.
And I will not let whoever it is
jeopardize the security
of the people of Pantora.
But if the Jedi discover
that the Separatists aren't behind this,
then perhaps
there is a peaceful resolution.
Senator, I am willing to fight and die
for my people.
It's time to ask yourself
if you are brave enough to do the same.
There's some kind of reflection
up there.
Do you see it?
Yep.
Well, they know we're coming.
Let's go.
Steady, Anakin.
They're only curious.
Let's not provoke them as the droids
and our troops must have done.
Too bad we didn't bring 3PO along.
How do you plan on communicating
with these things?
Patience.
Maybe they're smarter than we are.
Well, say something.
Just shut up.
We come to you in peace.
We will not bring harm.
Peace.
Glad you made it back, sir.
It's getting nasty out there.
You don't know the half of it.
What did you find?
It seems we've stumbled
onto an inhabited planet.
Impossible.
Our explorers have spent much time here
over the long history of Pantora.
No one lives here.
They're trespassers.
With respect, Chairman Cho,
these creatures, the Talz,
aren't advanced enough
to master space travel.
I think they may have been here
longer than Pantora.
Whoever they are, they belong to us.
This whole system belongs to us.
Your Majesty,
if there are life forms here,
then the Senate
must decide jurisdiction.
They are savages.
Look at what they've done.
They've slaughtered your troops.
They only want to be left alone.
The droids attacked them, and I'm afraid
our outpost got caught in the middle.
They must be subdued.
They're dangerous.
Captain Rex,
prepare your troops for battle.
We promised their chief
there would be no retaliation.
We've arranged a meeting
between their High Council and you
and the senator.
They want peace.
We can't send troopers.
They'll think we lied.
These creatures
are little more than animals.
You can't lie to an animal.
They can't be trusted.
- But, Your Majesty...
- No!
It is obvious
these creatures are not covered
by the convention
of civilized systems.
The Jedi Council
has no say in the matter.
If the Jedi are able
to communicate with them,
their status is in doubt.
Do you stand against your chairman,
Senator?
Of course not, Your Majesty.
If we're going to meet with Thi-Sen
and his council at the arranged time,
we'll have to leave now.
Sir, the gunships can't
take off in this storm.
We don't have enough bikes
for the entire platoon.
Have the rest of the men
stand by here.
No matter what the chairman thinks,
we're not going to war.
Captain, put your men
on that ice ridge.
We will attack
as soon as the savages arrive.
- There will be no attack, Chairman.
- You will do as I command.
This planet
is under my jurisdiction.
Nothing is under your control,
Chairman.
The Talz are already here.
Their scouts have been following us
for some time.
It seems Thi-Sen doesn't trust you
any more than you trust him.
Rex, tell your men to stand down.
Stay here and don't do anything
to provoke them.
Yes, sir.
- Your Highness.
- We have returned...
...as promised.
These savages have no rights here.
Chieftain Thi-Sen
welcomes you to his home
and hopes you come in peace.
He wishes to be good neighbors,
but he does not wish you
to remain on his planet.
Listen, droid,
translate everything I say,
and exactly as I say it.
Would you like me to
represent Pantora in this matter?
Not on your life, Senator.
There will be no diplomacy this time.
Listen here, you savage.
This world belongs
to the moon of Pantora.
And as the Supreme Chairman
and exalted ruler of Pantora,
you will not command me to leave
this planet or do anything else.
Your Majesty, we can't.
Droid, tell him.
Oh dear.
I recommend
a less confrontational discussion.
The Talz are easily provoked.
That didn't go over very well.
Chairman, I promised the Talz
that we would leave them in peace.
This is now an internal affair
of Pantora.
The great Thi-Sen, son of suns,
asks again that you leave
or it will mean war.
Then war it is.
Troopers, mount up and follow me.
What's up, General?
You're going to have to
stay with the chairman
until we can work things out.
Protect him at all costs.
Mount up! We're moving out!
Senator, you know
a pre-emptive strike is illegal.
Isn't there anything you can do
to stop him?
I'm afraid not.
He has proclaimed this conflict
an internal affair.
You could petition the Jedi Council
for an intervention.
You mean, without his authorization?
There must be someone on your moon
who could approve it.
The speaker of the assembly.
He has the power.
Let's get back to the base.
The storm is letting up.
Maybe we can get
a transmission through.
Here they are.
Fire when you're in range.
Sir, with all due respect,
we're only here to protect you.
- Ambush!
- It's a trap. Kill them!
We're surrounded.
Defensive formation!
Chairman, get down!
We've got to hold out!
Fall back!
First squad, cover the retreat!
Retreat?
We can't retreat from these animals.
Savages.
The assembly has decided
that the actions of Chairman Cho
are out of order.
Senator Chuchi,
you're given the authority
to negotiate a peaceful settlement
between the sovereign planet
of Pantora and the Talz.
- It is decided then.
- Pilot, let's get moving.
Here they come!
Senator, now that you have
the authority,
how do you plan on making peace
with the Talz?
Actually, Master Jedi,
since you're far more experienced,
I was hoping you could negotiate
on Pantora's behalf.
I'm afraid that's not possible,
Senator.
But I don't understand.
The Jedi serve the Senate.
- I must order you to...
- Senator,
it is your people
the Talz are at war with.
If the violence is to stop, it is you
who must represent your people.
- Good to see you, sir.
- You okay, Rex?
- It's just a scratch.
- What's going on?
We're in quite a mess, sir.
11 dead, the rest wounded,
including the chairman.
Chairman, can you hear me?
Senator, good.
You must avenge me.
As my final command
as chairman of Pantora,
I order you to destroy the Talz!
I'm afraid
I cannot do that, Chairman.
The Pantoran assembly
has called you out of order.
I am to negotiate peace.
No.
Impossible!
Peace?
Never!
I died for our people.
Senator,
now is the time.
Protocol droid, come with me.
3PO, get going.
Yes, Master Ani.
Droid,
- translate for me.
- Yes, Mistress.
To die for one's people
is a great sacrifice.
To live for one's people,
an even greater sacrifice.
I choose to live for my people.
What do you choose?
He chooses to live as well.
We will leave Orto-Plutonia
under the watchful eyes of the Talz
from this day forth
and recognize your sovereignty
as a free and equal people.
- Well done, Senator.
- Yes, most impressive.
Thank you, Master Jedi.
Now that you have created peace
between your people and the Talz,
remember one crucial thing.
Yes, Master Kenobi?
Make it last, Senator.
Make it last.
And be an example to others,
so not only this war,
but every war waged
may come to an end as well.
I will.
I promise you.