Galactic showdown!
In a fierce battle for survival,
the Republic and separatist
armies have clashed in the
distant sullust system.
Count dooku's most cunning
assassin, asajj ventress,
leads the vicious attack.
Trident group one, attack
the starboard engines.
Trident group two, knock out
their port shield generators.
I'll go directly for their bridge.
The port side deflectors are gone.
Lord tyranus.
My master.
There is a disturbance in the force.
Your assassin, she has
become very powerful.
Yes, my lord.
She is quite important to me.
Too important.
Master...
Silence.
I can sense her powers
growing stronger.
I would hate to think you
are training your own sith
apprentice to destroy me.
Never.
My allegiance is to you and you alone.
Then you must prove it.
Eliminate her.
She's my most trusted...
I said eliminate her!
As you wish, my lord.
Ventress.
Split up.
Looks like I'm her favorite.
I'm kind of disappointed.
Only the droids follow me.
You want to race?
Come on.
Anakin, I'm going to need some help.
Where are you?
Clang!
I'm hit!
I'm heading toward the
separatist flagship.
I see you.
I've got her.
Master, I need your help quickly.
I'm surrounded.
You have already lost
the battle, child.
I've ordered your
reinforcements to return.
No.
I will destroy the jedi.
I'll show you.
You have failed me for the last time.
You are no longer my apprentice.
And now you shall die.
Obi-Wan. Obi-Wan!
No, thank you.
No... thank you, artoo.
That's quite enough.
Ventress, you're not looking well.
She never does.
You have failed, ventress.
Surrender.
Never.
Ah!
Whoosh!
Yes, my lord.
Ventress is battling the jed
on board the command ship.
Turn your guns on our
command ship and open fire.
But, my lord, I calculate that
will destroy ventress, the jedi,
and all our forces.
Precisely.
Ah!
Uh!
Yah!
Ah!
We're in position.
Open fire.
Ah!
That is correct.
Calculate your flight path to
terminate in the main hangar.
It's over.
Anakin, look out!
We have to get out of here.
Abandon ship!
The command ship has been destroyed.
Our scanning indicates
there are no survivors.
Your work there is finished.
Recall the fleet.
By your command.
Master.
What is it, lord tyranus?
I have done as you've asked.
Asajj ventress is dead.
Once again, you've proven
your loyalty to me.
You took quite a beating there.
Didn't you, missy?
Which side of the battle was you on?
Aw.
Not too talkative, are you?
Take me to dathomir.
Now, why would anyone
want to go there?
Ain't nothing there
but fog and witches.
Exactly.
Whoosh!
We don't like strangers.
I'm not a stranger.
Prepare to die.
Stop.
She is one of us.
Take her to the village.
Who is she?
What is she doing here?
Shh. Quiet.
Mother...
Talzin.
Bring the water of life.
At last, you have returned,
and you are safe again.
I remember the day we were
forced to give you up
to protect the clan.
Your sacrifice has
never been forgotten.
Master.
Master, where are you?
They've killed you.
Whoosh!
Ah!
You are strong with the
force, little one.
Thank you, master.
Master!
Ah!
Revenge.
I must have revenge.
I can sense the darkness within you.
I will teach you the
ways of the dark side.
But you must prove yourself first.
Master, I need your help quickly.
I've ordered your
reinforcements to return.
No, I will destroy the jedi.
I'll show you.
You have failed me for the last time.
And now you shall die.
Dooku.
He betrayed me.
I know.
I had hoped you would find
your way to us sooner.
I will have revenge.
Yes, you shall, sister.
We will see to it.
Karis and naa'leth are the
greatest warriors of our coven.
I'll be the judge of that.
They will help you
destroy count dooku.
Alnadee, mah, reez,
ven, doo, la, tren.
Nadee, mah, reez, ven,
doo, la, tren.
Sister.
We have assembled a
potion for you to use
in order to reach dooku's
palace undetected.
Step into the mist and
become like shadows.
Now you are invisible to most.
Even count dooku?
Yes.
Perhaps even count dooku.
What if he can sense us?
Take this poison dart.
It will dull his senses
and distort his vision.
Then you can deal with him easily.
Jedi weapons.
You'll need these.
If the count engages you, he
must believe that you are jedi.
Naa'leth and karis,
serve your sister well.
Deliver your vengeance, sister.
Then return to us.
We shall prevail.
This way.
He's below us.
You can sense him?
I can smell his stench a parsec away.
Be on guard at all times.
He is no fool.
He is a sith lord.
Zip!
Ah.
What sorcery is this?
I do not need my eyes
to see you, jedi.
Ah!
He is stronger than I imagined.
I warned you.
Mother, we've...
We've failed.
Where one sees failure,
others see opportunity.
What do you mean, mother?
Your infiltration proves
dooku is vulnerable.
He will be eager to protect himself.
How?
By finding a replacement for you.
Count dooku.
It has been too long.
Yes, mother talzin.
How may I assist you?
It has come to my attention
that you have lost your most
prized assassin.
How would you know of this?
I know these things.
I have seen it.
After all, she was once one of us.
It is true that your warriors are
of an extraordinary caliber.
Perhaps something different this time.
Perhaps a male from our planet
will be more to your liking,
since you could not tame the female.
I shall take you up on your offer.
Excellent.
I will be in contact.
I will see count dooku dead.
I swear it.
So you shall.