A separatist have launched
a massive offensive
against the planet Ryloth.
A blockade of
deadly battleships
has cut off any support
for the dwindling
Republic defenses.
Though they have fought
Valiantly with the help of
Twi'lek freedom fighter
Cham Syndulla,
hold his faith in jedi master
Di and his men as the droid
Army closes in.
Master jedi, we're running
Out of food and water,
And our heavy weapon systems
Are out of power.
I'll contact our forces
In orbit.
Admiral Dao, this is general Di.
We're in trouble down here.
We need those supplies
Immediately.
I understand, general, but I
Am in no position to help.
We are critically low on fuel
And ammunition.
Contact the jedi
Council again!
Tell them reinforcements must be
Dispatched without delay!
If help does not arrive soon,
The entire outer rim garrison
Will be wiped out.
Surely there must be
Something you can do...
The main reactor's
Been hit, sir.
Systems are shutting down.
We are dead in space.
With regret, I report that
My fleet will no longer be able
To provide protection for the
Troops on Ryloth.
I repeat my request that help
Be sent right away.
The shields are gone.
We have no...
Trapped on Ryloth
Master Di and his men are.
My trade mission was
Successful,
Thank you for asking.
But what's the matter?
You all look very somber.
Senator, the fleet
Protecting Ryloth has been
Destroyed, and the supply
The troops are out of food,
Fuel, ammunition.
And the civilian population
Is starving.
That is grim news.
Our blockade runners should
Be able to penetrate the
Separatist lines and drop
Relief supplies.
But they do not have the range
To reach Ryloth.
The planet Toydaria is 2,000
Parsecs closer than the
Nearest fleet.
If the blockade runners can
Supply from there, they might
Reach Ryloth in time.
What would you have me do?
We've dispatched a ship
Loaded with relief supplies to
Meet you on Toydaria.
You are a more experienced
Diplomat than the representative
From naboo who is already there.
Senator amidala is an
Excellent negotiator.
I am sure...
Senator amidala could not
Leave the senate.
Representative Binks
Accompanied the shipment.
You must negotiate the treaty
So that we can dispatch ships
From Toydaria and get Ryloth
The relief supplies it needs.
I understand perfectly.
This had better be important.
Sir, we intercepted a coded
Transmission between senator
Organa and the jedi council.
We were able to partially
Unscramble it.
The jedi have sent senator
Organa to Toydaria to negotiate
A treaty which would allow them
To send relief supplies
To their forces on Ryloth.
Send a message
To senator lott dod
Of the trade federation.
I wish to speak with him
Immediately.
Stop where you are,
Offworlder.
We will provide you whatever
You need to continue
Your journey,
But you may not leave the ship.
I am senator bail Organa
Of the galactic republic.
I come to speak with the high
Exalted king of Toydaria.
Hi-Lo!
Let meesa through.
Meesa on a diplomatic mission.
Senator Organa!
It's a pleasure to be
Seeing yousa.
And you,
Representative Binks.
Shall we?
Our laws of hospitality
Demand that we offer assistance,
But this planet is closed
To offworlders.
We are obliged to deliver
Our message to your king
In person.
It won't take a minute.
H-Lo?
Yousa majesty?
Let me do the talking, okay?
State your business,
Offworlders.
Representative Binks
Of naboo.
Senator bail Organa of
Alderaan, sire.
We have come to ask for
Your help.
Perhaps you failed to pay
Attention to the senate
Orientation.
They should have explained that
Toydaria is a neutral system.
We are not part of the republic.
Yes, your majesty.
That is why we have come before
You as friends.
There is a humanitarian crisis
On Ryloth.
Millions will be starvin' and
Dyin' without your help.
My esteemed colleague and I
Humbly beg that you allow us to
Use Toydaria as a staging
Ground to supply the planet
With relief aid.
Do not make your decision in
There are other factors
You might wish to consider.
I believe you know lott dod,
Senator for the trade
Federation.
Yes, we are acquainted.
Senator.
Beggin' your highness,
What'sa he doing here?
Why shouldn't he be?
Toydaria has an important
Contract with his
Trade federation.
The trade federation is too
Chummy with the separatists
For my taste.
We have nothing to do with
The separatists!
Nute gunray is an extremist.
His views do not reflect those
Perhaps not.
The confusion.
We are only here to ensure
That nothing jeopardizes the
Agreement between Toydaria and
The trade federation.
Naboo and alderaan have
A long tradition of providing
Humanitarian aid.
I see no reason for conflict.
Nor do I.
The people of Ryloth
Are suffering,
And compassion is a sacred
Toydarian value.
Honesty is also a toydarian
Value, is it not?
I'm sure the senator mentioned
Around Ryloth.
A blockade?
Is this true?
Yes, your majesty.
But it changes nothing.
Inconceivable!
It changes everything.
Help the republic, it will
Destroy our neutrality.
I must convene my ministers,
Then we shall hear
Your arguments.
General Di, the right flank
Has collapsed.
The droids will be closing in
On our position.
What about reinforcements?
Communication has
Been spotty.
I promise you, cham,
The republic
Will not abandon Ryloth.
I've heard enough of your
Promises, jedi.
The fact remains: If we stay
Here without reinforcements,
We're all going to die.
Gobi, tell the people
We're leaving.
Yes, sir.
I don't think you
Understand.
The right flank has collapsed.
There's no leaving.
We're stuck here together.
We will now hear arguments
In the matter of using
Toydarian territory to aid the
Shipment of relief supplies to
The citizens of Ryloth.
Senator Organa.
Thank you, your majesty.
The operation the republic
Humanitarian.
We wish to deliver food and
Medical supplies to the people
Of Ryloth.
But if you won't listen to me,
Wise king, listen to senator
Orn free taa of Ryloth, who is
Well aware of the suffering of
His people.
Your highness, our cities
Lie in ruins.
Our transportation hubs are all
But destroyed, so I cannot
Return home.
Our crops burn.
The twi'lek people are starving.
And they will die if no aid
Comes to them.
I appeal to you, great king.
This is a crisis of
Planetary proportions.
We cannot let them starve.
The basic tenets of our
Morality and even our
Constitution demand that we
Help those in need.
Those ideals are noble, but
We must be careful that our
Compassion does not draw us
Into this war.
Senator dod, if you please.
Great king, senator Organa
Is deceiving you.
The inconvenient fact remains
That this is a war, and Ryloth
Is a battlefield.
The planet is under a separatist
Blockade because jedi knights
And clone soldiers
Are battling the droid army
For control of the surface.
This will not be
A humanitarian base.
It will be a military base.
The separatist senate will see
It as a violation of your
Neutrality.
That in turn will expose the
Trade federation's ships to
Attacks from the separatists
And force us to cease trade
With Toydaria, a situation
Desirable to no one.
We cannot...
How it might effect
Our economy.
Your majesty, the people of
Ryloth did not ask
To be invaded.
Do not let them suffer because
War came to them.
I sympathize with the plight
Of the twi'leks.
But this is not about saving
Them when they are fighting
Against the separatists.
Thank you, senators.
You have given us much
To consider.
I will summon you once I have
Made my decision.
Come on.
Hurry, hurry!
Captain,
Is the gunship ready?
Yes, sir.
But it's too small to evacuate
The refugees.
No escape?
But our families are with us.
If we reconfigure the fuel
System, we can turn the ship
Into a bomb big enough to
Collapse the pass here.
The enemy will then only be
Able to engage us on one front
From this ravine.
While we provide cover,
The twi'leks will have time to
Escape with their families over
The mountain.
Brilliant strategy, general.
I'll go tell the men.
After considerable debate,
I have made my decision.
I am sorry, senator Organa.
But for the sake of my people,
Toydaria must remain neutral.
A wise ruling, your majesty.
That did not go well.
What are weesa gonna do now?
My friends.
Toydaria cannot turn a blind eye
To the suffering of Ryloth.
The twi'leks are innocent
Victims caught between the
Warring factions through
No fault of their own.
I'm glad you agree,
Your highness.
What are you prepared to do?
You may use Toydaria
To transfer the supplies
You brought with you.
One, maybe two rotations.
It will have to do.
And you must guarantee that the
Trade federation will not be
Able to link Toydaria to
The mission.
Agreed.
I have an idea.
I'll signal you when the
Ships are ready to depart.
Meesa won't let you
Down, senator.
We're pleased
You could join us, senator.
Your majesty.
The pleasure is mine.
Formal dinners are
So tedious.
I am afraid that pressing
Matters require me to make
Immediate contact
But I leave you in the capable
Hands of my colleague,
Representative Binks.
General, we're loading the
Rest of the explosives onto
The gunship.
Very good, captain.
Ready the men.
All units:
Prepare for attack!
We won't be able to hold off
The droids for long.
You'll have to move quickly to
Get your families
Out of danger.
Cham is still angry.
He feels betrayed.
We counted on republic
Assistance, and it didn't come.
War turns promises into hopes.
I wish it wasn't so.
Tell him.
I will.
Captain keeli, tell the
Pilots to move the gunship
Into position.
This is command.
Are all the charges in place?
Copy that.
We're all ready.
The droid army is closing.
As soon as they're in range,
Blow up the gunship.
There is a gunship
Blocking our way.
Om-5, om-7, go check it out.
Careful, it might be full
Of clones.
Uh, no clones.
Just explosives.
Explosives?
Gotcha.
Beep!
Halt, halt!
We cannot get through.
We will have to find another
Way around.
Move those supplies into the
Transport as soon as possible.
Repeat, the ships are ready
To launch.
Uh, lookie, lookie!
Meesa proposing a conceptual
Ambassador of trade federation.
Uh, let's see.
I'll take that one.
Yeah, just give me.
Are you done with that?
That's really good.
I heard toydarians really like
That, but I'm taking it.
Thank you very much.
I'm sure you're finished
With that.
Did you enjoy that?
Did you like that one?
Well, I'll take it, thank you.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
I'll take that.
Gentlemen and gentlemen.
Here's a try this one.
Ah, you thought I was going
To drop...
I, here we go.
I'm spinning it.
One, two, three!
There is conceptual art piece.
Thank you.
Meesa just sharing my gungan art
With yousa and...
And meesa.
What are you looking at?
Meesa look at nothing!
At nothing.
Meesa creating and sharing
Gungan ritual style art
With trade federation...
To promote love
And understanding.
Steady.
Remember, we have to buy as
Much time for the twi'leks as
Possible.
Yes, sir.
For the republic!
For the twi'leks!
I'm not finished yet, sir.
We can do this, general.
Well, let's make the end
Memorable.
This is republic blockade
Runner oh-Niner-Niner.
We have broken through.
The twi'leks will live to
Fight another day.
The supplies have arrived at
The drop point.
It's food and medical
Supplies from the republic.
Safe journey, my friends.
I hope when we meet again it is
Under more pleasant
Circumstances.
Stop right there.
You look pale, senator.
I have just received
Information that a fleet of
Republic ships has penetrated
The blockade around Ryloth.
If the trade federation has
Proof of any treaty violation,
You're welcome to present it to
The full senate.
It takes years for the
Senate to decide anything.
You play a dangerous game,
Organa.
Next time, you will not get
Away with this.
The republic has heart,
My friend.
But I am not convinced it has
The strength to prevail.
However, after what I witnessed
Here today, perhaps it is time
I reconsidered our neutrality.
Tell the jedi I am open to
Meeting with them.
Master Yoda will be glad to
Hear it.
For now, at least,
The people of Ryloth
Shall endure.