Captured!
Returning from a perilous
assignment in the Outer Rim,
Jedi Master Even Piell's cruiser
has fallen under attack
and been boarded.
Seeking vital information he carries
about secret hyperspace lanes
called the Nexus Route.
Separatist forces have taken him alive.
Now the Jedi are preparing a stealth
mission into the heart
of Separatist space
in an effort to rescue master Piell
from the deadly prison
known as the Citadel....
As you are aware,
the citadel is their most isolated
and impenetrable detention facility.
No one has ever escaped.
There's a first time for everything.
Indeed there is.
Their security has prevented our probes
from obtaining recent reconnaissance,
so we've been forced
to construct a crude map
based upon data from the archives.
And since the data is extremely old,
the map will be difficult to rely on.
So we're essentially going in, blind.
Beg your pardon general,
But how do we know
master Piell is still alive?
The Separatists won't dare kill master
Piell until they have what they need.
He obtained the coordinates of a secret
hyperspace lane known as the Nexus route
which travels into the heart of both
the Republic and Separatist homeworlds.
They could prove vital
in maneuvering our forces
deep into remote separatist sectors.
Or the enemy could use them
to slip through our defenses
and attack Coruscant.
These hyperspace lanes are
of immense interest to both our sides,
and could tip the scale of the war to
whomever is in possession of them.
That is all.
Based on the archive schematics,
we've narrowed it down to three possible
locations they could be holding him at.
My greatest concern is,
infiltrating their outer security.
The life-form scanners will not
be easy to fool.
I've got a thought about that.
Master.
I'm sorry I'm late.
I just heard about the briefing.
We're going to rescue Master Piell, right?
but you won't be coming along on this one.
Not coming?
But you're breaking into the Citadel.
No one's ever done it.
The citadel wasn't designed
to hold common criminals.
It was created to hold Jedi
if any of us lost our way.
It's not a place for padawans.
You're just being protective again.
That's not fair.
How am I supposed to learn
if you won't let me share the risk?
This isn't a mission for learning.
You either do or die.
And that's not a risk
I'm willing to share.
Artoo, look out behind you.
You're being followed
by battle droids!
These are your troops?
They're battle droids.
What do you mean, they've been
reprogrammed to follow your orders?
We are awaiting your word, commander.
You heard him.
Move out.
Don't you go thumbing your gears
at me just because you have
a bunch of dim-witted
droids following you about.
Really.
We're trusting those droids
to get us into the citadel?
It's the only way.
We're flying right into the
heart of separatist territory.
Droids won't be detected.
Artoo, make sure they don't
stray from the flight plan.
It's all under control, sir.
I was talking to Artoo.
Master Plo?
May I speak with you?
What is it, little 'soka?
It's about the mission.
Master Skywalker doesn't
want me to go.
That is his choice.
I know, but I think he's
being overly protective.
He's picking and choosing which
assignments I can be a part of.
He is your master.
Yes, but
it's not for him to decide when
and how I should put my life in danger.
That should be my choice.
I've never been carbon-frozen
before, general.
It's the first time for us too.
This is your idea?
Carbon-freezing?
You wanted to shield us
from the life-form scanners.
Are, we sure this thing is safe.
I don't want to end up
a wall decoration.
Try to relax. We'll be unfrozen
as soon as we arrive.
May the force be with you.
Citadel command has contacted us.
This is central command.
Please identify yourself.
This is shuttle 81572.
Requesting access to citadel prison.
Make sure every part of that
ship is scanned for life-forms.
Yes, commander.
Make no mistake, the Jedi
will be coming for their
imprisoned brother.
They're not about to let one of their own
be tortured in the handing
over information that will help
the separatists win the war.
What is your cargo?
What is our cargo?
Supplies and frozen rations.
Do not deviate from your current course
until we have confirmed your cargo.
They're scanning us for life-forms.
I don't think this is working.
Quiet you're going to blow it.
The shuttle has no life-forms,
commander.
Scan complete.
You may proceed.
Fear.
A Jedi spends his whole life
training against it,
but at the Citadel, breaking
Jedi is our specialty.
Within these walls,
they will learn to fear us.
And if not, they die.
Hey, snips.
Hey, master.
I must have carbon sickness because
I could swear that's Ahsoka.
Your eyes are fine.
It's Ahsoka's hearing that needs help.
I received orders to join the team.
- I thought you knew.
- Oders?
- From who?
- I discussed it with master Plo.
He didn't tell me.
You were already in carbonite.
I gave you a specific
order not to come.
If there's one thing I've
learned from you, master,
it's that following
direct orders isn't
always the best way
to solve a problem.
I see Anakin’s new teaching method is
to "do as I say, not as I do."
Welcome aboard.
Guard the shuttle, Artoo.
We'll contact you when we're
ready for takeoff.
I see the entry point.
You were right.
The wind conditions are too strong for jetpacks.
Yes, we'll have to do it
the old-fashioned way,
with ascension cables
and a steel grip.
- I don't think so.
- What do you mean?
Electro-mines.
There's nowhere to put
a grappling hook at that height,
And we hit one of those,
the mission's over.
They'll know we're here.
I suppose that means we free-climb it.
you hanging in there, snips?
Couldn't be better.
I could do without the wind though.
The entry point is just
a few more meters.
They locked the door.
It's ray-shielded.
Ray-shielded?
That wasn't the plan.
Well, it's in the plan now.
There's an opening up there.
We know they're ventilation ducts,
but they're far too small
for us to gain access.
Too small for you maybe,
but I think I can squeeze through.
Well, we hadn't planned
on Ahsoka being here.
Perhaps she's right.
See, I can handle myself after all.
Sir, one of the cargo shuttles was
cleared for landing but never arrived.
Charger!
Well, they know we're here.
Sir, a mine in sector 9-g
was just detonated.
Mindless droids!
Activate all security protocols
lock everything down.
Where are my special units?
They are here, sir.
Clear.
Take out their surveillance.
The walls are electrified, go!
Go! Go! Go!
Longshot!
We must keep moving.
You're weakening.
You decide when the pain will stop.
Just give me the information.
No droid will ever break me.
Say good-bye to your
one good eye.
Secure the entrance.
Master Piell, are you all right?
Obi-wan.
What took you guys so long?
At least your sense
of humor is still intact.
It takes more than they got
to break me, young Skywalker.
So you have the coordinates
for the nexus route?
I got them, all right.
Half of them anyway.
My captain's got the other half.
I erased the computers when
we were boarded
and had both of us
memorize part of the intel.
That way, if somehow I cracked,
the information would be.
useless to them without
the other half.
Where's your captain?
Being held with the other
officers, I assume.
We're going to need a new
plan for getting out.
We need to keep moving.
Anakin!
Master!
You fools!
I hope you enjoyed the reunion.
With your fellow Jedi because
you're going to be my guests
for a very long time.
They're magnetized.
No, you don't.
- Are you all right, sir?
- Let's get out of here.
I hear something.
General.
Captain Tarkin.
I never thought I'd see you again.
And you brought friends.
Tarkin, this is Obi-Wan Kenobi
and Anakin Skywalker.
Now that you've found us, how
do you expect to get us out?
If they've locked this fortress down
there's at least ten
squads on their way.
It's going to be impossible
to escape.
What if we split up?
My team will create a diversion,
While Anakin leads the others away.
That way, if one of us is captured,
the enemy will only
have part of the information.
And not all of it.
General Kenobi, I think it's
better if we stick together.
A stronger force would have a better
chance of protecting the information.
Not in this situation.
But surely we'd have more strength
in numbers, rather than divide us.
Obi-wan has a point.
I'll go with him,
you go with Skywalker.
They escaped, sir.
Captain, show this droid what
happens when we use that word.
Sir, they've been spotted
heading for the upper levels.
They're trying to steal a transport.
Seal the landing platform
and send all battalions
to their positions.
Bring 'em back alive.
Everybody in.
This is one of the original
fortress tunnels.
The advantage of old archive data.
The tunnel's clear.
Looks like Obi-Wan's
distraction worked.
Things seem to be going as planned.
It's when things do not go
as planned that concerns me.
What then?
It's when things don't go as planned
that we Jedi are at our best.
Trust me.
I reserve my trust for those who
take action, general Skywalker.
Then let me remind you,
We rescued you back there
and I reserve my trust
for those who understand gratitude,
Captain Tarkin.