Mysterious deaths.
Unknown to the Jedi, a new threat
has been unleashed on the galaxy...
Savage Opress,
a pawn in the dangerous game between
Count Dooku and his
former assassin, Ventress.
The victims of his brutal
massacre on the planet of Devaron,
are being returned to the
Jedi temple for evaluation.
It's up to the Jedi council to find this
mysterious killer and eradicate him.
There were no survivors on Devaron.
Everyone was killed, including
master Halsey and his padawan.
In the past, only Dooku's assassin
was capable of such an effort,
but she was presumed dead
at the battle of Sullust.
Not everything is what it seems.
There may be a new threat.
Someone or something has eluded us.
Perhaps a new apprentice Sith Lord.
This is not the work of a
Sith Lord or a Jedi
but a reckless, impulsive animal.
You have no technique.
Sloppy.
But with the proper training,
you could be a powerful warrior.
You have a natural ability,
but we must hone it.
Are you up for the challenge of
putting your hate to better use?
Yes, master.
Master Yoda, you called for me?
Master Kenobi,
show you something we must.
We have recovered surveillance
footage of the massacre on Devaron.
Darth Maul alive?
It can't be.
I killed him myself.
Correct you are, Obi-Wan.
A creature of the same species he is,
from Dathomir.
Dathomir?
The planet of the witches?
I was under the impression that
Darth Maul's home world was Iridonia.
Dathomir is the planet
where Maul was raised.
Iridonia is where the rest of
the males of the species dwell.
Travel to Dathomir you must.
Find the source of
this threat you will.
You must strengthen your connection
with the force, my apprentice.
Feel its power within you.
What you ask is impossible.
Impossible?
The task is only impossible
because you have deemed it so.
You must connect with your hatred.
Focus on your power building.
Do not think of anyone
or anything else.
That's it.
Your anger is your strength.
I hate you.
Good.
How does one defend
against such power?
A wise master does not
reveal all his secrets at once.
In due time, my apprentice.
There's the village.
Be on guard.
These men are ferocious warriors,
and they will show no mercy.
Don't worry.
I won't start anything.
Let me handle the negotiations.
So much for not starting something.
Don't look at me.
Don't harm them.
Don't tell me, tell them.
Back off.
We are not here to fight you.
We're here for information.
A man from your village
murdered two Jedi.
We need to know where he is.
What makes you think
he is one of ours?
The Jedi council knows
he's from this village.
We have seen him.
Mother Talzin should
know of his whereabouts.
One of her women took him as a mate.
I apologize for the intrusion then.
Anakin, kindly release him, please.
Stop!
Let them go.
Who is this mother Talzin?
She's the leader of an ancient
order of witches, the nightsisters.
Great. Warrior-like men, witches...
- This place has all kinds of fun.
- I'm glad you think so.
You have completed
the first stages of your training,
and I am sending you on
an assignment to Toydaria.
You will bring me king
Katuunko, alive.
Kill all who might interfere.
Yes, my master.
It will be done.
I don't know much of mother Talzin,
but I don't expect to be
welcome here.
You never know.
I tend to be popular with the ladies.
Too popular.
We've got company.
Jedi, come with us.
Master Kenobi.
Mother Talzin,
thank you for your hospitality.
I believe you have
a question for me.
Yes, you're right.
We've had reports of a
Dathomiri male on the loose.
He's already killed two Jedi.
Perhaps you know who he is?
Master Jedi, we have no
control over the males.
Our clan has been
in exile for years.
Don't play innocent with me, mother.
Everyone in the galaxy knows females
are dominant on this planet.
I do not believe anything happens
here without your clan knowing about it.
To think that the Jedi collect their
facts from mere rumors.
You call two dead Jedi rumors?
This thing, this animal,
is extremely dangerous.
If you have any information about his
whereabouts, you must tell us.
Savage. Savage Opress.
Mother?
He is on Toydaria.
Thank you.
The time has come, sister.
You must put your plot against
Dooku into effect now.
He isn't ready, mother.
He needs more training.
He has to be ready.
Together the two of you will be
able to eliminate the count.
But you must act now.
We cannot keep your new
assassin a secret forever.
I will have my revenge.
You will, sister.
You will.
Your highness,
there is an intruder at the door.
Stop him!
I will not be intimidated.
At last.
I guess that's what's
left of our ship.
We'll borrow one from
the Toydarians.
You ignorant beast.
I told you I wanted him alive.
Forgive me, my master.
That is not the way
of the dark side.
Ventress.
That's no way to treat
your apprentice.
I should know.
Savage, you can make
amends for your mistake,
by destroying this witch.
I don't think that will be happening,
will it, Savage?
Remember where your
true loyalties lie.
With you, mistress.
Look. A separatist dreadnought.
The king's murderer
must have fled there.
Dooku sent his assassin to exact
his revenge on the Toydarians.
We'll make him pay for it.
Halt!
You are now...
Finish him now!
Get up.
We must defeat him.
Kill him.
Kill him, you fool!
I can't.
He's too powerful.
Your weakness will
not be my downfall.
A failed apprentice makes
for a foolish master.
Savage, no!
- We'll take him together.
- Right.
Leaving so soon, master?
You are no match for me
without the aid of your monster.
That remains to be seen.
As you wish.
Time to end this once and for all.
Commander,
Savage Opress is a traitor.
- Destroy him.
- Roger, roger.
They're attacking that monster.
You're not supposed to be here.
- No sense in hanging around here.
- My thoughts exactly.
You have come home to us.
I was betrayed by Ventress.
The Jedi are after me.
I'm not nearly strong enough
to defeat them all.
Calm yourself.
You will be.
I don't understand.
Who will teach me?
You have a brother.
A brother?
But all of my kin were killed.
Not all of them.
He lives in the outer rim in exile.
You will find him.
He will teach you
everything you need to learn
to become even more powerful.
My brother...
How will I find him?
This talisman has been imbued
with the power of our clan.
It will be your compass.
You have an important
destiny to fulfill, Savage Opress...
You and your brother.
Go.
You will know where to find him.
I will return, mother.