Male announcer: Mysterious message!
A transmission has been intercepted
far beyond the outer rim,
deep in the crelythiumn system.
Why the call has been made and
from where cannot be established.
But buried in the message
is a jedi distress code
that has not been used
in over 2,000 years.
Obi-Wan Kenobi, Anakin Skywalker,
and his padawan ahsoka
are sent to investigate.
Fearing a separatist trap,
they are to meet with
a heavily armed jedi cruiser.
[Metallic whirring]
Rex...
Rex, do you read me?
We're at the rendezvous point
awaiting your arrival.
Where are you?
Sir, we are at the
rendezvous point and there's
no sign of you on our scanners.
Oh, come on.
That's impossible.
Something's wrong.
We're at the exact coordinates
where the distress signal
originated, but there's nothing here.
Rex is at the exact same
coordinates and he's not here.
>> This is getting interesting.
Unable to find you.
Where are you, sir?
Something's blocking the signal.
[Electronics powering down]]
[Clicking and tapping]
Not good.
Everything's dead,
even the life support.
Hmm, this is really strange.
[Electronics power back up]
There.
See?
Nothing to be concerned
about after all.
Then what's that?
[Rapid beeping]
It's pulling us towards it.
Everyone, strap yourselves in.
Looks as though we're
going for a ride.
[Faint, strange bellowing]
[Moans]
[Gasps]
I must have blacked out.
Then who landed the shuttle?
Not me.
Mm...
Where are we?
[Beeping]
Some kind of organic mass.
All of our readings indicate that
it's bigger than an asteroid.
But at least the
atmosphere is breathable.
Well, this is getting more
unusual by the minute.
I can't even lock down where
in the galaxy we are...
Or if we are even in our own galaxy.
[Clicking and ringing tones]
Well, the ship's systems seem
ne but for whatever reason,
nothing's working.
Hey!
I saw something.
A reflection, up on the hill.
I don't see anything.
Are you the one?
What the...
What?
Did you hear that?
I didn't hear anything.
Are you the one?
Hello.
Who are you?
I am daughter.
Are you the one?
Uh...
The one what?
I will take you to him.
Him, who?
>> Did you bring us here?
Only he can help you.
There is little time.
Follow me.
We must have shelter by nightfall.
And we thought the planet was strange.
How about this one?
We'll be fine as long
as we stay together.
Have you noticed the
seasons seem to change
with the time of day?
Yeah.
And there are no animals.
And you sense it?
Mm-hmm, since we arrived.
The force is very strong.
An intersection unlike anything
I've ever felt before.
Be wary.
Excuse me.
Who are you taking us to?
The father, of course.
Of course.
And what exactly are you?
We are the ones who guard the power.
We are the middle, the
beginning, and the end.
Glad she cleared that up for us.
[Low rumbling]
Hey!
Look out!
[Loud rumbling and crunching]
[Both grunting]
[Yelps]
[Low rumbling bellow]
[Grunts]
Thank you.
You're welcome.
It is forbidden for you to touch me.
Sorry.
I was just saving your life.
That was my brother's work.
You are in great danger.
Wait for me.
Do not leave this place.
Hey!
Wait.
Anakin, are you there?
Are you all right?
[Sighs]
But our friend here has run off!
Go back to the ship and try
sending another distress call.
I'll follow her and find out
how to get off this rock.
And if this is a trap?
Then I'm not gonna wait
around to find out.
Anakin, stop!
Wait for us to find another
way around and meet you.
Anakin?
So reckless and impatient.
He'll find her.
Yes, and what else?
[Distant thunder rumbles]
Storm's coming.
The ship's gone.
Yes, I see that.
It was here, no question.
And look.
Everything's dying.
Did you lose something?
You didn't do as you were asked.
And what was that?
My sister said to wait!
Did she now?
Well, we were unfortunately separated.
We'd like our ship back
if you don't mind.
Not...
Yet.
Is it true that he is the chosen one?
[Lightsabers hum]
What do you know of such things?
What is about to happen shall
occur whether you like it or not.
[Humming stops abruptly]
You are sith.
Sith?
[Chuckles]
Yes...
And no.
The storms here are quite lethal.
If you want to live, I
suggest you find shelter.
What in the universe was that?
I'm not quite sure.
Quick.
There's a cave over there.
[Thunder crashing steadily]
Whoever I'm looking for
is in that monastery.
Welcome, my friend.
What is it that you want from me?
To learn the truth about
who you really are,
one that maybe you
have known all along,
one you must believe in order
to fulfill your destiny.
Enough with the riddles, old man.
Tell me what's going on here.
[Thunder cracks]
As you can see, there
is nowhere else to go.
It is late.
You will be my guest tonight.
[Rain pattering]
[Thunder crashing]
[Low rumbling bellow]
Obi-Wan, have you done as I asked?
Have you trained the boy?
Master qui-gon.
How are you here?
I am here because you are here.
No, I don't understand.
What is this place?
Unlike any other, a conduit
through which the entire force
of the universe flows.
Are we in danger?
This planet is both an
amplifier and a magnet.
Three are here who seek Skywalker.
They, like me, believe him
to be the chosen one.
You were right.
The force within him is
stronger than any known jedi.
I have trained him as well as I
could, but he is still willful
and balance eludes him.
If he is the chosen one,
he will discover it here.
And if not?
Then you must realize with
his power, this is a very
dangerous place for him to be.
Wake up, my son.
I must tell you a secret.
Who's there?
Who's there, I said.
It is me, ani, your mother.
What kind of black arts is this?
You're dead.
Nothing ever really dies, my son.
I have a secret to tell you.
Then tell me.
Everything you have done,
everything you have learned
has led you here.
Whatever you are, my mother is...
Is dead.
And you blame yourself.
Your jedi training has
served you well, ani,
but you are more than a jedi.
Tell me, where is your pain,
so I might take it away.
I was too late to save you.
I failed as a jedi and I failed you.
How so?
I tasted only vengeance
when I slaughtered so many
to avenge your death.
It is time you realized
that your guilt
does not define you, my son.
You define your guilt.
The only love I feel in my
heart is haunted by what
would happen should I let go.
Then it is not love.
It is a prison.
But I...
I have a wife.
You've met her.
She's everything to me.
She is not your destiny.
But I love her.
No!
She is a poisoner!
What are you?
Your fate!
Are you happy, child?
Your master, does he treat you well?
What concern of it is yours?
I am your future, your potential.
This is a trick.
There is a wildness to you, young one.
Seeds of the dark side
planted by your master.
Do you feel it?
No.
He is like no other jedi.
Passionate, impulsive, but
I trust him with my life.
There are many contradictions in you...
And in him.
Be warned, you may
never see your future
if you remain his student.
Leave this planet!
Ahsoka.
I had a vision.
I think Anakin may be in trouble.
[Lightsaber hums]
Cannot sleep?
To strike an unarmed man
is hardly the jedi way.
You're a sith lord!
You have a very simple
view of the universe.
I am neither sith nor jedi.
I am much more...
And so are you.
I see through your spells
and visions, old man.
Tell me what is going on here.
[Low humming and crackling]
Some call us force-wielders.
The jedi have never spoken of this.
Mm.
Few still know of our existence.
In that room, my mother came
to me, but it was not her.
It was something else.
Ah.
My son, I suspect.
We can take many forms.
The shapes we embody are
merely a reflection
of the life force around us.
You carry a great
sadness in your heart.
My children and I can manipulate
the force like no other,
therefore, it was necessary to
withdraw from the temporal world
and live here as anchorites.
As a sanctuary?
And a prison.
You cannot imagine what pain it
is to have such love for your
children and realize that they
could tear the very fabric
of our universe.
I don't understand.
It is only here that I can control them...
A family in balance.
The light and the dark.
Day with night.
Destruction replaced by creation.
Then why reveal yourselves to us?
There are some who would
like to exploit our power.
The sith are but one.
Too much dark or light
would be the undoing
of life as you understand it.
When news reached me that the
chosen one had been found,
I needed to see for myself.
The chosen one is a myth.
Is it?
I should very much like to know.
Why don't we find out together?
Pass one test, and I
shall know the truth.
Then you and your friends
may leave.
The longer we stay here, the
stranger this place gets.
It appears the planet
is renewing herself.
What about master Skywalker?
Anakin will not be easy to deceive.
[Wings flapping]
[Loud screeching]
It is time to face your
guilt and know the truth.
[Loud screech]
Roar!
Whatever he wants,
don't do it, master!
[Grunting and gasping]
[Screeches]
Let them go.
I will not play your games.
Oh, but I think you will.
I have ordered my children
to kill your friends.
The question is, which one
will you choose to save:
Your masr or your apprentice?
You must now release the guilt
and free yourself by choosing.
No!
[Gasps]
Their powers are too
strong for us, Anakin.
Save ahsoka.
[Growling]
[Gasping and groaning]
Let them go.
Only you can make my
children release them.
Anakin, the planet
is the force.
Use it.
You will let them go!
[Screeching]
[Dramatic singing]
♪ ♪
Down!
On your knees!
And now you see who you truly are.
Only the chosen one could
tame both my children.
I have taken your test.
Now fulfill your
promise and let us go.
Ah, but first you must
understand the truth.
Now all of you, leave us.
Do not trust him.
You think?
I said leave us.
Do you feel your destiny?
You must see it now.
I am dying, and you must replace me.
Replace you?
I can't stay here.
But this is yours.
It has been foretold.
The chosen one will remain to
keep my children in balance.
No.
I cannot force you to do this.
The choice must be yours.
But leave and your selfishness
shall haunt you and the galaxy.
Ready to get out of here?