Love comes in all shapes and sizes.
On great scape,
Cad Bane and his notorious
cruel band of bounty bunters,
liberated Ziro the Hutt
from a Republic prison,
after holding a galactic senator hostage.
The jedi council has assigned
Obi-wan Kenobi to retrieve
Ziro the hutt with the help
Of jedi knight Quinlan Vos.
Unknown to the jedi, we find
Ziro in the clutches of the five
Hutt families on the distant
World of Nal Hutta.
Gentlemen, gentlemen.
I see no need for resentment
In light of this joyous
Occasion of my freedom.
chuba kispa manta kul kispa.
Of course I do appreciate
The help in my escape.
ta kispa che copah, chuba
Yarpa za.
oh, I have no illusions about
The fact that my escape was a
result of the highly sensitive
knowledge that I possess--
A holo-diary cataloging the
nefarious deeds of this council.
[grumbles]
Un yoka, je puna boya chobo!
Kill me and the diary will
show up on the step of the
Senate.
The cold, hard reality is that
as long as I control this highly
sensitive material, my memory
will only get duller.
yacha chobo nichu.
Yes, take me to my room.
I only hope the accommodations
are satisfactory.
Sir, you seem troubled.
Quinlan Vos has that effect.
Ah, yes.
That jedi has quite a reputation.
That may be overstating it, Cody.
Let's just say he's crazy.
Ship entry from the west,
Sir.
[engine rumbling]
Hey, Kenobi.
Ha.
Hey, Commander.
Looking good.
Kenobi, you look worse for wear.
How's temple life?
Good to see you too.
Yes, well, if you could tell
time half as well as you could
stick a landing, we wouldn't be
behind schedule, now would we?
Well, that's your opinion, man.
Let's get down to business.
Ziro the hutt was broken out
during a hostage takeover.
Yeah, I read the briefing
about that mess.
I suspect Jabba the Hutt
is behind this.
He still has it out for Ziro
over the kidnapping of his son.
Well, my information
indicates that Ziro has damaging
evidence against the Hutt council.
My guess is they've taken him to
the Hutt home planet Nal Hutta.
As for this bounty hunter
Cad Bane, we must capture and
Return both he and his quarry
Ziro to the courts.
I trust you and I can keep eyes
Forward in this common goal?
no problem.
I owe Bane one anyway.
I'll fly.
You're my copilot.
I was afraid he'd say that.
[lively brass music]
♪ ♪
♪ oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ ♪
♪ ho ne hesa kozan ♪
♪ thota palowick dogan ♪
♪ ichaga setuka wermo naga ♪
♪ daa hutt muna ♪
♪ ta hutt muna ♪
♪ bato hat, mal, chone rot ♪
♪ makan hopo ji sot ♪
♪ ji pul ban haa yo ki ji isok ♪
♪ daa hutt muna ♪
♪ ta hutt muna ♪
♪ ga hutt muna ♪
sounds like that rough crowd
out there is an easy one tonight.
all in a night's work, baby.
course, having Ziro locked up
In the detention cell block
Probably isn't hurting their mood.
Ziro's here?
If you'll excuse me,
I need to step outside.
Gardulla has a request.
She wants to know which
one of you is stronger.
[both grunting]
Stop them. They're fighting!
Ziro, honey, my true love,
What happened to you?
I thought you were coming back
For me.
I waited so long.
I thought you didn't love me
Anymore.
our separation last time was
A bit abrupt, and I do blame
Jabba for that.
Jabba?
he forced me to have you sent
Away from coruscant,
Shattering the serenity of
The happiest time of my life.
oh, Ziro, honey,
Being with you was the happiest
Time of my life too.
And now hearing you say that
Makes me the luckiest little
Pa'lowick the galaxy has ever
Known.
unfortunately the cage that
Entraps me now also entrapv
The chance of loving you again.
what do they want with you?
Why would they do this?
as hard as it is to confess
This to you, snooty,
I'm not a perfect hutt.
I don't care what you've done
Or why they want to hurt you.
I only care about us being
Together--forever.
you--you really mean that?
from the bottom of my fluid
Sack.
[gasps]
Unfortunately, my love,
There's no way for us to be
Together, as long as I'm in this
Dreadful cell.
with true love, there's
Always a way.
[lips smooching]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
[upbeat dance music]
[record scratches]
kava su nudcha?
how goes the war, gentlemen?
great gardulla, we bring
Unfortunate news.
Ziro the hutt has escaped our
Custody with the aid of the
Bounty hunter cad Bane.
dobrah chuba koochoo.
the great gardulla already
Knows this, jedi knights.
I'm beginning to think
You're the ones who broke him out.
wanta?
and why would the great hutt
Families do such a thing?
that's what I'd like to know.
quinlan, the hutts are our allies.
chuba gusha Kenobi.
Solo chuba killya.
mighty gardulla says you are
Lucky to be with a jedi as wise
As Kenobi, or you might not be
Allowed to leave here alive.
in light of this joyous
Occasion...
maybe next time I'll come
Alone, hmm?
we only came to deliver
The message.
We should be leaving now.
obita.
[record scratches]
Ziro was here.
He was holding one of those
Cups.
nice work.
Vos, Ziro escaped.
I think he had help.
we best hurry.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
[laughs]
jedai moocha?
nobata.
Meendeeya tchuta ne pa.
I disagree.
The jedi aren't the ones that
Broke Ziro out of jail.
He was gone way before they
Arrived.
It looks like we're right back
Where we started.
mee tinka mee moolee-rah.
I'm kind of tired of being
paid for this job, too,
But not that tired.
If you hutts ain't interested
in knowing what's behind this
And making it go away,
- I can take a hint.
- Ho!
Coo sa konchee.
so we doing business or not?
I understand your tracking
Talent, but why wouldn't Ziro
Leave the planet?
Why not just fly away?
my senses tell me that he's
Still here.
it's illogical.
He knows he's being looked for
Here.
something is keeping him here.
if we'd brought a droid,
This would go faster.
[hissing]
Are you finished messing around?
We're trying to catch Ziro, remember?
which way have they gone?
well, since you're suddenly
So interested in my tracking abilities,
they went this way.
I never doubted you.
why are we stopping here?
I guarantee gardulla is
Searching for us as we speak,
So I came to the one place
She would never, ever show up.
Hello, there.
son, who invited you?
mama!
shoulda figured after all
These years of never calling,
You'd show up at dinnertime.
You gonna sit in your stink,
Or are you gonna pass the slime
Pods?
Never would of had to tell that
To your brother ebor, rest his
Soul.
[chomping vigorously]
So, sonny, what the heck you
Been doing the past few years
Anyway?
oh, a smidgen of this
And a pinch of that,
Using all of my facilities
For the betterment of my fellow
Hutts.
what is it you want, sonny?
can't a loving son just want
To visit his mother on occasion?
when plebos fly out of my
Hump.
well, now that you mention
It, I wouldn't mind swapping
My swamp speeder for your
Starship.
that's what I thought.
Who's chasing ya this time?
gardulla.
aw, take it.
Just make sure you
bring it back full power.
Thanks, mama.
I got some important
business on Teth.
todo, how far ahead are the
Jedi?
I don't know.
this is the last time I take
one of these jobs.
Looks as though we're not
the only ones after Ziro.
we must be cautious.
Vos, somebody lives here!
ugh!
Smells like somebody died here.
break in my house, will you,
Smart guy?
thousand pardons, madam.
He hasn't mastered the concept
Of knocking.
For that, I apologize.
I got trouble for you too,
Mr. Fancy pants.
no need.
We're not here to harm you.
that'll be a first for
Tonight.
meaning?
meaning first my deadbeat son
And his limp-lipped girlfriend
Come in and sponge me out of my
Starship.
Then some slime sap and his
Droid charge in and force me
To give up the skinny on where
Ziro's headed.
big hat?
yeah.
Chad something out for blood.
You want to kill my little boy
Too?
oh, no, madam, but if we
Don't find him before Bane does,
Your son will not be so lucky.
teth.
Ziro's heading for teth.
We need to get to that jungle planet.
We need to get there fast.
hey, who's going to pay
for my door?
Are we close to your
Holo-diary, baby?
This way.
My papa's grave.
I never did have the heart
To tell mama that papa ran away,
Or that he died.
Some people are just happier
When they're miserable.
the hutt council records.
every dirty deed those
Criminals have slithered
Through.
Worth a fortune, baby.
Plenty enough to retire on.
aww, that's too bad.
I still got work to do.
but--but--
What about solarine, the
Sunsets, you and me sharing
A future?
next time, you'll think twice
About breaking someone's heart.
Oh, wait.
There won't be a next time.
no!
[gunshot]
Ah, what a world.
[engine whooshing]
oh, I just hate it when
Someone does my job.
and the holo-diary is gone
As well.
oh, drat.
[engine whirring]
Jedi.
who could have done this?
Bane.
looks like we're both too
Late for the party.
so this is not your
Handiwork?
no, I wouldn't have made such
A sloppy kill.
Doesn't seem like much sense
Hanging around here
Or making any trouble between
Us.
are you forgetting how you
Held the senate hostage?
I may not be capturing Ziro,
But you are going to prison.
well, now that you mention
It, the separatists are paying
A million credits a head
For a jedi.
[blaster firing]
ugh!
[grunts]
Ugh!
Ooh!
[blaster firing]
ugh!
ha ha ha!
[moaning]
ah!
[engine whooshing]
I never did enjoy
hanging out with you.
[laughing maniacally]
Chuba inkabunga chik youngee.
Jabba thanks you for
delivering the holo-diary.
No one would suspect that a
lovely creature such as myself
Could do a bounty hunter's work.
Sync by Kerensky
www.Addic7ed.com
On a all new episode of
Star Wars the Clone Wars
Your friend is a succubus?
Asoka and Padme are going
behind enemy lines.
It's so good to see you.
But who's going to be cleaning up
Corruscant while they're gone?
I've deployed the infiltrators.
Oh, oh. That's not good.
Don't miss all new episode of
Star Wars the Clone Wars: Secrets Revealed.
- To peace then.
- To hope.