Pantora in peril!
The newly elected chairman of
Pantora, Baron Papanoida,
Is caught in a deadly political game.
The Trade Federation
has blockaded Pantora
and suspended all
commerce with the system.
Isolated from the rest of the Republic,
The people of Pantora are beginning
to rally against the senate,
Who have seemed unsympathetic to their plight.
To make matters worse,
Count Dooku has come forward
offering aid if Pantora joins
the separatist alliance.
Chairman Papanoida has dispatched
senator Chuchi to Coruscant
with the hope that she can motivate
the senate to act in favor of Pantora
Before Lott Dod can legitimize the blockade.
The Trade Federation is neutral in this,
but Pantora must pay its debt
before we can resume commerce
with the system.
That is a lie.
It is well known that the Trade Federation
is aligned with the Separatists.
Slanderous.
We are not separatists simply
because we do business with them.
How many times must I remind you
of the commerce treaty of 1647?
The Trade Federation is neutral.
I beg the senate to listen to our pleas.
Ignore the Trade Federation's feeble attempt
to paint this as a domestic financial issue
and allow us to resume trade.
Wait.
Senator Chuchi.
I wanted to compliment you on
your speech.
Thank you, padme.
You are very brave.
The Trade Federation
doesn't frighten me.
I just wanted to let you know
that there are many of
us in the Senate that
support you and Pantora
in these difficult times.
I know the separatists have
approached you to offer their help.
Please do not take it.
The senate will force the Trade
Federation to resume trade.
Don't worry, senator.
There's no way that Pantora will
The chairman of Pantora's just arrived.
I must go brief him.
Please, send him my best wishes.
Chairman Papanoida.
Senator Chuchi,
you spoke well on behalf of our
people today.
I only hope the senate is truly listening.
As do I, chairman.
Allow me to introduce my family.
These are my daughters,
Chi Eekway and Che Amanwe,
And my son, Ion.
Father, Amanwe and I
are going home.
Don't be too late.
I won't be long.
Ion and I have some issues to
discuss with the senator first.
Things are deteriorating rapidly, senator.
Ion has just brought word from
Pantora that things are far
worse than we've been led to believe.
The people are restless.
The Trade Federation blockade is causing far
more damage and disorder than we predicted.
We need more time.
The senate will vote in our favor,
I'm sure of it.
Count Dooku and the
Separatists are promising
immediate aid and a resolution
to the blockade.
You're not suggesting we
join them, are you?
Certainly not.
I merely point out that the
wheels of democracy are
moving too slowly.
There are Pantorans rallying
for us to leave the Republic
And join the separatists.
We cannot give up on the
Republic senate.
Chairman, you must convince the
people to remain loyal to our cause.
I will do what I can, Senator.
What's wrong with the lights?
Did you see that?
It's nothing.
Just the shadows playing tricks.
Don't tell me you're afraid of the dark.
Chi?
Stop fooling around.
My father's a powerful man.
If you hurt me or my sister,
You'll be dead.
Big talk.
You're coming with us.
Smack!
Hurry.
Let's go.
I don't like the situation
on Pantora one bit.
It reminds me far too much
of Naboo's own scarred history.
Well, that blockade wasn't that bad.
It's the reason I met you,
after all.
You certainly have a unique way
of looking at things, Ani.
Senator Amidala.
Master skywalker.
What is it, Ahsoka?
Someone has kidnapped
Chairman Papanoida's daughters.
I was afraid something like
this would happen.
Anakin?
The jedi can't ket involved.
This is a job for the local police.
I'm not so sure local
Authorities can handle it.
The separatists are putting a lot of pressure
on Pantora to join them.
I'm afraid this blockade may give the
Pantorans no other choice.
Master, if the jedi can't officially get involved,
let me do this on my own.
Senator Chuchi is a good friend
of mine.
All right, with the Separatists involved,
I guess it gives you cause to investigate.
Go help senator Chuchi,
but don't get in the way of the local authorities.
Aren't you going to help?
I said the situation gives you cause to investigate,
not us.
I need to go back to the jedi
temple and make sure the council...
doesn't find out about your
little expedition.
Should you really proceed
without the council's approval?
We do it all the time,
don't we, Snips?
Yep.
Well, be careful, Ahsoka.
I still can't believe
they let you teach.
Give your father my condolences.
If you want your sisters back,
we're here to help.
Father, count Dooku has offered to
help us find Chi Eekway and Che Amanwe.
Chuchi, senator Amidala
sent me to help if I can.
Chairman Papanoida.
This is my good friend Ahsoka.
Good.
A jedi can always be of help.
Senator Amidala thinks this may have
something to do with the separatists.
They've already made contact with us.
I don't think this is a kidnapping.
I think they're holding them hostage.
A not very subtle attempt to
get us to join the separatists?
If the separatists are involved,
your daughters may be held on
the Trade Federation ship
blockading your planet.
That is a possibility.
Why don't you and Chuchi pay them a
diplomatic visit and see what you can find out.
We'll stay here and follow the
police investigation.
Did you find anything?
We've completed a thorough
sweep of your apartment, Chairman.
No evidence of foul play.
My daughters' lives are in your hands, inspector.
You have nothing to worry about, your honor.
We are in complete control
of the situation.
That inspector is useless.
Somewhere.
Look here.
The icon of the moon goddess.
It should be up on the shrine
with the others.
Wait a minute.
What's this?
Blood.
It must be what they used
to fight off their attackers.
But the kidnappers didn't know
to put it back in the right place.
Information retrieval.
I need you to match this blood sample
against known galactic criminals.
A rodian.
It says here his name's Greedo.
Looks like
he's based on Tatooine.
Then what are we waiting for?
Senator Chuchi,
to what do we owe this pleasure?
I bring word from
the chairman of Pantora.
The chairman has finally
decided to agree to our terms?
Not exactly.
The chairman wanted to inform
you of an impending alliance
between Pantora and the
Confederacy of Independent Systems.
The chairman is planning to
join the separatist alliance?
If that were the case,
would you remove your blockade of Pantora?
If that were the case, the chairman
would have to go to the senate
And renounce the Republic.
Then we could discuss how
quickly we can resume commerce.
Very well.
I shall contact the chairman.
We can discuss the finer details
of the terms later this evening.
Agreed.
Now you and your servant may
stay as our honored guests.
Come this way to your rooms.
Be careful, Ion.
The hutts are the only law
that matters on Tatooine.
I don't scare easily.
Where do we start?
We'll have to get a feel
for the crowd.
Shouldn't we talk to Jabba directly?
No.
Remember, we're not sure who's
behind this kidnapping yet.
Jabba could be involved.
What if Greedo runs?
We'll let Greedo know
we're here.
That way, he'll come to us.
How are we gonna do that?
Follow me.
Ladies,
Do any of you know Greedo?
Who's asking?
We're asking.
We're looking to hire
a bounty hunter.
He's not here.
But if he comes back,
I'll tell him you were asking for him.
Patience.
If she won't lead us to Greedo,
she'll lead Greedo to us.
This is the ambassador's office.
Maybe we'll find something here.
The separatists are still
recovering from their defeat...
They're coming.
Hide.
We need to know who our supporters are.
I understand your profit margins with
the separatists can be considerable,
however, I object to the kidnapping.
The chairman's children are leverage.
Besides, they're well taken care of.
Yes, but why on my ship?
What was that?
Are you certain we're alone?
I'm sure I heard something.
All of this scheming with the separatists
is making you paranoid.
Do not worry.
The daughters are not to be harmed...
at least for now.
You see?
The Trade Federation is behind the kidnapping.
Let's find the detention area.
Come on.
Poodoo!
Greedo, baby, there you are.
There's some men here looking for you.
Pantorans.
They must have found some evidence.
We'll have to settle things
more permanently.
Have you done this before?
No, but I've been practicing.
The detention block is closed to visitors.
Move along.
You will let me pass.
I will let you pass.
I'm sorry, the detention block
is closed to visitors.
Ahsoka.
Ugh.
You will let us both pass.
I...
I will let you both pass.
Looking for someone, Chairman?
I was looking for you, Greedo.
Tell me where my daughters are
or die.
You were a fool to come here.
Let's dispose of them outside.
I don't want to die
on this dust ball.
We won't have to.
Hey!
We're going to talk to Jabba about this.
This is the fifth area we've checked,
and there's no sign of the Chairman's daughter.
Can't you sense where they are?
Isn't that something
you jedi can do?
It's not something I can just turn on or off.
We'll just have to keep looking.
Sir, we have intruders
in the detention area.
It looks like our guests got a little
too curious for their own good.
Chairman Papanoida,
the mighty Jabba wishes to know
why you tried to kill
one of his bounty hunters.
Great Jabba, my daughters
have been kidnapped.
As a father yourself,
I know you understand that I will do
anything to get them back safely.
I have evidence that
Greedo is responsible
which means that
either you are behind it
or Greedo is working for someone else.
Since we are friends, Jabba,
I know you would never
do such a thing.
No! No!
He's lying!
We found blood
at the scene of the crime.
If it matches Greedo's,
It will prove he is the kidnapper.
Jabba will allow a blood
sample to be taken.
Wait, wait, no!
It's all lies!
Okay, okay.
I kidnapped them.
The separatists wanted leverage
against you.
Where are they, you slime?
One of them is here
at Mos Eisley.
She's safe, I assure you.
Let's hope she's in this one.
Senator Chuchi,
how did you find me?
It's a long story.
Where's your sister?
I don't know.
We were separated.
All right, Sleemo, no tricks.
We're gonna go inside
Nice and easy.
You think they will just hand
her over to you?
No, but I'll bet they'll hand
her over to you.
Go get the prisoner.
Greedo,
what are you doing here?
There's been a change of plans.
We're going to have to
move the prisoner.
On whose orders?
Gunray.
He contacted me at Jabba's palace.
Why'd he contact you?
And who are those two?
They're emissaries of the Trade Federation.
Trade federation?
They don't look like
Trade Federation to me.
Father!
Father?
They're Pantorans!
Blast them!
Stop them!
Smash!
Surrender, separatist!
What is the meaning of this?
You've been holding the Chairman of
Pantora's daughter as a hostage.
What?
Sib Cannay, what is she talking about?
I want my litigator.
We are businessmen!
We deal in trade and commerce!
Yes, but perhaps your
business is war profiteering.
How dare you!
I dare because you claim
to have no involvement,
and yet here stands the
chairman's daughter on your ship,
held by your administrator.
I may understand your position,
but I doubt the rest of the
Senate will.
Blackmail.
No, business.
I could, of course, be persuaded to defend
your unfortunate circumstances to the senate,
That is, if this blockade ended.
I'll see what I can do.
It has come to our attention that
the ugly head of the Separatist
has once again raised itself in the
ranks of our very own Trade Federation.
Nute Gunray's influence extends farther
than we ever imagined.
It was Sib Cannay
acting on his own accord
who kidnapped the children
of chairman Papanoida.
In good faith,
we have returned them to him.
And also as a gesture of friendship,
we are removing our blockade
and reopening trade
with the Pantorans.