Clone troopers unite!
As war rages across the galaxy,
The republic's clone army
Strives for victory against the
Evil forces of the separatists.
Bravery, valor, unity:
The lifeblood of victory on the
Battlefield and in space.
It all begins on the planet
Kamino, where jedi general
Shaak Ti oversees the training
Of clones with the help of
Contracted bounty hunters.
Bred to be perfect soldiers,
These cadets must first be
Subjected to intense physical
And mental training before
Heading off to war...
You're clear.
You're clear!
Cover fire!
This is command:
You must break through enemy
Lines and take the tower.
Comlink just relayed
orders from...
We all had the orders, Echo!
Stop calling me that.
Stop repeating every order.
Less yappin'; more blastin'.
Let's smoke these chrome domes
And move on to the citadel.
CT-782,
You're breaking formation.
Just follow my lead, will ya?
He's clearing a path.
I'm moving.
Thanks, CT-27-5555.
That was close.
It's fives.
The name is "fives."
Yeah, Five pieces if you
Don't keep your head down!
How about we follow orders?
This is our last practice test.
Will you shut up with
Instructions?
You're not in charge.
This particular unit seems
To have some trouble.
What do you recommend?
Well, I'm no jedi, so forgive
My bluntness, but I say they
Fail.
Send 'em down to maintenance
Duty with 99 and the other
Rejects.
We can't fail them yet.
Remember, this is only a
Practice test.
And besides, the citadel course
Was constructed to be a
Difficult challenge.
Although I don't agree with
His sentiment, bric isn't wrong.
These cadets are far from ready.
I can't hit anything from
Here.
No, we have to follow orders.
The one they call "Echo"
Never adapts to the situation.
CT-782 seems to follow his
Own path.
He can't do it all alone.
You go; I'll cover you.
I'm a better shot. You go.
No, you go!
Look at those two.
End up dead.
Uh, and the last one...
I surrender. I surrender.
Need I say more?
If these cadets can't get
Past their shortsighted
Selfishness, they will never
Come together.
Unity wins war, gentlemen.
Computer, end exercise for
Domino squad.
99, would you please send a
Cleaning crew to the training
Ground?
We'll take care of the mess.
You should tell that 99 to
Drag away the mess called
Domino squad.
We almost had it this time.
Oh, yeah, and we all look
Nothing alike either.
Sorry about the mess, 99.
Uh, it's okay, boys.
Nice try.
So I says to her, "baby,
You and me could really"...
You've never even met a girl.
You know, you shouldn't
Worry because most clones pass.
Yeah, but not all of us,
Right, shortie?
Guys, we've got to follow
Orders.
Come on.
I don't know.
I think it went rather well.
Quit joking around.
Can we please stop arguing?
Can you stop being droid bait
Out there?
You're getting in my way.
Actually, our way.
Well, you want to be the
Best, then you got to think
Like it.
And I'm thinking like an arc
Trooper.
Care to repeat that, Echo?
Come on. Get him, Hevy!
Smack that know-it-all!
Cut it out.
If you two would focus on
Fighting droids as much as you
Do fighting each other, you
Might stand a chance out there.
Sorry, master chief.
Well, master chief,
Our training.
I'd rather be taught by a jedi
Than some mercenary bounty
Hunter.
Jedi don't have the time to
Train grunts like you.
That's why they hired me.
Listen, boys, when you were
Assigned to me, I had high hopes
For you.
Now we're approaching the end
Of your training, and you
Haven't advanced nearly enough.
Even this bad batcher, 99, has
More sense than you guys do, and
He's a maintenance clone.
You...you don't give them
Enough credit.
You're all a waste of my time.
I understand your concerns,
Master jedi.
Ever since the unfortunate
Death of Jango Fett, we have
Had to stretch his DNA to
Produce more clones.
A jedi does not feel
Concern, Lama Su.
However, I have noticed this
Unit of clones have been...
Deficient?
My only thought is for you to
Search the galaxy and find a
Suitable donor for your future
Clones.
And what of the clones
Produced so far?
As you know, there is no one
Way to make a clone.
Sometimes our efforts are less
Than successful.
Are you suggesting we just
Cast off the domino squad?
They're living beings, not
Objects.
You jedi show too much
Compassion.
Nevertheless, as general in
Charge of training, the decision
On what to do with them would
Be yours, master jedi.
Gentlemen, who wants to be
An arc trooper?
I do, sir!
You have to pass your final
Test first.
I want you to meet commander
Colt of the rancor battalion.
I want you troopers to
Remember, we're shoulder to
Shoulder on those front lines.
Brothers.
And sometimes we may quarrel,
But no matter what, we are
United.
Rule one:
We fight together.
So who's ready to step up first?
Let's start with the unit that
Ran the practice test in record
Time...
Arc trooper time.
Think he means us, boys?
Bravo unit, step up.
Well, bravo for bravo squad.
Show an arc trooper how it's
Done.
Come on, boys.
Maybe we can learn something.
Shut up, Echo.
Start the citadel challenge,
Version thx, variable 1138.
Go right!
Clankers!
We're better than these guys.
Okay, this is it.
Go for it.
He's going to make it.
I'm impressed.
You trained 'em well.
Who's next?
The domino squad.
And how are they?
We can do this, guys.
All we have to do is follow
Orders.
Check it out, guys.
Time to watch the dominoes
Fall.
They are so much better
Than us.
Knock it off.
Begin the program.
Let's not take it easy on them.
They're getting farther
Than normal.
Maybe so, but they're sloppy.
This is nothing.
Give them their next set of
Orders and watch the chaos
Ensue.
I'm telling you, these guys
Just aren't ready.
I'll flank left.
You flank right.
Take it easy.
I'm on your side.
Get it?
Your side, huh?
Pretty unorthodox.
Droidbait, behind you!
Man down!
Forget him!
I'm breaking for the citadel.
Hurry!
Guys, I think he's injured.
Leave him.
Come on!
We're gonna pass this time.
Okay, I spoke too soon.
That would be putting it
Broke formation, disobeyed
Orders, and you left a man
Behind.
You broke rule number one.
I'm sorry, domino squad.
This is an automatic failure.
I told you this was going to
Happen.
We've wasted enough time on
Those losers.
Their failure is our failure.
I've made a request to general
Shaak Ti that the domino squad
Be allowed to repeat the final
Test.
Why do you care about them?
Why don't you?
I care about getting paid.
It's a shame the bounty
Hunter in you sees this only as
A job.
More like an impossible task.
These cadets will be the
Finest troopers we've trained.
I have faith in them.
Faith?
Oh, you can't be serious,
El-Les.
We should treat them as a
Special challenge, bric.
We should treat them as
Failures.
Besides, I've already requested
That they be moved to cleanup
And maintenance.
That's all they're going to be
Good for.
Then I guess the general has
A decision to make.
General, may we have a word?
You are here to discuss your
Squad, aren't you?
How did you...
Ah, jedi, mate.
One doesn't need to be a jedi
To feel the stress on your mind.
General, we would like to
Request a transfer to another
Squad.
Bravo squad, perhaps?
I am a jedi, where the
Individual and the group are
One in the same, much like you
Clones.
Which is why Fives and I are
Looking out for each other.
As individuals,
But not as a group.
You are where you need to be.
Solve your problems as a whole,
Not as individuals.
I have decided to allow you and
The rest of your squad to take
The test again tomorrow.
You wanted to see me, sir?
Near as I can tell, you're
The reason your squad's a
Failure.
Ah, well, I'll take that as
A compliment.
It's all a big joke to you,
Right?
Like those little nicknames you
And your clone brothers give
Each other.
Oh, I could think
Of one for you right now, sir.
Oh, funny.
But I think it's all just
A cover.
You hate me, don't you?
No, no, no.
How could I hate you for doing
Your job?
You're just pushing me, sir.
No, this is me pushing you.
Come on, clone.
Hit me.
Hit me, you joker.
Can't take anything seriously,
Can you?
You're a real cutup, aren't you?
Come on!
Thank you, sir.
For what?
For my name: Cutup.
I like the sound of it.
Out of my sight, cadet.
One way or another, you'll be
Out of this army.
Count on it.
Hevy, you going somewhere?
Get out of here.
You're going awol, aren't
Just go back to sleep, 99.
This doesn't concern you.
But you can't do this to
Your squad.
My squad?
We're nothing but a bad batch.
Failures.
Like you.
Yeah, but how can I be
A failure when I...I never even
Got my chance?
A chance you're throwing away.
You're always trying to be the
Anchor, Hevy.
You know, do it on your own.
Well, maybe you should embrace
The fact that you have a team.
See, I never had that.
But you need them,
And they need you.
Why carry such a heavy burden
On your own when you have your
Brothers at your side, Hevy?
Hevy?
Would...stop calling me that!
We're just numbers, 99.
Just numbers.
Not to me.
To me, you've always had a name.
Hey, where's CT-782?
Yeah, where is CT-782?
If he is not here, we will
Fail.
Not today, brothers.
Today we pass.
And one more thing:
The name's Hevy.
Orders came in clear, mates.
Nothing to repeat, Echo?
Not today.
How's that shoulder treating
You?
I'll live.
We all know what we have
To do.
That's it, boys.
Stay together!
Fives, on your left.
Thanks, cutup.
No problem, brother.
They seem to be working
Together.
Still early.
A lot can change.
Keep it up.
We're doing great.
We might actually pass.
Not so fast; still got the
Citadel.
All right, prep the
Ascension cables.
Let's scale this thing.
Wait a tick.
Where are the cables?
They're not in our belts.
Just when things seemed easy.
Well, we can't scale the face
Without them.
We'll fail the test if we can't
Finish.
What's going on?
Where are their ascension
Cables?
Must have gotten lost.
What did you do?
I thought you had faith
They'd be the best, right?
Well, the best pass,
No matter what.
General, you have to stop
This.
This is unfair to the cadets.
Adversity in war is
A constant, el-Les.
But bric has cheated.
The enemy won't play fair
Either.
So this is it?
Not exactly.
Those guns up there...
We can use them as a step to
The next level, form a chain,
And use each other
To scale this face.
Use the guns?
Are you crazy?
Trust me.
I know weapons.
I'm gonna draw their fire.
You guys blast 'em.
Well, I'll be...
Creative little clones, aren't
They?
No unit has shown such
Ingenuity.
We did it!
I knew we could do it, boys!
We made it!
Bric, your actions have
Brought out the best in these
Looks like they were
Well-Trained, perhaps the
Finest soldiers I've ever seen.
Well, maybe you were right,
El-Les.
Congratulations.
You've graduated.
At ease.
Next stop, arc trooper.
Yeah, how 'bout we face some
Combat first?
You were right, you know,
About everything.
I heard you were quite
The leader out there.
No leaders.
We are a team.
All of us, 99.
The army's lucky to have
A clone like you, Hevy.
Not as lucky as I am to have
Well, this is good-Bye,
I guess.
Hevy ships out, and 99 stays
Here.
Eh, we'll see each other
Again.
I mean, how else am I supposed
To get this back from you?
You deserve it.
You're one of us.
Today is your graduation.
From here, you ship out to
Fight against the separatists
And restore peace to the
Republic.
Congratulations.
You are no longer cadets.
You are troopers.
May the force be with you.
Attention!
Helmets on!
Separatist attack!
After the destruction of
The republic outpost on the
Rishi moon, general Grievous
And Asajj Ventress plan
An attack the planet Kamino,
Home of the cloning factories.
Meanwhile, aboard a jedi
Cruiser, jedi knights
Anakin Skywalker and Obi-Wan
Kenobi examine an intercepted
Message from general Grievous.
We are decrypting the audio,
Sir.
The clone planet of Kamino
Will be a dangerous target.
Just make sure you hold up
Your half of the mission.
We must stop the production
Of new clones
If we are to win this war.
Kamino.
They're going to attack
Our home planet.
The separatists are taking
Quite the chance
Even considering this.
With all due respect,
General, if someone comes
To our home, they better
Be carrying a big blaster.
I concur with captain rex,
Sir.
This is rsonal for us clones.
We'll make sure Kamino
Is secure.
Tell your troopers in the 501st
They're going home.
Yes, sir.
All is ready, general.
Good.
We will attack tipoca city
First.
I have the exact locations
Of both the clone dna room
And the clone trooper barracks.
Both shall be annihilated
Under my hand.
Our hands, general.
Count dooku assigned us both
This task.
But of course, assassin.
I look forward to meeting you.
Are the aqua droids prepared
For phase two of the plan?
Yes, mistress.
Masters Kenobi and Skywalker,
Welcome to Kamino.
Greetings, generals.
I wish our arrival
Wasn't under such circumstances.
We believe Grievous is planning
A separatist attack on Kamino.
But the republic blockade
Is far too strong.
They would not dare.
Ah, look around, Fives.
Feels like yesterday
We were here,
Heading to target practice.
Heh, remember that?
Do I ever.
Hey, 99.
Ha, Echo.
Fives.
You actually remember us.
Oh, I remember all my
Brothers.
Is Hevy here?
Where's he?
There was an incident
On the Rishi moon outpost.
He saved our lives,
But he gave up his own.
Uh, let's see!
Hevy gave you his medal?
So why have you returned
To Kamino?
The generals received word
Of an impending attack here.
Well, how can I help?
Attack formation Echo-3.
Status.
Deflector shields raised.
Destroyers in position.
Forward cannons ready.
Landing craft prepared.
All ships are in position.
Commence attack.
The separatist fleet
Is pressing their attack, sir.
Contact command
At tipoca city.
Shore up our defenses.
The fleet is not as large
As I expected.
Begin the air strike.
Good to see you, general.
Ready to have some fun?
You know me, broadside.
I'd rather be up here
Than stuck in a command center.
Warning! Falling debris.
Grievous appears to be
Sacrificing his transports
In favor of protecting
His command ship.
Something's not right.
Reinforcements have arrived.
Send out the aqua droids
To assemble the assault craft.
Focus on the cruisers.
I'm gonna press the attack,
Master.
No, Anakin.
Wait.
It's too easy.
Not even Grievous would attack
So recklessly.
Master, the battle's up here
In space, not down there.
The debris from the destroyed
Separatist ships is the key.
What are you thinking?
I think I'd like to go
For a swim.
Nothing as of yet.
Only you could be worried
About the ships I already
Shot down.
Wait a minute.
Aqua droids.
Looks as though they're
Assembling assault craft.
Anakin, I was right.
Those downed transports
Were hiding ships for
An underwater assault.
Anakin, come in!
Hold it right there.
Do not move.
Thanks for the lift, friend.
Anakin, the city is under
Attack.
I need you down here now!
On my way.
Sir, you sent for us?
It's a dangerous assignment,
But I want you two up
On the bridge in sniper
Positions.
Yes, sir.
We're on it.
Watch out!
99, get out of here!
This is no place for you.
There aren't enough droids
Here to capture the city.
They're trying to distract us.
Go protect the dna chamber.
I'll deal with Grievous.
Got it.
Fives, keep firing.
We can beat these guys.
Zap!
99.
I...I brought you some ammo.
Is there a better spot
Than this, a better defensive
Position we can take?
Droids! Behind us!
Look! Grenades!
Thanks, 99.
Good job.
Look out.
There's more.
Cadets.
What are you doing here?
We got separated
From our group.
Where were they taking you?
The barracks.
Oh, I know the best way
There.
Keep firing.
No mercy!
Your skills are impressive.
Perhaps a match for my own,
Assassin.
Count dooku may have taught
You how to swing a lightsaber,
General, but that hardly
Makes you my equal.
And yet I am the general
In charge of this assault.
Remember, assassin,
You are to recover
The clone dna.
Why not just destroy it?
Because the dna could unlock
New possibilities for us.
Keep playing with your
Droids.
I'll handle breaking into
The dna room.
Shall I provide you
With a droid escort?
My dear general,
There's nothing you have
That I could want.
What are we gonna do?
A separatist victory
Means death for all of us.
The cadet is right.
What are we gonna do?
We fight.
But our training's not
Finished.
Look around.
We're one in the same,
Same heart, same blood.
Your training is in your blood.
And my blood's boiling
For a fight.
This is our home.
This is our war.
What about weapons?
The armory.
It's just a few corridors away
Here in the barracks.
I can retrieve all the firepower
That we need.
Hah, so who wants to blast
Some droids?
The droids are spread thin.
We must press our offensive now.
I was beginning to think
My presence went unnoticed.
You weren't planning
On leaving without saying hello,
Were you?
Ha, here it is.
Everything we need is here.
Excellent work, 99.
Hurry up.
The droids have almost reached
The barracks.
Let's get into position.
Open up.
Get those doors open
And scare the remaining clones
Out of hiding.
Roger, roger.
Blast them.
All too easy.
Define "easy," general.
Kenobi.
Kenobi, Kamino has fallen.
Your clone army is doomed.
I beg to differ, Grievous.
Cadets, now!
Last one, commander.
Make it count.
I'll get more.
99, you can't.
I'm a soldier like you.
This is what
I was bred for.
99, no!
Commander Cody.
Yes, sir.
The droids have been pushed
Back to the main hangar.
We've got to stop meeting
Like this, my friend.
Move it, troopers!
On the double!
Fire!
Look! It's the general!
To surrender.
Actually I plan to let
the clones execute you
Right now.
Not this time.
We did it.
We held them back.
We lost a true soldier.
He really was one of us.
Echo, Fives.
You both really stepped up
In the heat of battle.
We did what we had to do,
Sir,
What any clone would have done.
Both of you showed valor
Out there, real courage.
Reminded me of me, actually.
Echo, Fives,
You're both officially
Being made arc troopers.
I don't think the separatists
Will be coming back here
Any time soon.
But if they do,
Kamino will be lucky
To have clones like
you defending it.
Good job, men!