Male announcer: Escape
from a separatist prison!
Carrying information about
secret routes into the heart of
the Republic and separatist
homeworlds, jedi master Even Piell
was captured and imprisoned
in a fortress known as The Citadel.
Leading an elite strike team,
Obi-Wan Kenobi and Anakin
Skywalker rescued master
Piell and his officers.
Now the jedi have split up to
evade separatist forces as they
attempt to escape The Citadel.
Artoo, are you and your
battle droids ready to go?
[R2-d2 beeps]
All right, get the ship fired up.
We'll meet you at the pipeline
exit after you've picked up
Obi-Wan, assuming
he's still on schedule.
[R2-d2 beeps]
This passage will get
us near the landing pad.
Artoo, send the shuttle to
the rear landing platform.
We've already been given the
go-ahead by general Skywalker,
sir, assuming you are still on schedule.
The trick will be if
Anakin arrives on time.
A probe!
Did you get it?
Security doors!
Move, or you'll be cut in half!
I can't!
We lost one.
Looks like we've got some cutting to do.
Count dooku insists that you
speak with him, commander.
Well, let's not keep him waiting.
He's already waiting, sir.
Count dooku, my lord, how unexpected.
You may cease the
propriety, commander Sobeck.
I understand there is a
problem with the jedi prisoner.
An incursion team attempted
a rescue, but the situation is
taken care of.
Are you in possession of
the information the prisoner
is carrying?
Not yet, but we will soon have it.
You are aware that this
information will tip the scale
of the war to the side that controls it.
Perhaps this is a matter
that requires my presence.
No, my lord.
Find them, commander.
Get the information.
Then kill them all.
Don't ever surprise me with a
transmission from count dooku.
I need time to prepare!
Yes, commander.
I am beginning to admire
the design of this fortress.
It's raer formidable to evade.
How can you admire
such a horrible place?
Ah, you reveal your shortsightedness.
This ordeal only demonstrates
how effective facilities like
The Citadel are.
Pity it ended up in
separatist hands and not ours.
He has a point.
All right, snips, I need
you to lead the group.
Keep following the tunnel.
I'll catch up.
Hey, where are you going?
Obi-Wan's not here, so someone
has to protect our flank.
I guess it's a good thing
I came along after all.
We've received a coded transmission.
Apparently, they've
split up into two groups.
The rendezvous points are the
landing field behind the tower,
where artoo will pick
up Obi-Wan Kenobi,
and the pipeline exit, where
they'll find Anakin Skywalker.
And what if things don't
go according to plan?
Then we would have to send
an entire fleet to
get them out of there.
I am concerned that the jedi
have elected this
child to lead the group.
I've served with her many
times, and I trust her, captain.
Uh-oh.
Dead end.
It looks like there are
security guards there.
[R2-d2 beeps]
Okay, boss, we'll land and
wait for general Kenobi.
Uh-oh, that doesn't
look like general Kenobi.
We'll have to imprwvise.
Your arrival is long overdue.
Where haveou been?
[R2-d2 beeps]
Even so, the odds are three
to one that you are a traitor.
We will take you to interrogation below.
Yes, sir.
Move it.
[R2-d2 beeps]
Don't talk back to me, droid.
I'm in charge.
We have captured the shuttle
that infiltrated our defenses.
Good.
Guard the shuttle, and we'll
lure the jedi into a trap.
[R2-d2 beeps]
Sorry, commander.
Just wanted to fool them.
What are your orders?
[R2-d2 beeps]
You're right.
If we're not at the
shuttle, general Kenobi
could be walking into a trap.
We'll try to locate them
if they get captured.
Look out!
[Blasters firing]
[Lightsaber humming]
What happened?
Why didn't you blow the wall?
That part of the plan was your job.
I thought it was a dead end.
If master PLO really assigned
you to this mission, he would
have briefed you on the plan.
[Loud explosions]
The shuttle's there, but
there's no sign of artoo.
Something might have happened.
We'll have to make our way
around to the other side and
get a different view.
This could be a trap.
Anakin.
I must commend you on your
escape tactics, but in the end,
it was easy to predict your every move.
[Cackling]
This pipe leads up to
the top of the Ridge,
where artoo will pick us
up and get us out of here.
There's the hatch.
Let's go! Let's go!
Everyone in.
Don't use your lights, and make
sure your weapons are locked.
The slightest electronic pulse
could ignite this whole tube.
I hope somebody tells the droids that.
Welcome back.
I must say, you're not at all
what I pictured for someone
with such a soft voice.
I want your half of the information.
Give it to me now, or I'll
start executing your men.
This is war, Sobeck.
We're all prepared to
die to protect that intel.
[Laughs]
Really?
[Gasps]
[Blaster fires]
Sir, we have located the
other group, and our droids
are closing in on them.
Your jedi resolve only
delays the inevitable.
Take them to interrogation.
Torture them slowly.
[R2-d2 beeps]
So they were captured, huh?
And now they're moving
them to the prison block?
[R2-d2 beeps]
Yes, sir.
We will move to intercept them.
We'll take them from here.
Uh, I think we have
a... We'll handle it.
Yes, sir.
[R2-d2 beeps]
Good to see you, artoo.
I wondered where you've been.
[R2-d2 beeps]
The commander is pleased
to see you as well, sir,
but would like to return to
the shuttle as soon as possible.
Yes, I couldn't agree more.
What about general Skywalker, sir?
Not to worry.
He'll switch to plan "b."
How much longer are we
going to wander through this
tunnel in the dark?
Captain tarkin, haven't you
learned to trust me by now?
You may have earned my trust,
general Skywalker, but my faith
in your comrades is still lacking.
You lack faith in the jedi.
I find their tactics ineffective.
The jedi code prevents them
from going far enough to
achieve victory, to do
whatever it takes to win,
the very reason why
peacekeepers should
not be leading a war.
Have I offended you?
No.
I've also found that we
sometimes fall short of victory
because of our methods.
Well, I see we agree on something.
I think I found a way out.
What do you see, snips?
The coast is clear.
Any sign of Obi-Wan and the shuttle?
No, I don't see him or artoo anywhere.
We've got to go.
There could be a whole
battalion of droids out there.
Better than hiding in a fuel line.
[Lightsabers humming]
[Blasters firing]
The plan's been compromised.
The shuttle's not coming.
Throw me a charge.
[Loud explosion]
Let's go.
Time for plan "b."
There's a plan "b"?
There's always a backup plan.
We'll meet artoo at Obi-Wan's position.
Based on their recent
position, we believe they're
traveling along this cave system.
Uh, sir, the prisoners
did not make it to the
interrogation level.
What...Did...You... Just...Say?
Um, we think they might
have gone to the...
Sir, count dooku commands you
to contact him immediately.
Inform count dooku
that I am unreachable.
Send all units to the airfield.
It's their only possible way of escape.
Hold it.
Where are you going
with these prisoners?
We're transferring
them aboard the shuttle
from Citadel to Point Tarron.
Point Tarron?
There's no outpost there.
Uh, it's new.
[R2-d2 beeps]
We have orders.
We're coming aboard.
Wait.!
The prisoners are escaping
with reprogrammed battle droids.
Let no one on board that shuttle.
[Lightsaber hums]
[Blasters firing]
Sorry I'm late.
How nice of you to join us.
The ship is surrounded.
We need to launch a full forward assault
and take that vessel.
We may have a bigger problem:
Those turrets.
If we don't take them out, they
will use them to destroy the
shuttle and prevent our escape.
Which is precisely why we
should get aboard that shuttle
and use the weapon systems
to decimate those droids.
Whatever we're gonna
do, we better do it fast.
[R2-d2 beeps]
General Skywalker, a droid is
Manning one of those turrets.
They're gonna blow up the shuttle, sir.
This is our only chance.
We've got to stop him.
Echo, look out!
Echo!
We have to go now.
[Alarm beeping]
Master Kenobi, what has happened?
I'm afraid we've had a
situation with the shuttle.
By "situation," he
means "big explosion."
We're gonna need a rescue.
It will be done.
I'm sending our cruisers now.
We'll need to hold out until
the council sends a ship.
Not a problem.
We've beat them once.
We'll beat them again.
This landscape is almost
impossible to cross.
How are we going to get
to the rendezvous point?
That is the trap of The Citadel.
It was designed so it would be
almost impossible for fugitives
to get off the surface,
even if they escaped the tower.
Oh, lucky we're not just any fugitives.
I hope you're right.