Male announcer: Stranded!
Obi-Wan Kenobi,
Anakin Skywalker,
and his Padawan Ahsoka Tano
are caught in the middle
of a treacherous battle
between good and evil.
The scales now tipped
toward the dark side,
our three warriors must guard
against attack
as they plan their escape.
A great weight has been placed
on Anakin's shoulders,
for it is now that he must face
who he really is.
I'm getting a little tired
of how unreliable
the weather is here.
Some might say
that's part of the appeal.
You did well, Anakin.
How do you feel?
I'm not sure we're doing
the right thing by leaving.
The son is consumed
by the dark side.
And if we stay,
we may be used
to the dark side's advantage.
Well,
you want the bad news...
Or the really bad news?
Well, let's try
the bad news,
laced with a little optimism.
We've got two
cracked shilo pins,
a busted power converter,
the engines should be fired
twice to dump debris,
and the backup vents
need charging.
Sounds terribly downbeat.
Can it be fixed?
I can reroute
the primary initiator,
weld the dampening vents, and
that might give us enough power
to leave the atmosphere.
After that,
I have no guarantees
she'll hold together.
We'll take our chances.
Better than staying here.
Where are you going?
To see the father.
I'm not convinced that the son
will be contained here
without our help.
Perhaps we should make a stand.
Anakin...
if I don't get the father's
it'll haunt me forever.
> Forgive me, daughter.
I am an old fool
who believed
he could control the future.
Now you are gone...
And all is lost.
Sleep well, my child.
Sleep free.
You should have left by now.
Our ship needs repairs.
Do not underestimate my son.
He will seek your ship
to escape our isolation and
sow terror through the universe.
And while you are here,
he will use you to do it.
What will you do
now that he's given himself over
to the dark side?
It is my actions
that have unleashed great danger
on the universe.
I must kill him.
But he's too powerful
for you alone.
Hmm, perhaps,
perhaps not.
The force will decide.
I can help you.
The choice
is no longer yours to make.
Both our destinies are clouded.
This place
is strong with the force.
Darkness has no hold here.
Go,
ask,
you have grown strong
and powerful,
just as I imagined.
Master.
Do you believe
you are the chosen one?
How can I know?
I can tell you
what I believe.
I believe you will bring
balance to the force,
that you will face your demons
and... and this creature
of the dark side?
Do I leave,
or do I stay and kill him?
Neither.
Look deeper.
You will find another way.
I don't understand.
Not far from here,
there is a place which is strong
in the dark side of the force.
You must go there.
And destroy the son?
Remember your training,
Anakin.
Trust your instincts.
Master.
Master!
Might I suggest less sleeping
and a little more work?
Sorry, master Kenobi.
Here.
This should help.
We need to change plans.
You must focus
on the firing drives.
Disengage them.
But I'm almost finished
putting this junk heap
back together, and now...
just do as I say.
We don't have much time.
Well, you're the boss.
Where's Anakin?
He came to me for guidance,
but at the crossroad,
only he can choose.
The force will be his guide now.
I don't like this.
What have you done?
I have done nothing.
I am merely letting the will
of the force take shape.
Where has he gone?
To the well of the dark side.
Welcome.
I believe there has been
a misunderstanding.
We really don't
have to be enemies.
You murdered your sister.
The force is out of balance.
I have to stop you.
Must you?
[Lightsaber hums]
Anakin has gone to confront
your son, hasn't he?
Deep within this planet
all that is dark is channeled.
And how do I get there?
You cannot interfere.
The way I see it,
if we were not
supposed to interfere,
Ahsoka and I wouldn't be here
in the first place.
Look after the ship.
I'm going to find Anakin.
[Lightsaber humming]
There is no use
for such crude implements here.
I have a gift for you.
I've had enough
of your trickery.
Oh, but you'll like this one.
I promise.
What if I could show you
the future?
No!
Stop it!
Know yourself.
Know what you will become!
[Moaning]
I will not look!
The force is strong with you.
Anakin, please!
You were my brother, Anakin!
A powerful sith
you will become.
I hate you!
No.
No!
I will do such terrible things.
Yes.
But it doesn't have to be
that way.
The choice
is still yours to make.
How?
The future
by its nature can be changed.
Join me,
and together we will destroy
this emperor you see
in your visions.
Then we shall end war,
corruption, and suffering
throughout the galaxy.
Will we bring peace?
Of course.
[Faint tapping and beeping]
[Static crackling]
Finally!
This is jedi shuttle 634
calling on all secure channels
for help.
Do you read?
I repeat: We are stranded
and need immediate evac.
Come in, please!
Anakin, are you all right?
There has been
sorry.
You will not understand
what I have to do
to end the clone war.
[Screams]
Anakin, why?
I'm sorry.
I have seen
that it is the jedi who will
stand in the way of peace.
He's mine now.
[Cackles maniacally]
Ahsoka, come in, please.
Can you hear me?
Ahsoka!
Yes, master.
Any success with Anakin?
No, quite the opposite.
Master...
What are you saying?
Anakin has joined
with the son.
Do not engage him.
But...
just do as I say.
Listen to me.
You have to disable the ship.
But I just finished
putting it back together.
Ahsoka, please listen.
We have to prevent Anakin
and the son from leaving.
Yes, master.
Ahsoka,
what have you done?
Ahsoka!
[Grunts and gasps]
Hmm, nice job.
What took you so long?
Here.
I did as you said.
The shuttle's going nowhere
without that.
Good, that gives us
some time to rescue Anakin.
I can't make contact
with anybody.
I don't think anyone
will hear my signal.
My father still has hold
over this realm,
but I will be able
to draw any ship here soon.
If I know my old master,
he, too, will try to stop us.
Together with your father, they
would be a formidable opponent.
I can turn the tide
stay here.
What did he show you?
I've seen what I become,
and I cannot let that happen.
And for this, you join him?
Your destiny can change
just as quickly as the love
in one's heart can fade.
Nothing is set in stone.
But I will cause
so much pain.
If there is to be balance,
what you have seen
must be forgotten.
So cold.
It's ironic, my sister.
I truly loved.
Where am I?
I have brought you back
to my monastery.
[Sighs]
What happened?
My son broke the laws of time
and showed you
what you should never have seen.
I don't remember.
I have erased that time.
We shall never know.
Master!
Are you all right?
I think so,
but we must stop the son
once and for all.
We have little time,
and you'll get only one chance.
You know what you must do.
How quaint,
my own personal send-off.
I ask you one last time.
Do not leave, my son.
You have no power
to keep me, old man.
You must understand by now,
this planet is not my destiny.
What you will do
will destroy all that is good.
I beg you,
restrain yourself and stay.
I cannot.
And then it shall be.
I love you, my son.
Do you?
[Lightsaber hums]
[Low thudding]
[Gasping and choking]
[Lightsabers hum]
[Gasps]
[Grunts]
[Lightsabers humming]
[Both scream]
[Both grunt]
What?
[Chuckles]
You're going to kill me now?
I held hope that you
could resist the dark side.
But I see now,
there is no going back.
Father.
[Grunts]
No!
What have you done?
It did not have to be this way.
Yes, my child, it did.
You and I are tied together,
runs through me.
This way, I take your power.
[Gasps]
Please, don't die.
I always knew
there was good in you.
[Lightsaber hums]
[Gasps and groans]
And so you have betrayed me,
father.
[Gasping]
It is done.
And now I die,
my heart broken,
the role you will play.
And what is that?
You are the chosen one.
You have brought balance
to this world.
Stay on this path,
and you will do it again
for the galaxy.
But beware your...
Heart.
[Low rumbling]
[Rocks smashing]
[Glass shatters]
[Explosion]
General Skywalker, come in!
We read you, Rex.
Can you hear me?
Yes, sir, standing by.
We were worried.
You were off the scopes there
for a moment.
A moment?
We've been gone
more than a moment, Rex.
Sir, I don't understand.
You'll need to explain.
You wouldn't believe me
if I told you.
We're coming in now.