Separatist attack!
After the destruction of the Republic
outpost on the Rishi moon,
General Grievous and Asajj Ventress
plan an attack on the planet Kamino,
home of the cloning factories.
Meanwhile, aboard a Jedi cruiser,
Jedi Knights Anakin Skywalker
and Obi-Wan Kenobi
examine an intercepted message
from General Grievous.
We are decrypting the audio, sir.
The clone planet of Kamino
will be a dangerous target.
Just make sure you hold up
your half of the mission.
We must stop
the production of new clones
if we are to win this war.
Kamino...
They're going to attack
our home planet.
The Separatists are taking
quite the chance even considering this.
With all due respect, General,
if someone comes to our home,
they better be carrying
a big blaster.
I concur with Captain Rex, sir.
This is personal for us clones.
We'll make sure Kamino is secure.
Tell your troopers in the 501st
they're going home.
All is ready, General.
Good.
We will attack Tipoca City first.
I have the exact locations of both
the clone DNA room
and the clone trooper barracks.
Both shall be annihilated
under my hand.
Our hands, General.
Count Dooku assigned us both
this task.
But of course, assassin.
I look forward to meeting you.
Are the aqua droids prepared
for phase two of the plan?
Yes, mistress.
Masters Kenobi and Skywalker.
Welcome to Kamino.
Greetings, generals.
I wish our arrival wasn't
under such circonstances.
We believe Grievous is planning
a Separatist attack on Kamino.
But the Republic blockade
is far too strong.
They would not dare.
Look around, Fives.
Feels like yesterday we were here,
heading to target practice.
Remember that?
Do I ever.
You actually remember us.
I remember all my brothers.
Is Hevy here?
Where's he?
There was an incident
on the Rishi moon outpost.
He saved our lives,
but he gave up his own.
I see...
Hevy gave you his medal?
So why have you returned to Kamino?
The generals received word
of an impending attack here.
How can I help?
Attack formation Echo-3.
- Status.
- Deflector shields raised.
Destroyers in position.
Forward cannons ready.
Landing craft prepared.
All ships are in position.
Commence attack.
The Separatist fleet
is pressing their attack, sir.
Contact command at Tipoca City.
Shore up our defenses.
The fleet is not as large
as I expected.
Begin the air strike.
Good to see you, General.
Ready to have some fun?
You know me, broadside.
I'd rather be up here
than stuck in a command center.
Warning! Falling debris.
Grievous appears
to be sacrificing his transports
in favor of protecting
his command ship.
Something's not right.
Reinforcements have arrived.
Send out the aqua droids
to assemble the assault craft.
Focus on the cruisers.
I'm gonna press the attack, master.
Wait.
It's too easy.
Not even Grievous
would attack so recklessly.
Master, the battle's up here in space,
not down there.
The debris from the destroyed
Separatist ships is the key.
What are you thinking?
I think I'd like to go for a swim.
Nothing as of yet.
Only you could be worried
about the ships I already shot down.
Wait a minute.
Aqua droids.
Looks as though
they're assembling assault craft.
Anakin, I was right.
Those downed transports were hiding
ships for an underwater assault.
Anakin, come in.
Hold it right there.
Do not move.
Thanks for the lift, friend.
Anakin, the city is under attack.
I need you down here now.
On my way.
Sir, you sent for us?
It's a dangerous assignment,
but I want you two up on the bridge
in sniper positions.
We're on it.
Watch out!
Kill them all.
99, get out of here!
This is no place for you.
There aren't enough droids here
to capture the city.
They're trying to distract us.
Go protect the DNA chamber.
- I'll deal with Grievous.
- Got it.
Fives, keep firing.
We can beat these guys.
99.
Here's some ammo.
Is there a better spot,
a better defensive position we can take?
Droids! Behind us!
Look! Grenades!
Thanks, 99.
Good job.
Look out. There's more.
Cadets. What are you doing here?
- We got separated from our group.
- Where were they taking you?
The barracks.
I know the best way there.
Keep firing.
No mercy!
Your skills are impressive.
Perhaps a match for my own,
assassin.
Count Dooku may have taught you
how to swing a lightsaber, General,
but that hardly makes you my equal.
And yet I am the general
in charge of this assault.
Remember, assassin,
you are to recover the clone DNA.
Why not just destroy it?
Because the DNA could unlock
new possibilities for us.
Keep playing with your droids.
I'll handle breaking
into the DNA room.
Shall I provide you
with a droid escort?
My dear General,
there's nothing you have
that I could want.
What are we gonna do?
"A Separatist victory
"means death for all of us."
The cadet is right.
What are we gonna do?
We fight.
But our training's not finished.
Look around.
We're one in the same,
same heart, same blood.
Your training is in your blood.
And my blood's boiling for a fight.
This is our home.
This is our war.
What about weapons?
The armory.
It's just a few corridors away
here in the barracks.
I can retrieve all the firepower
that we need.
So who wants to blast some droids?
The droids are spread thin.
We must press our offensive now.
I was beginning to think
my presence went unnoticed.
You were planning of leaving
without saying hello?
Here it is.
Everything we need is here.
Excellent work, 99.
Hurry up. The droids
have almost reached the barracks.
Let's get into position.
Open up.
Get those doors open and scare
the remaining clones out of hiding.
Roger, roger.
Blast them.
All too easy.
Define "easy", General.
Kenobi, Kamino has fallen.
Your clone army is doomed.
I beg to differ, Grievous.
Cadets, now!
Last one, Commander.
Make it count.
I'll get more.
99, you can't.
I'm a soldier like you.
This is what I was bred for.
99!
Commander Cody.
The droids have been pushed back
to the main hangar.
We've got to stop meeting like this,
my friend.
Move it, troopers!
On the double!
Fire!
Look! It's the general!
I suppose
you expect me to surrender.
Actually, I plan to let the clones
execute you right now.
Not this time.
We did it.
We held them back.
We lost a true soldier.
He really was one of us.
You both really stepped up
in the heat of battle.
We did what we had to do, sir,
what any clone would have done.
Both of you showed valor out there,
real courage.
Reminded me of me, actually.
You're both officially being made
ARC troopers.
I don't think the Separatists
will be coming back here any time soon.
But if they do,
Kamino will be lucky
to have clones like you defending it.
Good job, men.