Trapped behind enemy lines!
Carrying secret information,
vital to the Republic's war
effort, jedi master Even Piell and captain
Tarkin were taken prisoner by the separatists.
An elite strike team
led by Obi-Wan Kenobi
and Anakin Skywalker landed
on the planet, Lola Sayu,
and infiltrated the prison.
The team rescued master Piell
and Tarkin, but they were
pursued by the prison's
evil commandant, Osi Sobeck.
During the escape,
their ship was destroyed.
Now we find them on the run, desperate
to escape the trap that is The Citadel.
We're clear!
What's our next move?
We're going to have to
fight our way off this rock.
Contact the Council.
See when they plan to rescue us.
I'll handle it.
Master Piell, it's good to
see you alive, my friend.
Likewise, master windu.
Our escape route has been
compromised, and there are several
squads of droids closing in on us.
When can we expect your arrival?
Master Plo is already en route.
Gunships will arrive to
evacuate you and your men,
but do not delay, only a small window of
opportunity shall we have.
Your rendezvous point will be this island.
Understood.
May the force be with you.
Incoming!
No doubt, there's more on the way.
Count Dooku, my lord.
Commander Sobeck, you've been
avoiding my transmissions.
My deepest respect.
I was hoping to surprise
you with good news.
Good news would indeed be a surprise.
Have the prisoners been captured?
Not yet, my lord, but we've
located their position and my
droids are moving in now.
I need not remind you that
the prisoners are carrying
secret hyperspace coordinates
into the core systems of the
Republic and our Separatist homeworlds.
This information will allow
us to launch a surprise attack
on coruscant, striking
a crippling blow to the
Republic and the jedi.
Yes, my lord.
I will see to it that they are
soon back in our possession.
You should know, commander,
right now your honesty is the
only thing keeping you alive.
They're boxing us in!
Lock in your cables!
Artoo, we need your droids
to hold off the enemy as long
as possible.
Good, everybody follow me!
This is sheer madness!
We understand, sir.
We will delay the enemy
as long as possible.
Prepare for attack.
It was an honor to serve under you, sir.
Keep moving!
All for one and one
for a...
Keep moving, keep moving!
Master Tiin, you should be
leading the fighter attack.
Once you punch a hole through
their defenses, I will lead the
gunships down to the
surface and extract the team.
Depending on the size of
their force, I don't know how
much time we can buy you.
You will do your best, I'm sure.
If the team isn't at the
extraction point when you
arrive, you may be forced to
leave them, or put us all at risk.
I'm afraid master gallia is right.
They'll be there.
The prisoners have evaded us long enough.
Bring out the anoobas!
Use them for tracking only!
Contact me as soon as the
fugitives have been located.
Roger, Roger.
What if your jedi friends
are not there when we arrive?
Keep moving and you won't have
to worry about that, Tarkin.
Why did master Piell have to
share half the intel with that guy?
It's like he's not even
grateful we rescued him.
Captain Tarkin feels the jedi
should be relieved from the
burden of leading the war effort.
That's ridiculous.
Maybe, but we aren't soldiers.
We're peacekeepers.
The jedi code often prevents us from
going far enough to achieve victory.
A rather simple point of view.
Either way, he is a good captain.
Did you hear that?
Yes.
We're going to have company.
Commander, the additional
reinforcements have arrived.
Tighten your grip, K2-B4.
The Republic will almost
certainly attempt a second
mission to infiltrate our
defenses and rescue the prisoners.
I'm counting on you to ensure that
nothing slips past our blockade.
You know it's not wise to
argue with master Piell.
It's certainly not a good career move.
General Skywalker, I stand by
my principles, no matter what.
Besides, I needn't worry about my career.
I've fallen into favor
with the chancellor.
He shall support me.
Oh, I happen to know the
chancellor quite well, myself.
Oh, really?
Really.
Let's keep moving.
If we're not at the
rendezvous at the exact time,
we'll miss our window.
Those creatures are gaining.
If they've caught our scent,
they'll lead the droids right to us.
We're gonna have to deal with them.
What about using this
cave to surprise them?
If we can get them to pass
by, we can attack them from
behind, but we need a distraction.
Leave that to me.
And Obi-Wan, of course.
Okay, the rest of you, follow me.
Keep going!
Ahsoka and I will take care of the droids.
Master Piell!
I have to get help.
No.
Don't leave.
Listen to me carefully, child.
The information, I need you to
deliver it back to the Council.
I should find Anakin or Obi-Wan.
They need to hear this.
No.
You must listen.
But I wasn't assigned to the team.
I lied just so I could
be a part of the mission.
Whether you were meant to
be on this mission or not,
you are now the most important part of it.
Remember this, and see to it that the
information I'm about to give
you is revealed to no one but
the jedi Council.
Sir!
The anoobas have located the
fugitives along the northern shore.
Squad, come with me!
I will deal with this personally.
So much for the hunting party.
There are more squads on their way.
Oh, no.
He died honorably.
What about the information?
I have it.
He told me just before he died.
We don't have much time.
Let's take this moment to
honor him, then we must move on.
He would have wanted us
to complete our mission.
There have not been battles like these
since the days of the old Republic.
Indeed.
Good hunting.
There's the extraction point.
Incoming!
Look what I found.
They are too many droid fighters.
We need more time to
break through the blockade.
We're out of time, master Tiin.
We must break through now.
Very well.
Wing commanders, form up.
We're going in.
Captain!
If I can't have the information,
it will die with you.
My thanks, padawan Tano.
I see you've trained her well.
The rescue ship should be here by now.
So should the rest of the separatist army.
I believe you've worn out your welcome.
Admiral coburn, we have the survivors.
Recall all fighters.
Yes, general.
Prepare to jump to lightspeed.
We're all ready, admiral.
Of master Piell's loss,
we are sorry to hear.
He will be missed.
Because of his great
sacrifice, we now have the
nexus route coordinates.
Captain Tarkin and Ahsoka
have each memorized half.
Debrief them both, we must.
With all due respect, master
jedi, I was instructed by
chancellor Palpatine to bring the
intel directly to him for debriefing.
I promised master Piell that
I would deliver it only to
the Council, and that's what I will do.
Hmm.
Personally meet with
the chancellor, I will.
Decide what is best to do, we shall.
Master Plo, there's
something we want to ask you.
Did you assign ahsoka to the mission?
It appears I did.
A job well done, general Skywalker.
I wish more jedi had your
military sensibilities.
Perhaps I can inform the
chancellor of your valor.
I'm not sure what to
think of your new ally.
Well, I think we need people like him.
This is a war.
If we aren't willing to
do what it takes to win,
we risk losing everything
we try to protect.
Unfortunately, war tends to
distort our point of view.
If we sacrifice our code,
even for victory, we may lose
that which is most important:
Our honor.