Conflict With no end in sight.
Across the galaxy, the
quagmire of war continues.
While clone troopers suffer
casualties at alarming rates,
The galactic senate convenes
an emergency session
To debate the true cost of the war.
Order.
Let senator Saam finish.
This is a matter not of philosophy.
More troops are needed.
The Republic cannot afford
to let the separatists
gain any more ground.
Our generals inform us
that troops in the field
continue to perform valiantly.
What we cannot afford,
is to be irresponsible.
The Republic is near bankruptcy
due to the cost of this war.
Bankruptcy is not
necessary, my friends.
If we pass senator Saam's bill
to open new lines of credit,
We will gain access
to the needed funds.
Won't this bill essentially
deregulate the banks?
A small price to pay To
finance the war, is it not?
We must keep the war going.
Get a bill on the table!
Keep the war going.
Members of the senate.
Do you hear yourselves?
More money, more clones, more war.
Say nothing of fiscal responsibility,
What about moral responsibility?
Hasn't this war gone on long enough?
Senator Amidala, are you
suggesting we surrender
to the separatists?
Of course not.
But negotiation might be a
better course of action.
You can't negotiate
with those animals.
Keep the war going.
Vote now.
Members of the senate, I suggest
we table any emergency bill
Until it is determined
whether or not deregulation
Is the right course of action.
Very well.
We shall let calmer heads prevail.
That legislation would have
meant billions for us.
I tried my best To
push the bill through.
You did your part, representative.
Senator Amidala is the problem.
I thought age might
temper her idealism.
I know people who could
do something about her.
That task is more difficult
than you presume.
Gentlemen, the banking
clan and trade federation
Are about business, not violence.
Hmm, in this case, our
business is violence.
Precisely.
With or without senator
Amidala, the galactic senate
Is unlikely to deregulate The banks.
until this war hits home.
What exactly are you proposing?
Perhaps some unexpected
bloodshed on Coruscant,
Uh, may change a few minds.
Coruscant?
Coruscant has not been
attacked in over 1,000 years.
Then it has a false sense of security.
There are some powerful clients
On the other side who could
Help us, uh, Shall we
say, make the point?
Ooh, I like this plan.
No one cares what you think.
You must ask the jedi council
To speak with chancellor
Palpatine.
Don't involve me in this.
A peaceful solution ls the only
way out of this morass of war.
That's not my role, Padme.
Why not?
Why isn't it your role?
Aren't we jedi knights?
Isn't it our duty to speak our
minds to advise the chancellor?
Uh, I suggest you teach
my young padawan
A thing or two about politics.
After today's debate, I was
hoping she learned a great deal.
Truthfully, I don't
understand any of it.
I know the separatists are evil,
But all anyone argued about
was banking deregulation,
lnterest rates, and, well,
Almost nothing about why We're
fighting in the first Place.
War's complicated, Ahsoka.
But let me simplify it.
The separatists believe
the Republic is corrupt,
But they're wrong, and we
have to restore order.
Maybe talking to the jedi
council isn't the role for you
after all.
Thanks for your help.
Come on, Ahsoka.
Hey.
You told me to teach
her about politics.
So I'm going to.
There is a problematic situation
brewing in the senate.
We must insure that everything
my master has set in motion
Does not unhinge.
My representatives ln the Republic
are relying on you, general.
See that your droids
complete their mission.
But of course, Count.
They will not fail.
If only I could talk
to senator Bonteri.
Who's he?
He is a she, a senator
in the confederacy
Of independent systems.
Your friend is a separatist?
One of Dooku's pawns?
The separatists used to be
a part of the Republic.
I was close with many of
the senators who left.
I may not agree with them,
but they're more than pawns.
If you think negotiating
is the right thing to do,
Let's talk to her.
The senate's made it illegal.
Illegal?
They say official meetings
would only legitimize
The separatists.
Well, master Skywalke
and I hold what we call
aggressive negotiations all the time.
It's a shame you can't hold more
peaceful talks When you want.
You just gave me an idea.
You're a jedi, which gives
you special clearance.
Right.
And jedi are allowed to travel to
neutral worlds like Mandalore,
Where we could then board
A cargo ship to a separatist System.
Are you suggesting I use
my status as a jedi
To smuggle you behind Enemy lines?
It's just that you could get
Us through to meet with her
And I haven't seen her Or
her family in so long.
Relax.
I'll help you.
Besides, master Skywalke
Said you should teach me
About politics.
Right.
You know, you two have more
ln common than you think.
It's no wonder you get along Well.
Huh.
Of course.
So where are we heading?
Raxus.
Have all the preparations Been made?
I'm about to deploy The infiltrators.
You must hurry.
The senate is restless.
I don't take orders from
you, only count Dooku.
You have been designed
for this mission
to be the ultimate infiltration units.
Some of you may not return.
Actually, none of you Will return.
But don't let that get ln your way.
Is that clear?
Get them to Coruscant.
Roger, roger.
Move along, please.
Move along.
Identification, please.
Excuse me.
Is this platform b?
Uh, platform b... this way.
Hello, old friend.
Ahsoka, this is Miina Bonteri.
She was my mentor when I
was growing up on Naboo.
You're a separatist?
Well, of course, my dear.
What were you expecting?
Now, come.
I have a transport waiting.
Lux, come down here
and help our guests
With their luggage, please.
Padme, it's so good to see you.
Yes.
How things have changed
since the last time we met.
Let's go inside.
There's much to discuss.
Please, allow me.
May I?
I can handle it.
He's grown so much, Miina.
Time won't stop, even
if we are at war.
And I'm afraid tse events
Are shaping his young life.
With all due respect, As a separatist,
Didn't you create this war?
Ahsoka!
It's all right.
That's a very polarized
point of view, my dear.
Would it surprise you to
know that many of the people
You call separatists feel the
same way about the Republic
And the jedi?
Lux's father was like that.
Maybe I could speak with him.
If only you could.
A year ago next week,
he was setting up a base
on Aargonar when clones attacked.
My husband fought bravely in
self-defense,
but was killed.
Excuse me.
I think I'll get some air.
Ah, the cleaning droids.
Finally.
Don't waste any time.
Get to work.
You're a jedi, aren't you?
Yes.
Why do you ask?
Before the war, I was
always told jedi were good.
And now?
I don't know anymore.
There are lot of terrible things
happening, a lot of killing.
And now my friends are saying
the jedi are to blame.
I'm the first jedi you've
ever met, aren't I?
Well, um...
Yes.
Look at me.
I'm not so bad, am I?
No, not bad at all.
Uh.
Well, it seems boys are the
same whether they're Republic
Or separatist.
Wait.
How many separatists have you met?
What?
Well, I mean, you think
we're all the bad guys.
But how many of us
have you actually met?
And droids don't count.
Well, other than military officers
like Grievous and Ventress,
None, I guess.
You and your mother are the first.
Well, look at me.
Am I so bad?
I sense Dooku's dirty
hand ln all of this.
He's just the leader of the senate.
He's not the leader of
the entire universe.
Oh, I forgot.
You actually admire the man.
We'll never entirely agree
on Dooku, my old friend,
But we can agree on the
need to stop this war.
The question is how.
That is why it was so urgent
that I speak with you.
The Republic senate is holding
a critical vote on whether
or not to escalate the war effort.
However, many of the delegates
are undecided as to what to do.
How interesting.
You would find the separatist
parliament in a similar dilemma.
I am certain if you could
convince your representatives
to extend an olive branch of
peace towards the Republic,
there might be enough sympathy
ln the senate to finally
open negotiations.
I admire your spirit, Padme.
I can at least put the
motion on the floor.
Thank you, Miina.
That's all I ask.
To peace, then.
To hope.
How many lives on both sides
have to end before we see
the futility?
Surely there's room in the
galaxy for confederate
and Republic planets to coexist.
I move that we immediately
open peace negotiations
with chancellor
palpatine on Coruscant.
The corporate alliance will
never allow this to happen.
This is a democracy, and
unlike the Republic,
corporations do not rule us.
Nay!
Quiet.
In accordance with the bylaws
of independent systems,
a voice vote is required.
All in favor of initiating
peace negotiations with
the galactic Republic, say aye.
Aye.
All those opposed.
Nay.
The ayes have it.
This is quite troubling, your own
senate voting to end the war.
I assure you, gentlemen, your
worries are gravely exaggerated.
How can you be sure this groundswell
of peace won't continue?
Where is the attack we were promised?
We need fighting to feed the
machine and our profits.
After our attack, the chances
of peace will disappear.
The banking clan, the trade
federation, and the techno union
will all get their fair
share and then some.
Well, this is good-bye.
I've been disappointed before,
and yet, I almost feel as if
this time the tide has
turned in the war.
You should hurry.
Goody-bye, young one.
You really believe the
Republic will vote for peace?
I hope so.
I wouldn't want to meet you on
the battlefield,
for your sake.
Go, you two, quickly.
Team leaders, come in.
Commence phase two.
All right, everybody
have your passes out.
Hmm, generator maintenance, eh?
Yeah, well, everything checks out.
Good luck down there.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, wait a minute.
Power generators are that way.
Stupid droids.
Well, well, well.
This is quite a stunning development.
Your excellency, we would be
remiss, if not irresponsible,
to reject the separatists proposal.
Of course.
An end to the fighting,
would mean there's no need
to borrow money for more clones.
I can see why you would
Want so badly to believe
That the separatists Desire peace.
I don't understand.
In the past, whenever we've
reached out our hands in peace,
They've been slapped away.
Can we believe that they're ready
to sue for peace so easily?
If I might speak with
you confidentially,
I know that this is sincere.
I've been in contact with
my old friend Miina Bonteri,
And the origin of the
proposal is with her.
Bonteri?
How was the dialogue established?
Does it matter, chancellor,
if the result is an end to the war?
I see your point, my child.
Then we shall put the
vote to the floor.
Sweeper droids?
We didn't schedule a cleaning.
Oh!
What's going on?
Given that the separatists have
put a call for negotiations
On the table,
the need for additional
troops seems ill-timed.
Which means there is no need
to deregulate the banks.
I say we vote that down now.
There is a move to vote on the
proposed bill to lift regulations
On the banking clan.
Dooku promised he
would stop this vote.
You may enter your vote.
We're under attack!
The bombing of the power
Generator has been confirmed
As a separatist attack.
They must pay for what they have done.
But was the separatist congress
that issued the bill of peace.
Obviously a tactic to lower our
defenses and launch this attack.
No.
That's not true.
I move to immediately
deregulate the banks.
We need a banloan to
get more troops now.
What are we waiting for?
I'm afraid we've been
given little choice.
to insure the safety of the Republic,
We must deregulate the banks.
I'm returning your padawan.
I'm sorry your talks
with Bonteri failed.
How did you know?
We have eyes and ears
everywhere, Ahsoka.
That was dangerous and
careless, going to Raxus,
Not to mention illegal.
You went too far this time.
You would do the same.
You do the same all the time.
This was too much.
Maybe so.
But I did realize something.
The politics of this war,
are not as black and white
as I once thought they were.