Truth can strike down the spectre of fear.
Peace shattered.
Once-promising negotiations
between the Republic and
the separatists are now in
shambles following a droid suicide
bombing on the capitol
city-planet of Coruscant.
As fear and anger prevail,
the senate overwhelmingly passes
a bill to deregulate the banks,
opening the gateway
to additional troops and
an increase in fighting.
Members of the senate, please, please...
How dare they?
They attack,
and now they want peace?
Chancellor Palpatine,
may I remind the senators that
the peace proposal was made
prior to their assault.
That only highlights
its insincerity.
Chancellor Palpatine,
in light of this unprovoked attack
on Coruscant and the
vulnerabilities it raises,
I propose the Republic purchase an
additional 5 million clone troopers.
The Republic is already
operating in deep debt.
How do you propose we pay
for these additional troops?
My people are drafting an
emergency appropriations bill
- that would raise funds...
- from the banking clan?
Yes, of course.
Do you have an alternate means of paying?
One alternative might be to
stop the war, not escalate it.
- Traitor!
No!
You cannot believe her.
Whoever attacked the power grid
wants us to continue to fight.
It's a calculated attempt to
destroy the peace process.
Not everyone in the confederacy wants this.
I know this for a fact.
You have separatists
friends, senator?
Whose side are you on?
What?
We will not stand for this.
Please, the young senator
from Naboo makes a point.
There is no need to...
We have just received a
message from our opponent,
Count Dooku.
Your Republic forces have carried
out a barbaric attack on our people,
and among the deaths was the
very sponsor of the peace accord,
senator Miina Bonteri.
What? No.
With her needless death,
I must formally withdraw the proposal
for peace offered by our senate.
We must not show weakness.
Thank you, Teckla.
Yes, my lady.
I can't believe it.
I just can't believe the Republic
would target senator Bonteri.
She was the only one willing
to stand up for peace.
You shouldn't believe it.
The Republic spies are
reporting that senator Bonteri
was murdered by Dooku's thugs.
That message to the senate was a
ploy to disguise his true actions.
I am so sorry, Padme.
If your friend met with a violent
end because of her politics,
let's make sure her courageous
effort wasn't in vain.
What can we do?
For one, defeat this bill.
Can we really win this war
with the troops that we have?
Let's hope we don't have to.
I'll start lining up support,
but I'll need ammunition.
We can't afford ammunition,
remember?
I joke.
Go to the banking clan and
see how much interest they're
going to charge for the loan.
The more I know about what the
exact cost of this bill will be,
the better I can make my case to defeat it.
Right, let's go, uncle.
You know these
banking clan people.
Plus, you owe me for
telling such a bad joke.
Tee ta poo shan aka.
We will lend the Republic at our
standard interest rate of...
25%.
- What?
- 25%.
That's outright theft.
Your previous arrangement
with the Republic was 10%.
Please, please,
that was before deregulation.
The same rules don't apply,
my dear.
The separatists don't
seem to mind a rate hike.
In fact, they just secured a
loan to fund an additional
3 million battle droids.
They would wipe us out.
You would let Dooku do that?
You live on Coruscant too.
We have no stake in this war,
senator. You know that.
War is... Distasteful to all of us.
25% interest.
That's a lot of credits.
The interest alone could
completely bankrupt the Republic.
As it is, social services have
suffered because of this war,
education, infrastructure, health care.
If we go deeper into debt, the basic
needs of our people will evaporate.
- This is good.
- It is?
Clearly taking out a loan
on such obscene terms
would essentially
destroy the Republic,
regardless of the
outcome of the war.
We only need to sway another
handful of senators,
as long as they don't
buckle to the threats.
What threats?
Some members have
received messages,
warning them not to vote against the bill.
Considering what's happened
to your friend Bonteri,
they're frightened.
A mandatory blackout
is in progress.
All citizens report to the
designated safe area.
A mandatory blackout
is in progress.
All citizens report to the
designated safe area.
Ugh!
No!
No! Ugh!
Can't you all see this
bill is short-sighted?
Millions of clones
won't win this war.
The only winner will be the banking clan.
They want to pass
this bill so badly,
they're using scare tactics to sway votes.
I am not intimidated,
senator Amidala.
Then why are you voting
for additional troops?
I happen to believe more clones
are precisely what we need,
and my caucus agrees with me.
I'm sorry.
Uncle ono, what happened?
Two thugs jumped me,
but I am fine.
This is outrageous.
Something has to be done.
Padme,
this will not change my mind.
No matter what,
I will vote against the bill.
♪ ♪
I see senator Amidala
hasn't given up her crusade.
She doesn't have the votes,
my lord.
Ha-ha-ha.
We've taken care of 20 senators.
Ha.
It may be time to send
her a message as well.
You want us to have
a talk with her?
No.
I think something special is called
for in senator Amidala's case.
We're all ears, boss.
Take her out of the game.
♪ ♪
As long as senators are being
threatened and attacked,
I'm afraid we don't
stand a chance.
Intimidation won't work on everyone.
Senator Farr is proof of that.
Even so, we're still at least
six votes short of a majority,
and you saw how effective
my plea was today.
Some minds can't be altered
no matter what they hear.
From my experience,
it depends a great deal on
who's sending the message.
And what are you thinking?
Bail, you're the finest
public speaker I know.
If anyone can convince
the senate that voting
for this bill will
bankrupt the Republic both
financially and spiritually,
it's you.
It will be dangerous.
I urge you to speak before the full senate.
I'll need some time to prepare.
Good.
In the meantime, I'll pay another
visit to those still undecided.
I'll be parked just over there, my lady.
Thank you.
This way, uncle.
What does ideology matter at this point?
Is it worth being beaten to death?
Look at what they did to you.
These wounds will heal,
but what about the millions
who are dying in this war?
Who?
The clones?
We created them for
just that purpose.
They are people.
The people I care about
are my constituents,
the ones who put me in office.
And when was the last time you
ever spoke to your people?
Probably the same time you did,
or you, senator.
Senator Christo, please,
is there anything we can do to
get you to change your mind?
Where does senator
Organa stand on all this?
Why isn't he here?
Senator Organa is preparing to
speak before the full senate.
Senator Organa?
Hmm, I'll listen to what he has to say.
So you are open to voting with us?
I said I'll listen to what he has to say.
Well, it's better than a no,
and I'm sure when Christo and the
others hear what bail has to say,
they will vote our way.
Can I give you a ride?
My driver's only a block away.
I think I'd like to walk.
- But, Padme...
- Don't worry, uncle Ono,
I can take care of myself.
Plus, I can use the fresh air.
Just be careful.
Oh, yeah...
Put your hands up.
Arrest these bounty hunters.
We'll take care of this, miss.
Drop your weapons and come with us quietly.
Quietly?
Where's my driver?
Where's my...
Hey, my ride!
My eyes!
Land the vehicle.
That is a stolen vehicle.
Those bounty hunters
were trying to kill me.
I am a senator.
I demand that you arrest them.
Get your hands in the air.
Ouch.
Don't you think you should
report this to the jedi council?
There's nothing they can do.
I know who did it.
They were bounty hunters,
paid to stop me from voting
against the troop increase.
What has happened to democracy?
And why doesn't
anyone seem to care?
You do.
Forgive me, my lady.
Um, you're not like
most politicians.
If only that were enough, Teckla.
Well, you actually
talk to the people,
people like me.
- Good night, my lady.
- Teckla,
tell me, how is your family?
They are fine.
How is the war affecting them?
Well, it hasn't been easy,
and it's only getting worse.
How?
Please, tell me.
Tell me how it's geting worse.
You're not gonna get away like
your lady friend, senator.
Senator.
Medic!
Oh, Padme.
- What is it?
- You must come quickly.
You need to see something.
Bail, what happened?
- Padme...
- Senator, you need to lie down.
My speech, my speech...
The senate is expecting me.
Is there any way?
I'm sorry. He's in no
condition to even stand.
We need to take him
to the hospital.
Of course. Take him at once.
The speech... Padme,
you must address the senate.
Only you can do this.
Perhaps we should get the vote started.
I told senator Organa
I'd allow him to speak.
We have waited long enough.
I agree with senator Orn free Taa.
Let's vote.
You must give the
speech in his place.
But they're expecting to hear
from the great bail Organa.
He carries a certain weight.
He's seen as a voice of reason.
You are very respected.
As a partisan.
I've been against this bill from day one.
If they didn't listen to me before,
why would they listen now?
Because you do listen.
You understand what the
people are going through.
Please.
Your people are waiting for you.
Let us now vote on senator
Burtoni's bill to fund
5 million additional clones.
The opposition to this bill
must be allowed to speak first.
Unfortunately, senator Organa
is nowhere to be found.
I will speak on his behalf.
Senator Amidala will be permitted to speak.
Teckla Minnau.
What did she say?
Teckla is one of my aides.
Like so many of the people that we
tell ourselves we're here to serve,
Teckla lives in a district that rarely
has electricity and running water
as a result of the war.
Her children can now only
bathe every two weeks,
and they have no light in which
to read or study at night.
The Republic has always
funded these basic services,
but now,
there are those who would
divert the money to the war
with no thought for what
the people need to survive.
If not for people like Teckla
and her children, who are we
fighting for?
My people, your people, all of our people.
This war is meant to
save them from suffering,
not increase it.
I support our brave soldiers,
whether they come from the clone factories
or from any of the thousands of
systems loyal to the Republic,
but if we continue to
impoverish our people,
it is not on the battlefield
where Dooku will defeat us,
but in our own homes.
Therefore,
it is our duty
and our responsibility
to preserve the lives of those around us
by defeating this bill.
Well done, Padme.
Isn't it remarkable,
that one can have all
the power in the galaxy,
and yet the words of a single senator,
can sway the thoughts of millions?
What do you plan to do about this?
For now, we must adhere to the
principles of our democracy.
We must let the wheels of the senate turn.