Narrator: Jedi abducted!
Ahsoka Tano is missing in action.
Captured and released
into an hostile jungle
she fights to stay alive
with the help a small
band of jedi younglins
As Anakin Skywalker scours the galaxy
desperate to find his lost apprentice.
Trandoshan sport hunters
track the youngling prey.
With the death of their leader Kalifa,
and separated from her friends,
we find Ashoka on the run
as the hunters close in around her.
[TENSE MUSIC]
[TRANDOSHAN SNARLS / SNIFFS]
[ASHOKA PANTS]
Where is she?
This one was faster than most.
I have lost the scent.
[SNARLS]
She can't hide forever.
Mark my words, I'll have her
hide and nail it to the wall
for killing my son.
[SNARLS]
[FLYING CREATURES CHIRP]
You made it.
We feared the worst.
Where's Kalifa?
She didn't make it.
She's dead?
I... I can't believe it.
She had been here longer
than any of us and now...
We're all going to die here.
It's only a matter of time.
If it's only a matter of time that
we die I say we go down with a fight.
[SCOFFS]
That is suicide.
You've said that every few days they
they release new prisoners on the beach.
I say we attack that drop ship
head on. They'll never expect it.
[SIGHS]
Is it worth a shot?
Maybe it is.
Get ready, we'll have to be swift.
The drop point's not far.
Now!
What the..?
It's one of those blasted
jedi welps. Get her!
I'll take the pilot.
[TRANDOSHAN SNARLS]
[STRAINS]
[SNARLS]
[GROANS]
[ASHOKA STRUGGLES]
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLES]
[SHIP GROANS]
[SCREAMS]
Get out of there! Come on!
But the prisoners, they'll die!
Hit the release! Hurry!
-Well, I guess we won't
be escaping on that ship.
We'll find another way.
[GROAN / METALLIC CLATTER]
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLES]
What was that?
A survivor.
It could be one of the
prisoners they were dropping off.
What is that?
It's a Wookiee.
[GROWLS]
[TRANDOSHAN GROANS]
- It's the youngling's that
did this, they're getting bold.
What about survivors?
Both of our men were killed
and there was only oe prisoner.
A Wookiee.
And... he's missing.
So, now the younglings are organized,
bold, and they've got a Wookiee.
Your name is Chewbacca?
[GROWLS AFFIRMATIVE]
Chewbacca, does anyone
even knows you were taken?
[GROWLS NEGATIVE]
[SPEAKS IN SHYRIIWOOK]
No, but he says his
home world is very close.
That's great but it might as well be
Corruscant as far as i'm concerned.
We've got no ship.
[GROWLS]
[SPEAKS IN SHYRIIWOOK]
He thinks he can contact his home planet
if we find a wayto transmit a signal.
Right, and how would we do that?
Send smoke signals?
We don't exactly have a transmitter
lying around if you haven't noticed.
[SPEAKS IN SHYRIIWOOK]
Chewbacca says he can build a transmitter
from the wreckage on the beach.
[SPEAKS IN SHYRIIWOOK]
Well, we can't just sit here.
Fine. We'll do it the Wookiee way.
Chewbacca and I will go out
to inspect the crash site.
You two stay here and signal
us if you see anything.
Get back! It's a patrol.
[TRANDOSHAN]
Hopefully that patrol
won't be back for a while.
What are we looking for?
[GROWLS]
Are you still feeling optimistic about
making a transmitter out of this junk?
[GROWLS]
[TRANDOSHAN] Now, what do we have here?
[SIGHS] We better get going.
That patrol may come back.
Come on, pretties, one more step.
It looks clear, come on.
[GROWLS]
It's OK.
Time to join the Force, Jedi.
[SNARLS]
Sniper! Get down!
[GROWLS]
I'll gut you, whelp.
[GRIMACES]
Wait! We should take him prisoner.
Fine. Chewbacca, let's take him.
[FLYING CREATURES CHIRP]
[TREE CREATURE SNARLS]
[TREE CREATURE YELPS]
How's it looking, Chewbacca?
[SPEAKS IN SHYRIIWOOK]
Will it work?
[TRANSMITTER BLEEPS]
Well, something's working.
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLES]
We've got a prisoner.
We should be using him to our
advantage while we have a chance.
- I thought the prisoner
was the backup plan.
- It's clear enough that we
cannot relay on that device.
[GROWLS]
No offence.
- But we just can't sit here any longer.
- We should wait.
I... agree with Jinx.
We have to act while we have an advantage.
Let's say we do it your way.
What's the plan?
We can use the prisoner to trick the enemy
into flying one of their pods thoward to us.
Then we hijack the pod,
fly up to their base and
take them by surprise.
Ahsoka, you got us to
believe in ourselves again.
- And, well, I believe
Jinx's plan will work.
Look, do what you want,
but O-Mer and I are leaving
with the prisoner in the morning.
Their hearts are in the right place.
You know I can't let them go alone.
[GROWLS]
We're not going to be able
to do this without you.
We need your help.
[GRUNTS]
Who knows? Maybe our
luck'sjust abou to change.
[GROWLS]
Alright, we better get started.
Right, time to call your friends.
[SLITHERS]
I'm not helping you, whelp.
Chewbacca, we need him
at eye-level, please.
You will listen to me.
[CHUCKLES]
No, I won't.
You will listen to me.
[SLITHERS]
I will listen to you.
You are our captive,
and now you've escaped.
I was your captive, but now I've escaped.
[SLITHERS]
- You need to call a
speeder to pick you up.
- I need to call a
speeder to pick me up.
[SLITHERS]
[COMLINK BLEEPS]
"Smug, where have you been?"
I need a speeder to pick me up.
[SLITHERS]
Get in, let's go.
Now!
[CHEWBACCA ROARS]
Want a lift?
[TRANSMITTER BLEEPS]
[SIGNAL LOCKS]
[WOOKIEES SPEAK IN SHYRIIWOOK]
Krix and Smug should be back by now.
[CHEWBACCA GROWLS]
[SNARLS]
[SCREAMS]
[TRANDOSHAN SCREECHES WARNING SOUND]
Kill them! Kill them!
I want their skins!
Hey, let's give him a lift.
A valiant effort, little younglings.
Especially you, Togruta.
You will be a prize
trophy in my collection.
[GROWLS]
Make it quick, General,
we'll charging by the minute
and if my ship gets damaged,
it will cost you extra.
[GRUNTS]
[ROARS]
Can you get me up there?
[MOANS]
Lo-Taren!
What?
You're beaten.
You murdered my son!
And you need to pay for what you did!
Your son died because of
your own actions. Not mine.
Don't!
[SCREAMS]
[THUD]
[WOOKIEES GROAN]
Ashoka!
- It is good to see
you safe, little Ahsoka.
Ashoka, I am so sorry.
For what?
For letting you go, for
letting you get taken.
It was my fault.
No master. It wasn't your fault.
I should have paid more attention,
I dhould have tried harder, I...
You already did everything you could.
Every thing you had to do.
When I was out there, alone,
all I had was your training
and the lessons you thaught me.
And because of you, I did survive.
And not only that, I was able to
lead others to survive as well.
I don't know what to say.
I do.
Thank you, Master.
You're welcome, my Padawan.