Sync by mczolly
www.addic7ed.com
Corrected by Kerensky
www.Addic7ed.com
Evil is not born, it is taught.
Open for revenge.
Betrayed and left for dead by Count Dooku.
Asajj Ventress has begun
a deadly game with his former master.
Launching a secret assasination
attempt againts him
with the help of her kind,
the misterious Nightsisters.
Deceive in beliving the jedi
are behind the recent attack.
Dooku has travel across
the galaxy to enlist the Nightsisters.
In his quest for vengeance.
Mother Talzin.
Count Dooku, come.
We have much to discuss.
[Engines humming]
Thank you for receiving me, sister.
I believe the old alliance can
again be what it once was.
You would only have to pledge
your clan's allegiance to the
separatists' cause.
We could certainly use the
powers of the Nightsisters
against the jedi.
Such a generous offer, count.
But our loyalty is reserved
for only each other.
The only reason I am aiding
in your search for a new
assassin is because long
ago, you chose to help me.
After this matter is resolved,
I hope our paths never
cross again.
As you wish, sister.
[Eerie humming]
Drink.
You must gather your strength
after such a long journey.
Thank you.
Blackroot, to replenish the body.
You have heard of the sith warrior
darth maul, have you not?
Yes, he was slain on Naboo at
the hand of Obi-Wan Kenobi.
A few still remain in his bloodline.
The men dwell on the
far side of Dathomir.
What if I could provide
another of his kind?
A warrior of the same caliber?
Yes, but I warn you.
Men are easy to acquire,
hard to control.
With my last assassin,
Asajj Ventress, dead
and the jedi's attacks
against me increasing.
Procuring a new
personal assassin is essential.
Very well.
It shall be done, my Lord.
[Engine humming]
So he has agreed to take
another apprentice...
A barbarian, no less.
A man we deliver to the count
with all of the training and skill
an assassin can possess.
This warrior must have
no loyalty to Dooku.
He will be our pawn.
Yes, yes.
We will use our magicks to
manipulate his assassin,
and when the time is right...
Dooku will pay for his
betrayal with his life.
You will go to the far side
of Dathomir and find the men.
You will select the most
suitable candidate, one with
your strength and skill, one
we can use to our advantage.
Yes, mother.
[Speeder rattling]
[Bell dinging]
[Grunting]
[Engine humming]
Ah, welcome, sister.
I have come for the selection.
Yes, yes, of course.
Line up, heads of each tribe!
Line up for the sister!
Feral, try not to draw
attention to yourself.
That won't be a problem
for me, Savage.
What a fine-looking specimen.
But looks aren't everything.
[Choking]
[Groans]
Too small.
[Grunts]
Too weak.
These will do.
Him.
And him.
These men are to your liking, sister?
Yes.
Now for the tests.
There will be three of them.
Whoever survives will be my
champion and go on to serve me.
Understood?
All: Yes, sister!
Excellent!
Let the games begin!
[Wind whistling]
[Breathing heavily]
We must be vigilant, feral.
Aren't I always?
[Both yelling]
[Both grunting]
[Groans]
[Grunts]
[Whooshing]
[Screaming]
[Grunting]
[Blades whirring]
[Both grunting]
[Gasps]
Feral!
[Grunts]
Brother, get up.
The witch.
Where is she?
Pathetic.
[Grunts]
Where are the warriors I came for?
Is this is all the power
these men possess?
In order to fight against the
force, you must see what cannot
be seen.
Only four of you remain.
Who will be the first to fall?
[Laughing]
[Laughing maniacally]
[Gasps]
Not fast enough.
[Laughing]
[High-pitched whirring]
[Blades scraping]
Show yourself.
Good.
Let the third and final
challenge begin.
There are only two of us
left, brother, but only one
will survive.
No, not if I can help it.
[Rumbling]
Stick together.
We must work as a team.
[Rumbling]
Go!
[Grunts]
Savage!
[Grunting]
[Grunts]
As long as I live, you
will not harm him.
Please, spare him.
Take me.
Leave us.
[Both grunting]
[Loud crash]
[Yells]
My life is yours.
Yes, it is.
[Engine roars]
[Speeder rattling]
He has surrendered his life to me.
[Eerie humming]
This one is strong...
A perfect male specimen.
Oh, such hate, the sheer power of it.
A tremendous gift from
the galaxy, mother.
He will serve us well.
[Eerie humming]
All: Geiss kan erde mak harden
ob Stein, geiss kan lewf mak
krig ob blitz, geiss kan
pire mak blud loge raga,
geiss kan vass byn skol zum Asajj!
Erde-blitz-raga-byn,
erde-blitz-raga-byn,
erde-blitz-raga-byn, zum Asajj!
[Whooshing]
[Bones crackling]
He is ready, sisters.
Look at the strength
in him, the power!
[Groaning]
Let me go!
Calmly, sister.
Let me go.
[Grunting and gasping]
That's better.
Bring in the prisoner.
Now for the final test.
Savage?
Kill him.
Savage, you know me.
I am your kin.
Do not do this.
Whack!
I said kill him.
No!
Brother! Brother, please!
You beg?
Weakling!
Savage!
[Bones crunch]
Good.
You will learn to draw your
strength from your emotions.
Hate will feed you.
Never sympathize with the
enemy, not even for a moment.
Yes, sister.
[Whooshing]
For you, an enchanted
blade, blessed with our
most potent magicks.
I think it's time we introduce the
apprentice to his new master.
Wouldn't you agree?
[Engine whooshing]
At last.
Sister.
Count Dooku.
May I present Savage Opress.
[Thumping footsteps]
[Rock crumbles]
He certainly is a sight to behold.
The fiercest of his kind, my Lord.
He shall serve you well.
Yes, he shall.
Mother Talzin speaks very
highly of your skills.
Still, I require proof of
your abilities as a warrior.
The jedi are in control
of a vital outpost on the
jungle planet of Devaron, a temple.
A temple?
Do not be fooled, Savage.
The temple of eedit serves
only as a front for the mility
operations of the Republic.
It is essential that we seize
the temple if the separatists
ever hope to take control of
that corner of the galaxy.
You shall go to Devaron and
take what is rightfully ours.
Yes, my Lord.
[Engine humming]
[Blasters firing]
[Metal clanging]
Get him!
[Lightsabers humming]
Jedi.
Master?
Stay back!
[Lightsabers humming]
[Grunting]
No!
My Lord.
Is it finished?
Yes.
The temple has been taken.
And the jedi?
Dead.
Very impressive, Savage.
Return to Serenno immediately.
Very well, my Lord.
You have done well, Savage.
I'll have much use for you.
Thank you, my Lord.
I foresee we will do
great things together.
I shall teach you the
ways of the dark side.
Soon your powers will rival
that of the great sith Lord
Darth Maul.
We will be even more
powerful than Lord Sidious.
We shall rule the galaxy
together, my apprentice.
I am your servant, Master.