A world in crisis!
The peaceful planet of Mandalore
is being strangled by
the grip of corruption.
With shortages of every kind,
citizens must turn to the black
market in order to survive.
Desperate to free her people,
Duchess Satine has asked
her friend Padmé Amidala,
to speak with the Jedi council,
in hopes that they will send assistance
to her struggling world.
The Jedi council gives
you a mission Ahsoka.
It's your duty to see it through.
Don't you think I’m just
a little over qualified for this ?
According to Senator Amidala,
Mandalore
is a deeply corrupt world.
If the cycle is to be broken,
the future leaders at the royal
academy of government must learn,
the evils of corruption.
Yoda feels that only a young padawan
like you can get through to them.
My lady, if I may,
what do the jedi know of our ways?
Do we really want them meddling
with our children's education?
Surely there is nothing to fear from
exposing them to new ideas.
Duchess Satine.
Prime minister Almec.
Master Skywalker,
so good to see you again.
This is your padawan, I assume.
Yes, my lady.
May I present Ahsoka Tano?
Duchess.
Prime minister.
I am grateful that the Jedi council
could spare the two of you to help,
instruct our leaders
and peacekeepers of tomorrow.
Please thank master Yoda for me.
I'm afraid that due to our
limited resources,
I must return to battle immediately.
So you will not be staying,
Master Skywalker?
No,
but I assure you, padawan
Tano is a highly capable jedi,
and has the full
confidence of the council.
Very well.
Cadet Korkie, Amis, Lagos.
These are some of the cadets that you
will be instructing, Padawan Tano.
Nice to met all of you.
That's a fine weapon.
May I see it?
No offworlders may carry
weapons on Mandalore.
Master Obi-Wan caused trouble?
That's a first.
Just give me the lightsaber.
Thank you for respecting our ways,
master jedi.
Excuse the interruption,
sir, but it is time to depart.
- General Fisto is expecting us.
- If you'll excuse me.
Corruption is what happens
when someone in power,
puts their own personal gain before the
interest of the people they represent.
- So it's a result of greed?
- Yes.
A leader sacrifices moral integrity
for the sake of money or power.
Entire star systems have
collapsed into chaos,
or revolution because their greedy
politicians got caught up in a cycle,
of bribery and blackmail
while their people suffered.
Does that mean most
government officials are corrupt?
Well... No,
but the point is that temptation
is always there,
and citizens must be vigilant
so corruption can't take root.
The deadliest enemies of a society,
well within its borders.
and from these internal threats,
the people need to be protected.
But if you don't trust your
leaders, isn't that treason?
It's every citizen's duty to
challenge their leaders,
to keep Them honest, and hold
them accountable if they're not.
How do you do that?
By exposing corrupt officials
for what they are.
Lasting change can only
come from within.
Be sure your assignments
are prepared for tomorrow.
The school's out of rations again.
I guess there'll be no
late-night snacks tonight.
Listen, we've had a food shortage
since the war began.
Transport ships keep coming in,
but there's strict rationing.
Something is wrong on Mandalore.
But these problems are bigger than us.
Just let the authorities handle it.
We have to do something
about it, like Ahsoka said.
Let's go down to the
warehouse district
and see if there really is
a food shortage.
Beats sitting around here
listening to my stomach growl.
These doors are heavily
secured by the government.
It won't be secure for long.
Looks like the academy taught us well.
Come on. Up and over.
I have a bad feeling about this.
- What are you doing?
- Quiet.
It sounds like someone
else is in here.
Let's get out of here.
No, come on.
The risk involved makes the price up.
You must be more cautious.
Coming here could raise suspicion.
It's a little late for a
meeting, isn't it?
Let's get a closer look.
Are you crazy?
It wasn't my idea.
Soniee, quick, use your holocam.
Those look like mandalorian police,
but they're unmarked.
Who's that?
Who are those guys?
What are offworlders doing
on a secure port?
I don't like this.
I'm getting out of here.
Hurry. This way.
Hey, no!
What are we going to do?
This is bigger than we thought.
We're going to need help.
We should speak to my aunt Satine.
Aunt Satine, may we speak with you?
Of course, Korkie.
Come in.
We did some investigating.
There's no food shortage.
We found stores of food at
the government port.
How would you know this?
That doesn't matter right now.
I beg to differ.
We made a recording
of a secret meeting
between what we know was a government
official and a black marketeer.
That's why everything costs so much,
and so many people are starving.
We need your help to find
the one responsible.
This is a serious matter, I agree,
but the source of this evil may be
more than you cadets can handle.
People can be very deceiving.
You don't want to get
yourselves into trouble.
But, auntie, don't you see?
You can't ignore this.
I won't. Trust me.
But for your own safety,
you must let me take care of it.
Now run along, all of you.
Concentrate on your studies.
There will be a time to save the
world when you're a bit older.
She refused to help us because
she doesn't think we can handle it.
She just thinks we're
a bunch of stupid kids.
She acted like nothing was wrong.
We need to find someone
else who believes us.
Like who?
Mandalore has two people in charge.
Since my aunt won't help,
We'll have to go to the prime minister.
What makes you think he'll listen?
I've known him my whole life.
He's always told me to me
to him if I'm ever in trouble,
And I'd say we're all in big trouble.
I must concern by this allegations,
my intrepid young cadets.
You think duchess Satine knows
who the conspirator is?
She said she was going to handle it.
Meet me in the Palace Plaza tonight.
Bring the recording you took
of the black market deal and all
the cadets who know about it.
You seem distracted today.
What's going on?
We did what you said.
- We found evidence of corruption.
- What do you mean?
Well, we were hungry,
so we decided to go look for food.
Food?
Down at the government warehouse.
Someone just let you in
to inspect the warehouse?
- No, we broke in.
- Oh, great!
So you committed a crime.
It sounds bad, I know, but then we
saw a meeting and offworlders...
And they chased us.
Maybe they chased you
because you broke
into a government warehouse.
No, it was a black market Deal.
I know it.
My aunt Satine told us to stay out
of it, but we must do something.
Do you have proof?
We made a holo-recording.
The prime minister is
meeting us tonight to...
Are you sure that's a good idea?
I thought you said it was
the duty of every citizen
to expose corrupt officials.
I'm only saying that you
should take this slowly.
Examine all of the facts,
and all of the people
involved before you act.
You sound more like my
aunt than a jedi knight.
You Korkie?
Prime minister, is that you?
Secret service.
You're all under arrest for treason,
corruption, and conspiracy.
You will come with us.
These are the same guards
we saw last night.
We've done nothing wrong.
Looks like the prime
minister set you up.
That's treason.
He's the leader of our system.
He couldn't possibly be a traitor.
We need proof.
We have the recording.
That's no good.
You can't see who it is.
Wait. Stop right there.
Information retrieval.
I need you to I.D. a hologram.
- That's him!
- You're right.
That is the prime minister.
We have to take this to
my aunt and warn her.
They know I talked to her.
We're too late.
He's dead.
Korkie, wait.
The intruders may still be inside.
They took her.
This is all my fault.
Who knows what they've done to her.
Now what?
How are we supposed to find her?
Who can we trust?
I need all of you to calm
down and focus.
We know the prime
minister is behind this.
After my aunt, he's the most
powerful person on Mandalore.
So let's go talk to him.
Master jedi, this is
an unexpected pleasure.
What can I do for you?
Actually, prime minister,
It's what I can do for you.
I believe some of my students are
involved in a conspiracy against you.
Intriguing.
You can't do this!
We trusted you, master Tano.
Thank you for bringing the
traitors to justice, master jedi.
They mentioned that duchess
Satine was their leader.
We should arrest her too.
Do not worry.
We already have her in custody.
Really? Where?
That is none of your concern.
Now, I must prepare a public statement
about the duchess and her crimes.
Officer, I need to interrogate the
prisoners Immediately.
Careful.
We're being watched.
Did he buy it?
Have you found my aunt?
Not exactly,
but I know they have her in custody.
- Where?
- The prime minister wouldn't tell me.
I knew this plan wouldn't work.
Have a little faith.
I'll find her.
We'll just modify the plan a bit.
How are you going to do that?
Don't worry. You'll know when
to act when I give the signal.
What's the signal?
You'll know it when you see it.
You will take me to duchess Satine.
I will take you to duchess Satine.
What are you doing?
I must interrogate the duchess.
You must interrogate the duchess.
I'm getting you out of here.
Ahsoka, it's a trap.
I see you found the duchess,
youngling.
You may stop your
playacting now, sergeant.
Prime minister, sir!
Using a jedi mind trick was a
very poor decision.
My guards have been trained to
resist such archaic magic.
And now you have revealed
yourself as a conspirator.
Set for stun.
You little fool.
Where is she?
Stick to Ahsoka's plan.
But how do we do that?
It's falling apart.
Ahsoka wants us to wait for a signal,
and that's what we're going to do.
Sigit. Sign the confession and
admit to your treasonous ways.
There is only one traitor to
Mandalore here, prime minister,
and that's you.
You control the black market.
You have betrayed the public trust,
and used your office to
accumulate wealth and power.
It's shameful.
Your idealism is inspiring,
my dear, but hopelessly naive.
I established the black market
for the people.
That's absurd.
The war is disrupting trade across the galaxy.
The profits from the black
market are being used to,
purchase humanitarian
supplies for Mandalore.
Think of it as a new tax in the
interest of national security.
It's a tax for your benefit,
Prime minister.
Where are these humanitarian
supplies you speak of?
Sergeant, put the shock
collar on her.
My patience has worn thin, duchess.
Maybe this will convince you.
I would rather die than sign
your confession.
That can be arranged.
You're wasting your time.
Bring me those traitorous Cadets.
No, you can't.
They're just children.
All right, let's move.
I'm afraid your nephew will
have to suffer needlessly.
Put the shock collar on cadet Korkie.
Go!
Got ya.
Stop fighting.
Send for my personal guards.
You must know by now that
I didn't bring you here just to teach.
I knew something was amiss,
but I had no one to trust.
I thought if I brought a jedi,
Especially a friend
of senator Amidala's,
we could solve this mystery together.
I never doubted you, duchess.
Neither did we.
It was an honor to serve with a jedi knight.
It was my privilege to be your teacher.
I hope this assignment wasn't
too boring for you.
Ah, it had its moments.
Like the one where you convinced
untrained children to help you
you overthrow a corrupt Government?
That was a highlight.
It sounds pretty risky.
- You're lucky you didn't get hurt.
- Nothing you wouldn't have done.