Stolen secrets!
Villainous mercenary Cad Bane
was hired by Darth Sidious
to steal a holocron
from the vaults of the Jedi Temple.
After fleeing the scene of the crime,
Bane hunted down
and captured Master Bolla Ropal,
who has a crystal which holds secrets
of the Jedi Order.
As a Separatist fleet arrives
to help the bounty hunter,
Anakin Skywalker races in
to cut off their escape
and stop Bane
from delivering the stolen holocron.
- l guess we're going down with the ship.
- Roger, roger.
General, we're receiving
an urgent transmission from the planet.
General Skywalker,
our base has been overrun!
There's no possibility of evacuation!
They've taken General Ropal
and the holocron memory crystal.
Do you know where they've taken them?
Sorry, sir. We tried to stop them,
but they left the outpost.
Wait a second.
There's too much interference.
Transmitter's been destroyed
at the source, sir.
We have to find out
what ship Master Ropal is on.
You will remain conscious, Master Jedi.
The bounty hunter
has some questions for you.
Attach mind limiters, pain pulsers
and give him a full dose of X-C33.
Sir, that Republic ship has destroyed
our escort and is blocking our escape.
Whoever's commanding that cruiser
is a bold one.
Move us out of the battle zone
and prepare to jump to hyperspace.
l have a small favor to ask our Jedi guest.
General, a Separatist command ship
is fleeing the battle.
You think they have Master Ropal
on board as a prisoner?
l'm sure of it.
Admiral, intercept them
before they can jump to hyperspace.
- l'll ready the troops for boarding.
- Boarding? We have no boarding craft.
We were prepared to land on the planet,
not aboard another ship.
- You can't be serious.
- l am, Admiral. Thank you for your opinion.
Now, target their hyperdrive.
We don't want them getting away.
Sir! Captain!
Sir, they hit the power converters
so we can't go into hyperspace.
Hmm. l wonder what the Jedi are planning.
l've rounded up three brigades, sir.
Where are we going?
We're going to board a Separatist frigate,
rescue Master Ropal
and recover an archive holocron.
We have no assault craft, sir.
Only a couple of fighters and The Twilight.
Waiting for orders, sir.
And the plan is?
Just curious.
l came down to see if l could be
of any help, General Skywalker.
Actually, you can.
Activate those walkers, Admiral.
You are not thinking of using those
to transport the clones to that frigate.
- Well, they are pressurized.
- And they're equipped with magnetic feet.
- Hmm. Good call.
- Master, you're a genius.
Those walkers are designed for terrain,
not space.
Rex, load them up. Let's go, Snips.
Execute Battalion, take AT-AT 300!
Carnivore Battalion, Walker 773! Let's go!
Simply open this little box of yours,
so l can get the information
from this crystal,
and your suffering will come to an end.
You will never get me
to unlock the holocron.
Unfortunately, l don't have time
to discuss this with you.
Hit him again, full power.
l'm not sure
how much more of this he can take.
- Are you a medical droid?
- No, sir.
- Then step back and shut up.
- Roger, roger.
More power.
- We've lost all his vital signs.
- Check.
- He is no longer functioning.
- Drop him.
He's dead.
Looks like we will have to find
another Jedi to open this holocron.
Only next time,
l will try a different method.
When Darth Sidious asked me
to loan you the Federation fleet,
he didn't say you were going to war!
Bane, you have already lost
four of my ships.
l hope you can pay for all of this.
One authentic Jedi holocron
and the memory crystal l was after.
When my benefactor gets this,
he will compensate you
for your puny fleet.
Sounds like the Jedi want it back.
The Jedi are overwhelming
our vulture droids.
- Should we send out reinforcements?
- No.
- What are you doing?
- Did you say, "No"?
- Mmm-hmm.
- Roger, roger.
The Jedi will board the ship
and get the holocron back!
Transmit the information
and close the deal immediately!
l can't. Only a Jedi can access the device.
Fortunately, there are two Jedi
on their way to help me.
One more than we need for our purposes.
You'd better live through this.
l want my money, Bane.
You can count on it.
Artoo!
Wipe all the frigate's memory banks
and destroy every record of our mission.
lnitiate the self-destruct sequence.
You, transfer all ship functions
to my wrist com.
l want control of doors,
gravity generators, everything.
Roger, roger.
The rest of you,
stay here and defend the bridge.
We're defending the bridge alone?
Against the Jedi?
l hate this job.
Don't shoot! l'm not the commander.
He's the commander!
Guess l'm the commander now.
Artoo, see if you can find Master Ropal.
One authentic Jedi holocron
and the memory crystal l was after.
Oh, no. He has both pieces now.
Rex, send a squad,
lock down the hangar bay
and destroy all the escape pods.
No one gets off this ship!
Yes, sir.
Artoo, you have to find Master Ropal.
Hurry!
What was that?
General Skywalker, one of the engines
on that frigate has exploded.
l caution you to avoid the aft section.
- How much damage is there?
- l suggest immediate evacuation.
Not until we get what we came for.
Spread out. While you take on the clones,
l will separate the Jedi
and lead one of them away.
Master, l found him!
Rex, have some men
take Master Ropal back to the Resolute.
We might not be able to find
the holocron in time, Master.
But if it's destroyed with the ship,
Nute Gunray won't get it either.
Maybe, but l'd rather
return it to the library personally.
Come on, Artoo.
Artoo says we're close. Stay sharp.
Ow!
Switch to night vision.
There!
Welcome, Jedi. We've been expecting you.
Kill them!
Let's make this a bit more interesting.
Lockdown!
Magnetics! You were trained for this!
Artoo, turn the gravity generators
back on!
Check your fire! Hit one of those shells
and this fight is over for all of us!
l'll get him, Master!
Ahsoka, wait! lt's a trap!
Ahsoka, wait! We'll take him together!
Whoops!
You thought you could get away?
You're not much of a challenge, youngling.
l got you right where l want you.
Ow!
l'm not impressed.
General Skywalker, can you hear me?
Are you all right in there?
Yeah, l'm all right. Get back to the hangar.
Find a transport,
but wait for us as long as you can.
We're on it, sir.
Ahsoka, do you copy?
There's a power surge
heading toward the bridge.
lf you're there, get out immediately.
You must abandon your mission.
l don't have the holocron memory
and l seem to have misplaced
my Padawan.
The ship is tearing itself apart!
Move off to a safe distance, Admiral,
and await my signal for evacuation.
Of all the Jedi,
why did l have to end up with Skywalker?
Oh, l wouldn't do that.
Those binders have been
specially designed for Jedi.
The more you struggle,
the tighter they get.
- lmpressed now, youngling?
- Not really.
Enjoy this while you can, sleemo.
This burning boat
is about to finish us both off.
We have time.
The bond between a Jedi teacher
and his apprentice is strong.
Which means my Master
will be coming for me any minute.
Let's see if we can get him here any faster.
You said we'd be safe back here.
Come on,
there's three of us and only one of him.
lt won't matter.
Sir, a Jedi is coming.
He looks very unhappy.
Your Master has gotten the message.
You have nowhere left to run,
bounty hunter.
Let me worry about that, Jedi.
lf l activate this control,
the outside airlock will open
and she will be sucked into oblivion.
Do you think you can kill me
and then save her
before she's pulled out into space?
lt's a horrible way to die.
Besides, isn't negotiation the Jedi way?
What do you want?
This holocron carries information
l've been paid to collect.
l can't unlock it, but you can.
The last Jedi who had it wouldn't open it.
l hope you don't make the same mistake.
We don't have much time.
Hurry it up, Jedi, or she dies!
- No, Master! Don't do it!
- l can't let you die, Ahsoka.
Master, no!
- We'll deal with the holocron later.
- How touching.
All units make for that shuttle!
Captain, the main reactor is exposed.
lt will implode at any moment.
Yes, sir. We're trying to make our way
to the shuttle now.
- Get out of there!
- Sir! Yes, sir.
You two find the General and help him!
This frigate's not going to last.
We have to get out of here!
Yes, sir!
Come about. We need to put some
distance between us and that frigate.
Now l will combine this holocron
with the memory crystal
l acquired from your dead Jedi friend.
My employers will be most pleased.
- Bane, did the Jedi cooperate with you?
- With some encouragement.
l have access to the holocron
and all the information
the memory contains.
l only have to get off this ship.
Maybe you should transmit it to me now.
Then l can send another ship for you.
No thanks, Viceroy.
l have a plan for my own escape.
Hold it right there!
You're not going anywhere, bounty hunter.
Rex, l hope you found us
a ride off this bucket!
We've got to leave now.
The reactor's gonna blow. We cannot wait!
You'll have to.
l'm going after that bounty hunter.
Master, wait! Stop!
This is the way to the hangar!
We must get off the ship now!
- l can't let Bane get away.
- Patience, Master.
Patience.
You're right.
Come on, come on!
- Trooper, did you get the holocron?
- No, sir.
- l'll get it, Master.
- No time. Rex, get us out of here.
Well, it looks like
the holocron was destroyed,
but at least the Separatists didn't get it.
Bane's dead, but l can still feel him.
Master, l'm sorry
l let that mercenary get the upper hand.
lt wasn't your fault, Ahsoka.
lt was mine, start to finish.
So, did you manage
to recover the holocron
or capture the bounty hunter?
Um, no and no.
l see.
So the mission was
your usual version of success, then?
lf by success you mean, "l won," then yes.