Calm before the storm!
A rare and welcome respite
from endless battle
awaits Jedi Knights Anakin Skywalker
and Mace Windu
as they travel through deep space
aboard the Jedi Cruiser Endurance.
Preparing to rendezvous
with a Republic frigate,
the Jedi remain unaware of a deadly peril
lying hidden in their midst.
War does not come with a guarantee.
No soldier gets the promise of safety,
survival, or victory.
But men, l guarantee you this:
Every member of this Clone Youth Brigade
will have his moment.
And it is that moment
when you are no longer a cadet,
you are a soldier.
There's the Jedi Cruiser.
You have the best training in the galaxy,
but no one can train you for the moment
you look death in the eyes.
What you do then,
and the soldier you become,
that is up to you.
Docking procedures begin shortly.
Until then,
dismissed!
- Who's the new guy with the long hair?
- Some last-minute replacement.
Looks green to me.
- Hey. What outfit you from?
-322nd.
- l heard they had their tour.
- They did.
l... l couldn't make it.
Broken arm.
A real trooper could lose an arm,
and still report for duty.
So what are you, soft?
- What's going on here, gentlemen?
- Just having a little fun.
Oh, l've seen your kind of fun, Hotshot.
Stand down.
Come on, Whip.
Air's getting stale around here.
- Hey. What's your name?
- l'm Lucky.
- Jax.
- Thanks, but l can handle myself.
Yeah, sure, but a trooper's only as strong
as the trooper beside him.
- We're all in it together, right?
- Right.
And with the training we got,
l feel ready for anything.
Oh!
Man!
Don't be nervous. Only thing
between us and them is experience.
lt's not like they're Jedi.
Morning, troops.
Welcome aboard
the Jedi Cruiser Endurance.
- l am Mace Windu. And this is...
- Anakin Skywalker. Welcome aboard.
Today, you'll see how a real,
working Jedi Cruiser operates.
And you'll have the chance to serve
right alongside two Jedi Knights.
- Serious? No way!
- That's gonna be awesome!
Jedi? Yeah!
Can you believe it?
Generals, new orders from General Kenobi
await you in the War Room. lmmediately.
Another time, then.
Wow!
The other guy's
Anakin Skywalker.
No way!
l heard he's the strongest Jedi.
This is going to be the best!
You seem more disappointed
than our cadets.
- lt's ourjob to instruct and inspire.
- You just wanted to show off.
Hey, when l show off,
it is instructive, and inspiring.
For you, maybe.
Looks easy, doesn't it?
Well, looks can be deceiving.
There's nothing more dangerous
in all of space than a moving target.
- What do you use for targets, sir?
- Malfunctioning droids.
Mechanical skeet, packed with explosives.
Now, this is my ship, and my rules.
l do not allow tourists on board.
Only soldiers.
Now, time for target practice.
You, there. Take the gun.
- Not even close. Next!
- But l only...
Oh, no, you're done.
You only get one chance.
l promise you,
the Separatists don't give more. Next!
Near-miss is still a miss, kid.
The Sergeant's right.
Training is no match for experience.
And it's the one thing none of you have.
l know that look.
Whoo-hoo!
Yeah!
l see why they call you "Lucky."
But let's see how you are when Seppies
come at you in tri-attack formation.
- Yeah!
- All right, all right, cut the chatter, men.
We're due on observation deck 13.
Fall out!
Now that's a cadet to watch.
Cadet 1151, tell me where this
Jedi Cruiser's main stabilizers are located.
Sir, hull 17, behind the main reactors, sir.
Good. Cadet 1174,
how many engines fail
before auxiliary power kicks in?
Sir, three on port and starboard sides, sir!
Channel 7 open,
ready to receive Code 5 transmission.
- Boba, is that you?
- lt is.
l'm sending you the data now.
Received transmission. Boba out.
- Hey, what are you doing here?
- Uh, communiqué, sir, eyes only.
l've been dispatched
to General Windu's quarters.
- There's no problem, sir.
- Oh, there's a problem. You're lying.
Admit it. You're lost.
Come on, cut the kid a break.
Windu's quarters are that way, shiny.
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
- Eyes on where you're headed, cadet.
- Yes, sir. Sorry, sir.
Cadet 327, what reaction propels
the main engines of this Jedi Cruiser?
Pulse combines sparking off
the reactor core rods, sir.
Hmm. Excellent.
Sir. General Skywalker
requests your presence on the bridge.
l'll be there shortly.
The General requests
your presence immediately, sir.
No rest for the weary.
Put these inside my quarters, would you?
Yes, sir.
Are you all right? Trooper! Trooper!
This doesn't look like a drill.
No time for chatter.
There's been an explosion.
Let's show these troops how the Clone
Youth Brigade rises to the challenge.
Line up! Two by! l don't want any heroes.
Ourjob's to get to the nearest safe room
and let these troops do theirjob.
Now, move!
- Think it's a Seppie attack?
- Out here? Perfect place for it.
You heard the Sergeant!
Secure the loose talk!
- Status report, trooper.
- Ship's undamaged, one man down.
General Windu's quarters got hit
but he survived.
Survived?
- You're lucky to be alive. And our trooper?
- Dead.
- This was no accident.
- Agreed.
Keep moving!
Ship's navigation is nearby.
Admiral, has the navigation
been damaged?
Hobbled, not destroyed.
Systems are repairable.
l've ordered shutdown of all engines
until we're fully operational.
We'll hold orbit over Vanqor.
- Any sign of attack ships?
- None, but we'll keep scanning.
Until we get navigation back,
the Endurance is a fat and easy target.
l won't have it. Kilian out.
lf navigation wasn't the target,
then hitting your quarters was intentional.
Watcher, this is Boba. lt's a miss.
Repeat, miss. What should l do?
Head to the reactor. Blow the core.
But the crew!
lt isn't about them, just Mace.
lfyou want Windu dead,
do as l say!
We have a killer on board this ship
and we are locked in dead space.
Just like our assassin.
We'll form an unbroken line of troopers
and scour the ship from bow to stern,
checking every corridor,
bulkhead and storage unit.
l want him alive.
Hey, you there! Come here!
l got lost, sir.
- Ship's on full lockdown, son.
- Yes, sir, l know, sir. l just...
- l'll return to my company.
- Not alone, you won't.
Emergency protocol's in effect.
Look, l'm calling a trooper
to escort you out of here.
This is CT-1477, l need an escort
for a cadet back to his group.
- ls that a DC-15A?
- Yeah. Here. Keep the safety on.
Copy that, CT-1477.
We're pretty overloaded
with the emergency status,
we'll get someone there
as soon as possible.
What?
What are you doing?
We're brothers! Don't shoot!
- You're not my brother.
- Don't shoot!
Don't worry...
CT-1477, report in.
CT-1477,
why have you broken off transmission?
Our sweep has now covered
over half the ship, Admiral.
Still no sign of the assassin.
The more ground we cover,
the less there is in which to hide.
Huh. More action
than you signed on for, eh, boys?
- We're headed for the safe room now, sir.
- Fine, fine.
Although, on second thought,
let's make a drill of it.
Head for the pods.
Escape pods? Things must be bad.
- The escape pods, sir?
- Mmm. l want to see what they're made of.
l'll even time you.
lt'll all make a fine story
when you return to your base.
- This can't be happening.
- Get a hold of yourself.
Prepare to launch the distress beacon.
We're going down.
Get your men out of here!
There's nothing more you can do.
Artoo, prep the fighters,
be ready to take off.
- Lucky! Stay with the group!
- Yes, sir.
- How are we gonna get through this?
- Groups of four, men. Groups of four.
Take pods one and two.
Set rendezvous coordinates
with the other pods,
at a safe distance from the cruiser.
See you at rendezvous mark six.
This is the moment, men. Make it yours.
The pod's malfunctioned!
The main reactor's beyond hope.
You have to abandon ship.
No. You must abandon ship. l'm staying.
- We missed the rendezvous!
- l can't stop it!
l'm staying with the Admiral.
You better evacuate.
Admiral, you must abandon ship.
- Not a chance.
- But, sir, with respect, that's an order.
lt may be your command, General,
but it's my ship.
We don't have time
for that kind of sentiment!
lt's not sentiment!
An Admiral must go down with his ship.
l don't expect you to understand it, Jedi.
We're lost.
What happened? Do we still have control?
Navigation's shot. Looks like
our pod was damaged in the escape.
- Can we steer?
- No.
- How about fuel?
- No feed. We're dead weight.
- So what do we do?
- Ourjobs.
Get ready to attach the hyperspace rings.
Admiral, what's your status?
We're caught
in Vanqor's gravitational pull.
We're going to try to set her down
on the surface.
All right. Once you're down, we'll get
the rescue teams to your location.
General Skywalker,
this is Sergeant Crasher.
Yes, Sergeant.
lt's the cadets, sir.
l can't raise them on any channel,
and their locator beacon's not active.
Theirs is the only pod unaccounted for.
Sounds like our saboteur
may have gotten to the cadets.
We have to find that pod.
- What was that?
- l don't know. A ship, l think.
- Rescue ship?
- lt's too early.
What, then?
Well, what do we have here?
You boys look lost.
Congratulations, Boba. Job well done.
- His name's not Boba. He's Lucky.
- "Lucky"?
That's a good one.
You're with her?
l wasn't expecting you
to bring friends along.
l couldn't help it, Aurra.
What are you going to do with them?
- What do you think?
- Let them go?
They're living witnesses, honey.
That was never part of the plan!
l just wanted to kill the Jedi
that murdered my father.
Well, that will have to wait.
Grow up! You'll get your revenge in time.
Now get on board.
We have to get out of here.
Or, you can go with your friends,
who l'm going to jettison into the unknown.
That would be poetic.
l'm sorry.
Traitor.
Do it!
You'll regret this!
l can't believe it.
A traitor? He was a traitor?
Yes, well,
we can't worry about that right now.
We have to find a way
to contact somebody.
We already tried! This pod is dead!
- We only have minimal life support.
- Yeah?
Well, whose fault is that? None of us!
That guy you defended left us for dead!
Stow it, Whiplash!
We need to work together.
You're not in charge here!
They have come back to finish us off!
No, wait! lt's the Jedi!
l found your missing cadets, Crasher.
Nice work, General.
How are they?
l can't raise them on the comm channel.
Their pod must have been damaged
in the evacuation.
Head to point 038
and you can pick them up.
Right away, sir.
Skywalker, have you heard
from Admiral Kilian?
No, l lost contact
when they entered the atmosphere.
- Jax, l'm sorry. l lost my head. l didn't...
- lt's okay, l understand.
l can't believe it was one of us,
someone just like us.
- He's nothing like us!
- Let's hope he is. lf he is like us,
he'll realize he's wrong.