Victory on Geonosis!
After a massive assault, the Republic has
finally recaptured the Separatist planet
and shut down its droid factories of doom.
An investigation by Luminara Unduli led to
the discovery of Queen Karina the Great,
whose hive mind
could reanimate dead Geonosian soldiers.
During the destruction
of the Queen's temple,
the Jedi apprehended
her advisor, Poggle the Lesser,
and now prepare to deliver the villain
to Coruscant for trial.
- l'm afraid we have a complication.
- Don't we always?
l've just received a distress signal
from our forces on Dantooine.
Master Windu's defenses held,
but at a great cost to his men.
They need medical supplies immediately.
We can obtain these supplies at
the medical station near Ord Cestus.
We're delivering Poggle to Coruscant,
and Cestus is not exactly on the way.
The Republic must begin
debriefing Poggle right away
if we're to get useful intelligence from him.
Master, l suggest we let our Padawans
handle the supply mission.
Whatever needs to be done, Master,
l'm happy to help.
- As am l.
- Very well. Take a medical frigate.
And after we've delivered Poggle
to Coruscant,
we'll rendezvous with you
for the voyage to Dantooine.
Sorry, boys. Hope l didn't interrupt
any pleasant dreams.
We got another mission, sir?
You bet. We're making
a medical supply run to Ord Cestus.
Thought we were bred
for battle, not running errands.
Hey! We were bred
to follow orders, Pulsar.
You got a problem with that?
- No, sir. No problem.
- That's what l thought. Now, move!
Scythe, come on.
Up, brother, up and at 'em.
Hey, Scythe.
Welcome back to the land of the living.
Thank you, sir.
We are ready to make ourjump,
Master Fisto.
Good. l look forward to your arrival.
What? What is it?
lt's too quiet. lt's a big change
from all the fighting the last few days.
- You should enjoy this peace while it lasts.
- l can't. Let's go eat.
l was just thinking
about what you said earlier,
about enjoying the peace while it lasts.
As a Jedi,
l'm not sure l know how to do that.
Master Windu has said we are
keepers of the peace, not warriors.
However, once the war is over,
it will be ourjob to maintain the peace.
Yes, but will we do so
as keepers of the peace or warriors?
And what's the difference?
l don't have all the answers, Ahsoka.
Like you, l am a learner.
- What does your Master tell you?
- Anakin? Oh, um...
You might find some of his thoughts
on the future a bit radical.
Really? Why?
Let's just say my Master
will always do what needs to be done.
l'm not even sure
how peacetime will agree with him.
Just came up to check on us, Scythe?
Well, we're on course,
and all systems are green.
What the...
We have control of the bridge.
Evening, Ox, Edge.
Would you like to join us?
ls something wrong,
troopers?
Troopers! Stand down!
What are you doing?
Two clones just attacked us.
What is going on?
Trap, do you know
what happened to those troopers?
Couldn't tell you, Commander.
l'm just as confused as...
You're in charge of those men!
Did you order them to kill us?
No, sir! l did not.
What's happening?
Why would they do this?
We don't know. We heard shots.
Why should we believe you?
Look, no guns.
These men wouldn't just attack us
without reason.
My Master had a clone betray them once,
a traitor who was paid off by Ventress.
lt can't be that simple.
At least, it didn't feel like that.
Excuse me, sir, we should make sure
that we're still in control of the bridge.
Bridge, this is Barriss. Respond.
We need to get up there.
We need to find out what's going on.
But these two
will be coming around any minute.
Havoc can watch them
until we check on the bridge.
Okay. Let's go.
The cargo ship failed
to check in on schedule.
l attempted to contact them.
There is no reply.
l don't like it. Something's up.
lt is certainly most unlike either Padawan
to lose contact.
- They're in trouble.
- Anakin, have faith in your Padawan.
She would have checked in.
- Like you always do?
- Good point.
Sometimes l don't think you realize
how alike you two have become.
We need to continue
our interrogation of Poggle.
Yes, agreed.
He's being most uncooperative.
- Keep your ears open in case Ahsoka calls.
- Got it.
Engage the autopilot
and put up the security shields.
Someone doesn't want us going up there.
l'll attempt to override the controls.
He's infected!
Get this thing off me!
What is that?
Looks like some type of parasite.
lt must be controlling their actions.
Mind control.
Well, that explains a lot.
Trap was my friend.
He would never have tried to kill us.
How did these things get on board
in the first place?
They must have infected the clones
while they were on Geonosis.
We'll have to quarantine the ship.
We should also contact Master Fisto
and let him know about the situation.
Let's go.
- That sound. lt's...
- Geonosian.
We have to help him.
lt's too late.
Barriss! Let's go for the vent!
l'll go to the reactor room
and disable the thrusters.
You head for the aft comm center
and send a warning to Master Fisto.
We have to stop the ship
from reaching the medical station.
l don't know, Barriss.
l think we should stay together.
As do l. Unfortunately,
that's not a luxury we have right now.
One of us must succeed, Ahsoka.
lf you need to, you'll do
what must be done. l know it.
Yes. Of course. Then l'll see you soon.
As long as these things are on board,
we dare not dock with the medical station.
You must bring the ship in.
The only way we can stop these parasites
is to analyze them.
You don't understand how terrible
these things are. What if they get loose?
We will take precautions.
l have a bad feeling about this,
Master Fisto,
but l will follow your instructions.
lf there's one thing we clones know,
it's how to stop a Jedi.
NO!
Almost got it.
Cargo ship TB-73, this is
Clone Captain Rex. Please respond.
Rex, this is Ahsoka.
Boy, am l glad to hear your voice.
Likewise, sir. l've got someone here
who wants to speak with you.
Ahsoka, what's going on? Are you okay?
Well, not exactly.
Make sure you have a wrist com.
Keep it on.
l'm going to interrogate Poggle.
He might have some answers.
Find Barriss and wait for my signal.
Barriss, you're back. Were you successful?
Barriss? What's wrong?
Barriss, no!
l'm your friend! Barriss, snap out of it!
Barriss, it's not you, it's the creatures!
Fight them!
Leave us.
You will answer my questions.
Your feeble Jedi mind tricks
do not work on Geonosians.
The other Jedi already learned this.
Mind tricks?
l don't need mind tricks to get you to talk.
- l will never talk, Jedi.
- We'll see about that, Poggle.
- l made contact with Ahsoka.
- What's their status?
Geonosian parasites
have infected her crew.
How did they get on board her ship?
Poggle said the parasites
must have needed a new host
after we raided the Queen's temple.
You interrogated Poggle?
l did. There wasn't time
to get the rest of you.
How did you get him to talk?
Look, all that matters is that
he told me how to stop the worms.
This is Ahsoka. Come in.
Ahsoka, listen to me.
The worms are affected by the cold!
Cold? That's how we stop them?
Rupture the coolant system.
Did you hear me?
Rupture the coolant system!
The coolant system. Got it.
That's Ahsoka's ship.
lt just came out of hyperspace.
Send out the tugs to help guide them in.
Warn all medical hazard crew
that l don't want anyone boarding
that ship until the parasites are contained.
Sound all the alarms.
And prepare the sub-zero conduits.
Engage tractor beam.
There you are.
You can't hide from me.
The bridge. At last.
We're coming in awfully fast.
This is Ahsoka Tano, can you hear me?
l'm shutting down the engines.
l'll try to reverse the...
l'm having a hard time slowing her down.
There's no one at the controls!
The pilot must be dead!
- Sir, she's listing.
- The escort ships must maintain control.
Kill me. Please.
l can't.
Full power! Now! Now!
We got her. We got her!
Attach the sub-zero conduits.
- The temperature is below freezing, sir.
- Let's board, then.
But stay on guard.
They may still be dangerous.
Hello, Master Fisto.
We're ready to pick up the supplies.
We'll take care of that.
You rest now, Ahsoka.
lt's all right, Ahsoka. lt's okay. You're safe.
Barriss?
Barriss is fine, thanks to your efforts.
And so are the clones.
- What were those things?
- l think l can help answer that.
We had the parasite worms analyzed.
They are the same type of creature
you found on Geonosis, Master Skywalker.
We'll have to inform the troops
on Geonosis.
This parasite might explain how
they recaptured the planet the first time.
l don't want it happening again.
You've been through quite an ordeal,
little one.
Master Skywalker, may l have a word?
Master, on the ship, Barriss was
gone,
and she wanted me to kill her.
- She told me...
- But you couldn't do it.
No. No, l couldn't. But should l have?
l mean, it worked out now,
but if we had failed,
if the ship docked
and the worms spread and...
Ahsoka, it's your duty
to save as many lives as you can.
Barriss knew you could save thousands
if the worms were destroyed.
Which she thought
meant destroying her, too.
But you did the right thing.
You knew the freezing cold
would kill the worms.
Letting go of our attachments
is a difficult struggle for all of us.
You followed your instincts.
l'm sure she would agree
that you made the right choice.