Diplomacy or deception?
The Council of Neutral Systems
speaks for over 1,500 worlds
who want to stay out of the war.
But rumors have reached
the Republic Senate
suggesting that the Council's new leader,
Duchess Satine of Mandalore,
is secretly building her own army
to fight for the Separatist cause.
Now Jedi Master Obi-Wan Kenobi
has been sent to Mandalore
to discover the truth behind these claims.
The Duchess awaits you, General Kenobi.
Far be it for me
to keep the Duchess waiting.
General Kenobi.
Thank you for meeting with me,
Prime Minister Almec.
l welcome you as a servant of the people.
But l am troubled by the false rumors
that brought you here.
Mandalore would never turn
against the Republic.
The Duchess Satine values peace
more than her own life.
Oh, l'm aware of the Duchess's views.
Master Kenobi,
Mandalore's violent past is behind us.
All of our warriors were exiled
to our moon, Concordia.
They died out years ago.
Hmm. Are you certain?
l recently encountered a man
who wore Mandalorian armor. Jango Fett.
Jango Fett was a common bounty hunter.
How he acquired that armor is beyond me.
Well, Master Kenobi.
My shining Jedi Knight
to the rescue once again.
After all these years,
you're even more beautiful than ever.
Kind words from a man
who accuses me of treachery.
l would never accuse you
of personal wrongdoing, Duchess.
However, a Separatist saboteur
attacked one of our Republic cruisers.
A Mandalorian saboteur.
You must be mistaken.
No Mandalorian would engage
in such violence, not anymore.
Where is this prisoner now?
He took his own life
rather than submit to questioning.
l know these commandos fought
in many wars, often against the Jedi.
Every one of my people
is as trustworthy as l am.
- l know we sound defensive, but...
- Clearly, your investigation was ordered
because the Senate is eager
to intervene in our affairs.
My investigation was ordered
by the Jedi Council.
l stand corrected.
General Kenobi, perhaps you'd like
to join me on a walk through the city.
lt's so good to see you again, Obi-Wan,
despite the circumstances.
Your peaceful ways have paid off.
Mandalore has prospered
since the last time l was here.
Not everyone on Mandalore believes
that our commitment to peace
is a sign of progress.
There is a group
that calls itself Death Watch.
l imagine these are the renegades
you're looking for.
They idolize violence
and the warrior ways of the past.
There are those among us,
certain officials,
who are working
to root out these criminals.
lt has been an ongoing investigation.
How widespread is
this Death Watch movement?
lt's hardly a movement.
lt's a small group of hooligans
who choose to vandalize public places,
nothing more.
We shall soon have them in custody.
We have tracked them down
to our moon, Concordia.
l hope you're right, Duchess.
l do not understand why
the arrival of this Jedi doesn't upset you.
You promised to support
the Death Watch forces
so we could overthrow the Duchess Satine
and her weak, peace-loving government.
And l intend to keep my promise.
But how? lf the Republic interferes now,
Death Watch will not be able
to take over the planet.
Consider, once the Senate orders
peacekeeping troops to Mandalore,
the people will be surrounded by
a military presence. Most distasteful.
- They will rebel.
- And rally to Death Watch.
Our insurgency will grow stronger.
Yes. And Duchess Satine shall fall.
A peacekeeper belongs
on the front lines of conflict.
Otherwise, he wouldn't
be able to do his job.
The work of a peacekeeper is
to make sure that conflict does not arise.
Yes, a noble description,
but not a realistic one.
ls reality what makes a Jedi
abandon his ideals?
Or is it simply a response
to political convenience?
- Are you all right?
- l'm fine.
Hooligans couldn't have arranged
an attack of this scale.
Then this must be the work
of an offworlder.
Are you sure of that?
The sign of the Death Watch.
This goes far beyond vandalism.
This is a political statement
against your government.
And against you.
You're not safe here.
l'm taking you back to the palace.
l want to interview everyone here.
Nobody leaves this scene.
You there!
l only want to talk.
l don't want to hurt you.
Stay back!
What is he saying?
He was speaking in the dialect
they use on Concordia, our moon.
l should like to visit this moon of yours.
Perhaps l could accompany the body.
The Concordian moon is a province
with its own governor.
You'll need me to escort you.
- That won't be necessary.
- Actually, it will.
You won't make much progress
without me there,
especially since you've just been involved
with the death of a Concordian.
- l didn't kill him.
- l know.
That's why l'm still talking to you.
l thought Concordia was
an agricultural settlement.
Before the end of our wars,
they turned it into a mining base.
The sheer number of mining facilities here
nearly destroyed our forests.
They're finally growing back.
- Duchess Satine. You are most welcome.
- Thank you, Governor Vizsla.
May l present Master Obi-Wan Kenobi,
representing the Jedi Council.
Governor Vizsla
is one of the officials l spoke of.
He has been working to find
the members of the Death Watch.
l take it you've heard the rumors
about Satine.
About how she's supposedly
leading Mandalore
into an alliance with the Separatists.
My only instructions are to seek the truth.
This was the man
who bombed the Memorial Shrine?
Yes. He was apparently
part of Death Watch.
A worrisome prospect.
lf you'll pardon me, General,
we must attend to the body.
l need a favor from you.
Please keep Governor Vizsla
occupied at dinner.
- Where are you going?
- Just for a look around.
l'd like to see one of these
mining facilities for myself.
You mean you want to determine
if they're still operational.
l hope to determine they're not.
l want you to wear this earpiece
so that we can stay in contact,
in case you run into trouble
while l'm gone.
Remember that you are here
under my protection.
Please try not to cause problems
where none yet exist.
Think of me as searching for solutions.
l have to tell you,
l'm opposed to all of this.
l'd be disappointed if you weren't.
Forgive me, Duchess.
l'm writing a condolence letter
to the dead man's family
and making arrangements
for them to retrieve his body.
Of course, Governor. Very proper.
General Kenobi will join us shortly.
He said he needed to meditate.
lt doesn't look abandoned to me.
l am here on a diplomatic mission
under the protection of Duchess Satine.
We do not recognize her rule.
Someone is feeding misinformation
directly to the Republic Senate,
saying that the Death Watch
is taking over Mandalore.
Who stands to gain from these lies?
Death Watch, of course.
They could not engineer all this.
The problem has clearly grown
much larger than we thought,
and l suspect
some external force helped it along.
Hard to believe.
lt would have to be someone
at the highest level of influence
among the Separatists.
But why target me?
You lead the Council of Neutral Systems.
Thus you threaten the Separatists' goals.
Take it as a compliment.
Someone very powerful
is working towards your downfall.
The commander wants us
to sweep the area
and check for any other Jedi
until he arrives.
This one's harmless enough
without his lightsaber.
The boss will love this.
General Kenobi's meditation
is taking a rather long time.
You know the Jedi,
they never do anything by halves.
Duchess, please acknowledge.
- May l offer you another drink?
- Yes. Certainly.
l'm in a bit of an awkward spot.
l'm being held by the Death Watch.
Sorry, Duchess. We're out of ice.
Sorry to hear that.
Perhaps we should begin dinner
without General Kenobi.
There's a tracking function on your comlink.
Follow it due east to my location.
l don't know if l can do that
at the moment.
- lt's extremely urgent!
- Are you not feeling well, Duchess?
Perhaps some fresh air would do me good.
Shall l escort you outside?
Take a speeder,
it's rough terrain.
Oh, l'll find my way, never fear.
Yes, sir.
Start the machine. Time for the Jedi
to meet with his fatal accident.
With pleasure.
This is not good.
Where exactly are you?
Listen for the loud, metallic,
clanging sound.
That would be the machine
about to smash me into bits.
There's some kind of disturbance
at the entrance. Let's check it out.
Well, it certainly took you long enough.
You know, l haven't saved you yet!
- Yes, no need to remind me of that.
- Be patient.
l happen to be a bit short on patience
right now!
Now, let's see, one of these...
- Satine, turn the machine off!
- l'm trying!
Satine!
There!
Look out!
For a man sworn to peace,
you take an unseemly pleasure
in the injuries of others.
For a woman sworn to non-violence,
you don't seem troubled
that l could have been killed back there.
But you weren't.
And yet l still haven't heard any thanks.
Well, you certainly haven't changed much.
This is not the way we came in.
Look there, it's the Jedi.
We'll have to stand and fight.
Or in your case, just stand.
You three, stop him.
You there!
- Satine!
- l'm all right.
l'll deal with this.
Get to your ships and evacuate.
Failure.
Governor?
For generations, my ancestors fought
proudly as warriors against the Jedi.
Now that woman tarnishes
the very name Mandalorian.
Defend her, if you will.
This lightsaber was stolen
from your Jedi Temple
by my ancestors
during the fall of the Old Republic.
Since then, many Jedi have died
upon its blade.
Prepare yourself to join them.
Warriors, finish him!
Satine?
- Should we go after him, sir?
- No, there's no time.
Don't worry, we'll catch up
with the Duchess soon enough.
l suppose we're even now.
- Oh? How so?
- l saved your life, you saved mine.
Yes, well, mine was the more daring
of the two rescues.
But if Pre Vizsla fled,
we have no way of learning
how widespread Death Watch really is.
lt's obvious the Separatists
are supporting the Death Watch.
l disagree. l told you
l wanted to stay out of this conflict.
Given the current situation,
l'm afraid that may no longer be possible.
l thought you of all people would
understand my position on this matter.
l will never be a part of this war.
Reporting for escort duty, General.
Oh. Anakin, am l glad to see you.
You sound tired.
The peaceful ways of the locals
wore me out a bit.